<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Thomas Midena</title><description>Generally genuinely enthusiastic</description><link>https://thomid.me/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:59:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>My favourite soundtracks of 2024</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2024/</guid><description>My top original scores from TV, movies and games</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thumbnail_v3.D3oXGXiW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite soundtracks of 2024&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For the sixth year in a row, I&amp;#39;ve created a list of my favourite soundtrack music of the year. This year I present my &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; top original scores released in the year 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex justify-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ujTxANp-6FA?si=7YNg_xTN2kIV7kzm&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video above presents this list with short clips from each score, but below you can find my list in written form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;24. &lt;strong&gt;IF&lt;/strong&gt; – Michael Giacchino&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/24IF.tfl0gwun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;#39;s a colourful and delightful Michael Giacchino score! He&amp;#39;s very much in his Pixar mode here; cutesy melodies with playful instrumentation, whistling and upbeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never really gets very complicated or intricate, but it&amp;#39;s very pleasant and in places effectively touching and nostalgic. The only downside is that on album it struggles to really get going. There are great statements of themes, but even on the suite tracks they somehow struggle to take off into a really satisfying cue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, beautiful short statements are better than no statements at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23. &lt;strong&gt;RED ROOMS&lt;/strong&gt; – Dominique Plante&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/23RedRooms.hEzu5G5p.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of this score is this courtly sort of baroque canon, lulling us into a sense of security and order. It sounds like progress, but underneath there&amp;#39;s certainly a sense of irony, of farce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other places, this film score also features some strange, twisted material with modulating strings and trance-inducing percussion. Plus some distorted screams in places, to make sure you&amp;#39;re really discomforted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a memorable score for a disturbing film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22. &lt;strong&gt;THE DRY 2: FORCE OF NATURE&lt;/strong&gt; – Peter Raeburn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22TheDry2.Cc7iX_9h.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a surprisingly sweet and tender score that—actually, no, the sweetness and tenderness wasn&amp;#39;t the surprising part about &lt;em&gt;The Dry 2&lt;/em&gt; . What surprised me is how epic and sweeping it can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relatively contained mystery movie here didn&amp;#39;t necessarily beg for such scope, but this music leans into a heightened sense of melodrama in a way that I absolutely love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m also delighted to have something Australian on the list this year. Rare for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;21. &lt;strong&gt;WOODWALKERS&lt;/strong&gt; – Anne-Kathrin Dern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/21Woodwalkers.DeghGM6W.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne-Kathrin Dern has been on my radar since &lt;em&gt;The Devil Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt;, and this was my favourite score of hers I heard in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;#39;s done well here working with a film that was clearly using temp tracks from things like &lt;em&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean&lt;/em&gt; and maybe some other Remote Control scores. And when I hear something that&amp;#39;s clearly following a temp, emulating the pattern of a cue I&amp;#39;m much more familiar with, I become very interested in how this composer has made their music different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even in those temp-y places, &lt;em&gt;Woodwalkers&lt;/em&gt; is plenty original. Its main themes are full and rich, blanketing the whole score in magic. I love the warm, heavy strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, &lt;em&gt;Woodwalkers&lt;/em&gt; is rather wondrous and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20. &lt;strong&gt;THE PENGUIN&lt;/strong&gt; – Mick Giacchino&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/20Penguin.CFZeEa1y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Michael Giacchino, now let&amp;#39;s have his son, Mick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;#39;t a massive orchestra on this score, but the instruments sound so good. Mick Giacchino is clearly benefiting from some family expertise in giving character to the orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But yeah, this is deliberately more intimate and smaller in scale than &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;, though it continues many of the same musical ideas. Disturbing psycho-esque strings, for example, are used to great effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main motif for &lt;em&gt;The Penguin&lt;/em&gt; is a simple little two-note riff, like Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s Batman theme. It&amp;#39;s an instantly iconic identifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all culminates in a really wonderful frantic, chaotic, powerful main theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19. &lt;strong&gt;WICKED&lt;/strong&gt; – John Powell and Stephen Schwartz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19Wicked.BySbvtJB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting one, because since it&amp;#39;s a musical we kind of need to clarify: am I talking about the score, or the songs, or both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;#39;m here doing this because I&amp;#39;m primarily a fan of orchestral music, so that&amp;#39;s where my focus is. And John Powell and Stephen Schwartz have made a really luscious colourful score in that regard. It has really wonderful moments of incredibly detailed expansive composition—some of the most beautiful &lt;em&gt;moments&lt;/em&gt; in a score this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that doesn&amp;#39;t let it reach really great heights, in my opinion, is the fact that it&amp;#39;s clearly connected to a musical. So anytime the orchestral score feels like it&amp;#39;s building to something... it doesn&amp;#39;t quite get there, because it&amp;#39;s been building to a song, which is over on the other soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That handicaps it a little bit. But still, some of these tracks are pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18. &lt;strong&gt;CALL OF DUTY: BLACK OPS 6&lt;/strong&gt; – Jack Wall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/18BlackOps6.lJA5-gAi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m still pretty new to being a fan of the music of this series, but a couple years ago Bear McCreary&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; was my favourite score of the whole year, so I&amp;#39;m pretty on board for each new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;Black Ops 6&lt;/em&gt; by Jack Wall reminded me in some ways of how entertaining I found that Bear McCreary one. This is a big and propulsive score... lots of musical ideas, really energetic and pulse-pounding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally that becomes too much, a bit of a Wall of sound (so to speak), but throughout the album there are points where I think that mix is just right, and it feels like a big action blockbuster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17. &lt;strong&gt;CONCORD&lt;/strong&gt; – Daniel Pemberton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/16Concord.DmdWtDiO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to a much less popular game, to say the least. A game that failed so spectacularly you can&amp;#39;t even play it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we get to keep Daniel Pemberton&amp;#39;s score, which is super charming and energetic. It sort of does the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; thing, of having contemporary rhythms and some classical heroic motifs on top, but I&amp;#39;d say &lt;em&gt;Concord&lt;/em&gt; actually leans a little more cool and modern compared to &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s sometimes kooky retro style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, it&amp;#39;s certainly good at hyping me up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. &lt;strong&gt;WE WERE THE LUCKY ONES&lt;/strong&gt; – Rachel Portman &amp;amp; Jon Ehrlich&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/17WeWereTheLuckyOnes.BzbgrJuo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing like a bit of Rachel Portman to tug on your heartstrings. Here with Jon Ehrlich too, we have a classy drama score that I really enjoyed, especially when it goes big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it soars, it&amp;#39;s really something. When that main theme kicks in, your heart explodes. That&amp;#39;s just Rachel Portman, that&amp;#39;s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;15. &lt;strong&gt;THAT CHRISTMAS&lt;/strong&gt; – John Powell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/15ThatChristmas.DNb4jeOa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting this above &lt;em&gt;Wicked&lt;/em&gt; is probably a little controversial, but for me, &lt;em&gt;That Christmas&lt;/em&gt; was the John Powell music that most delighted me this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s whimsical and Christmas-y and gets just as playful as any of the best John Powell scores from over the years. It&amp;#39;s yet another reminder, as if we needed it, of just how agile John Powell&amp;#39;s writing can be, with cues that jump from idea to idea without ever feeling too busy or directionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, as all John Powell fans know very well, when it comes to melody and leitmotif, he&amp;#39;s one of the best in the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14. &lt;strong&gt;ARK: THE ANIMATED SERIES&lt;/strong&gt; – Gareth Coker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/14ARKAnimatedSeries.CJ8qdqk8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gareth Coker has created a lot of music for the &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; series of games over the years, but now here he is doing a score to an &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; animated series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#39;s brought over many of his great existing themes, and he continues to flesh out this bombastic soundscape. I just find all of the music in this series so listenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to contrast with the bombast, there&amp;#39;s some really delicate, gentle, romantic material in here too, which surprised me a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically this release is labelled as Volume 1, but I don&amp;#39;t believe there&amp;#39;s been a Volume 2... yet? Which is fine. This release is uh... over 3 hours long. There&amp;#39;s so much to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13. &lt;strong&gt;FINAL FANTASY VII REBIRTH&lt;/strong&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/13FinalFantasy.BvPyqKDl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those soundtracks that&amp;#39;s kind of impossible to summarise. It is many hours of music. Not all of it is great, and a lot of it is in styles of music I don&amp;#39;t really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But so much more of it is great than needs to be, and some of it is out of this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as a re-imagining of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;, this sees the return and reinvigoration of some of the greatest themes in the history of video games. Many of the reiterations are beautiful beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only worry is finding the time to listen properly to all of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12. &lt;strong&gt;PRINCE OF PERSIA: THE LOST CROWN&lt;/strong&gt; – Mentrix &amp;amp; Gareth Coker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/12PrinceofPersia.Coz1L4tr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game score has a little bit of &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; about it, with some electrifying high-tempo beats. It&amp;#39;s got some really cool tracks, and when it comes to the main theme, which is my favourite part of the soundtrack, its presentation can be so huge and enormous, like the example you&amp;#39;ve just heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t expect &lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; to sound like &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt;, but thanks to Gareth Coker, that&amp;#39;s sometimes the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; is higher than &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; on my list because overall I just found it to be a newer and fresher experience in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11. &lt;strong&gt;MASTERS OF THE AIR&lt;/strong&gt; – Blake Neely&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/11MastersoftheAir.B6cWSQBh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blake Neely has big shoes to fill in this follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Band of Brothers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Pacific&lt;/em&gt;. And I think he really pulls it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the sort of sentimental World War II soundtrack that I was hoping for. It combines some gloriously wistful, patriotic sop with some really tense and exciting action cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s really what it says on the tin, and that&amp;#39;s a great thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;HOUSE OF THE DRAGON SEASON 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Ramin Djawadi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/10HouseoftheDragon.B2KeLaao.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dark and brooding score here for a season of &lt;em&gt;House of the Dragon&lt;/em&gt; that&amp;#39;s all about the inevitable escalation of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;#39;s actually a recurring motif that exactly represents that theme, sometimes in the form of this foreboding wailing female vocal. It&amp;#39;s really raw and tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this soundtrack is quite bleak, similar to previous Ramin Djawadi &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; music, but it&amp;#39;s still full of standout pieces of beautiful montage and intense action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;TALES OF KENZERA: ZAU&lt;/strong&gt; – Nainita Desai&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/9TalesofKenzera.JiZ5ezau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one came out of nowhere for me. I&amp;#39;m not familiar with the game or the composer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s really exciting though. Brilliant musical storytelling—you don&amp;#39;t need anything but the music to start seeing vivid images. There are clearly a lot of inspirations here, but what immediately jumped out to me is some very big Ludwig Goransson &lt;em&gt;Black Panther&lt;/em&gt; inspiration, particularly on a couple of action cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, again, being able to see a clear line between this and its inspirations doesn&amp;#39;t negatively impact my enjoyment in the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a gorgeous and vibrant soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;TRANSFORMERS ONE&lt;/strong&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/8TransformersOne.0dIf_I6t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never thought a spiritual sequel to Brian Tyler&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Transformers Prime&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack from 2012 is something we&amp;#39;d get. But here it is. Brian Tyler even references those great old themes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, even if you don&amp;#39;t already love the music of &lt;em&gt;Transformers Prime&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Transformers One&lt;/em&gt; is so great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Tyler gives the Transformers such profound nobility in his iconic long-winded melodies. There are few things that I love more than a big melodic Brian Tyler blockbuster score, and this really is another good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some really, really big heavy brass here too, and that always gets me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;YOUNG WOMAN AND THE SEA&lt;/strong&gt; – Amelia Warner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/7YoungWoman.Dy_Vv1BB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between &lt;em&gt;Transformers One&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Young Woman and the Sea&lt;/em&gt;, this is definitely the most uplifting, inspirational section of my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This score is really wonderful, magical and beautiful. It&amp;#39;s got a bit of Enya DNA in there, and there aren&amp;#39;t many 2024 scores I can say that about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a couple of brief little moments, the orchestration even reminded me of Justin Hurwitz&amp;#39; &lt;em&gt;First Man&lt;/em&gt;, and that&amp;#39;s just an all-timer for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, solidly entertaining album, end to end. It only gets better with each listen, and that&amp;#39;s why it&amp;#39;s this high on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;DUNE: PART TWO&lt;/strong&gt; – Hans Zimmer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/6Dune2.oY_Hy9tQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s funny, these days Zimmer&amp;#39;s presence is felt so keenly across the board, on film scores he had no direct hand in, so it feels strange to actually come to one that&amp;#39;s got his name on the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the thing is, and what&amp;#39;s clear in &lt;em&gt;Dune Part Two&lt;/em&gt; , is that the Hans Zimmer of today is quite different to the Hans Zimmer we&amp;#39;ve heard in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses many of the same elements and techniques, but &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; is much more minimalistic and experiential than a lot of his most famous scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from interviews how passionate he is about this particular story, and how personal the experience of creating this music is for him. And that really comes through in the music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s full of so much feeling, saying so much with, at times, so little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piece you just heard is for me the most heartbreaking piece of the year. Zimmer&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Dune: Part Two&lt;/em&gt; may not be eligible for an Oscar, but it&amp;#39;s eligible to be high on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;HELLDIVERS 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Wilbert Roget, II; Ross Tregenza&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/5Helldivers2.CSoPE8RF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helldivers&lt;/em&gt; is mad fun! Talk about &lt;em&gt;Starship Troopers&lt;/em&gt; on steroids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s an upbeat, rousing action blockbuster, with a cheeky sense of irony that never gets in the way of just being FUN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murray Gold once talked about comedic music, and that tough balance of knowing when to lean into the comedy, and when to play it straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for the most part, Wilbert Roget II plays this perfectly straight, and I think that&amp;#39;s the right approach. He gives himself full permission to lean into the naïve capitalistic heroism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This album is on the shorter side of things, but it&amp;#39;s just some of the most fist-pumping fun I&amp;#39;ve heard all year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;WORLD OF WARCRAFT: THE WAR WITHIN&lt;/strong&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/4TheWarWithin.md8WuhUJ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know much about my musical tastes, you know I can never get enough &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; in my ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s just one of the great musical landscapes, inspired by all of the greatest epic fantasy music of decades past, and taking it in bold new directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after a couple of slightly disappointing soundtrack releases, I think &lt;em&gt;The War Within&lt;/em&gt; is a return to form for the series. It&amp;#39;s packed full of new ideas, and it&amp;#39;s beautifully recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to this album on repeat for a couple of months in 2024, and it helped me get through some challenging work. I find that music with this much character, magic, and heart is just a perfect companion through difficult times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;STAR WARS OUTLAWS&lt;/strong&gt; – Wilbert Roget, II; Kazuma Jinnouchi; Jon Everist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/3StarWarsOutlaws.BZrrcKPa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, it&amp;#39;s another game score by Wilbert Roget II!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m obviously a sucker for some &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music, but its combination with contemporary styles in recent years has been hit and miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not one of the people who thinks &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; always needs to sound like John Williams, but I do think many attempts to leave that classical romantic style behind have been fairly disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here however, I think they found a great balance. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Outlaws&lt;/em&gt; references some Williams themes, surprisingly appropriately, like its use of the Imperial theme from &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt; . But for the most part, it&amp;#39;s original and exciting, taking us into new areas of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one thing it does so well is keeping a sound that&amp;#39;s a little unusual, a little alien, a little not of our world. That allows the composers to incorporate modern elements without it losing all of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars-y-ness&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&amp;#39;s so cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;DRAGON AGE: THE VEILGUARD&lt;/strong&gt; – Hans Zimmer &amp;amp; Lorne Balfe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/2DragonAge.iLsD732Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; game score!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a little surprising to have the new &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; this high on the list. I mean, the series has always had great music, particularly &lt;em&gt;Inquisition&lt;/em&gt;. But I liked this entry by Hans Zimmer and Lorne Balfe (well, let&amp;#39;s be real, mostly Lorne Balfe) way more than I anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in terms of measuring a score by how much fun I&amp;#39;ve had with it, how much enjoyment I&amp;#39;ve gotten out of it—well, from that perspective, &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age: The Veilguard&lt;/em&gt; deserves to be here at number 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main title theme, which is heaps of fun, and probably where Zimmer&amp;#39;s influence is most prominent, actually sounds a lot like Junkie XL. And not in a bad way. It&amp;#39;s like Junkie XL&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mortal Engines&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s pretty over-the-top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of recognisable modes of Lorne Balfe here... some &lt;em&gt;His Dark Materials&lt;/em&gt; in the thematic shapes, a bit of &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; grandiosity, and a whole lot of &lt;em&gt;Skylanders&lt;/em&gt;. This really is basically &lt;em&gt;Skylanders&lt;/em&gt; with a bigger, darker sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And overall, it&amp;#39;s much more upbeat than I&amp;#39;d expect from &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt;. In the end, this score just has a whole lot of tracks that I really really enjoyed. Many times, on repeat. And I was thoroughly entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;RINGS OF POWER SEASON 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Bear McCreary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/1RingsofPower.DXCaEMpp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It almost feels like a cop out. I tried to find anything that could knock this off the number one spot, but I couldn&amp;#39;t. For me, &lt;em&gt;The Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; is just head and shoulders above everything else out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scores for the first season blew everything else away. Some come-down was to be expected in this follow-up, and yes, it re-treads a lot of the same territory, which isn&amp;#39;t quite as novel this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the leitmotif writing on this is still just so good, and it&amp;#39;s full of wondrous new ideas, like the powerful theme for Rhûn and the delicate sounds of Eregion. Meanwhile, themes from the previous season are refreshed with some of their best presentations yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so good, and just like last time, there&amp;#39;s so much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of strong themes, great orchestration, and satisfying cohesive cues, &lt;em&gt;Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; continues to be my favourite music of recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew! There we are, another year of this down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, I feel bad about all the things I couldn&amp;#39;t fit on the list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t even put on the &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; movie, or the &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; game, or the &lt;em&gt;Gladiator&lt;/em&gt; sequel. There were about half a dozen scores that during the year I felt super sure would be on the list, so I even wrote up a little blurb about them for this video. But they ended up not fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a pretty even split across categories this year—I had 6 TV shows, 9 movies, and 9 video games. But the top of the list leaned heavily into the video games. I guess that&amp;#39;s largely where I found the most musical entertainment this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movies were down big-time from last year, when I had 14 film scores. And only one score on my list this year was nominated at the Academy Awards—&lt;em&gt;Wicked&lt;/em&gt;. Though that&amp;#39;s not unusual, I can&amp;#39;t remember ever really agreeing with the Oscar picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a couple of double-up composers this time around... having John Powell twice isn&amp;#39;t surprising. Wilbert Roget II at spots 3 and 5 is a little. Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s name is there twice, on &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt;, but really I do think of &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; as a Lorne Balfe score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always love to see the surprises that come out of nowhere for me each year. Like, I had never heard of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Kenzera&lt;/em&gt; until a couple months ago, and even now I know nothing about it except that I like the music. It&amp;#39;s so much fun to expand the pool of things you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next year!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>music</category><category>soundtracks</category></item><item><title>My favourite media of 2024</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-media-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-media-2024/</guid><description>The things I watched, read and listened to most (and what they say about my year)</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/trakt2024.BMftwwmy.png&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite media of 2024&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Like most humans, I just can&amp;#39;t get enough stories in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TV Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024 was a great year for TV. My top 10 features a range of things I loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomastvshowstrakt2024.DDl_6Dzl.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom end is &lt;strong&gt;The Curse&lt;/strong&gt;, which was divisive but completely enthralled me. And it proved that I don&amp;#39;t only love Nathan Fielder for his provocative reality TV satire, but also for his fiction! And bloody hell, Emma Stone is good. I know the finale didn&amp;#39;t work for a lot of people, but I think about it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;#39;s &lt;strong&gt;Fallout&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Blue Eye Samurai&lt;/strong&gt; — colourful genre shows that are widely acclaimed, and I can see why. These shows make their lore-rich worlds perfectly accessible for any old shmuck, without dumbing things down too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we&amp;#39;ve got the shows that brought me deep into the spy game. I caught up on all of &lt;strong&gt;Slow Horses&lt;/strong&gt; in 2024, and I&amp;#39;m now a massive fan. I thought the 2nd season in particular was just delightful. The latest season was probably the weakest, but still a lot of fun. I hadn&amp;#39;t yet finished &lt;strong&gt;The Agency&lt;/strong&gt; when I scored it 8/10, but I was so enjoying the early episodes that it felt like an easy call to make. It stumbled a little towards the end of the season, but oh well. Honourable mention for &lt;strong&gt;Black Doves&lt;/strong&gt;, which must have just missed my top 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evil&lt;/strong&gt; had its series finale in 2024, and it&amp;#39;s really sad to say goodbye to that show. You know when you feel like something is made &lt;em&gt;just for you&lt;/em&gt;? Well for me, that was Evil. I&amp;#39;ve loved many TV Shows by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/06/20/the-couple-behind-tvs-boldest-shows&quot;&gt;the Kings&lt;/a&gt;, but this was my favourite. It had all the cleverness of The Good Wife, all the genre thrills of BrainDead, all the contemporary relevance of The Good Fight... plus, it was about angels and demons! I had an absolute hoot. It&amp;#39;s one of my favourite shows ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had a good time following the horrible exploits of sociopathic narcissists in &lt;strong&gt;RIPLEY&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;The Penguin&lt;/strong&gt;. Both walked that line of making the horrible protagonists likeable enough that it was never a pain to hang out with them. But hey, when you have Andrew Scott and Colin Farrell, that&amp;#39;s not too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then at the top of the list, the shows I enjoyed most in 2024, we have &lt;strong&gt;Shōgun&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;House of the Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Season 2. Thoughtful, character-focused examinations of pre-war tensions. Both had the best performances I saw all year. And particular props to Shogun for such a thrilling use of language and translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some new seasons I absolutely loved, like &lt;strong&gt;The Rings of Power&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s second outing. I couldn&amp;#39;t get it to show up on my Trakt list above because, well, sometimes Trakt is weird. Speaking of which...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmoviestrakt2024.pAapz4yk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d already seen the first &lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Gladiator&lt;/strong&gt;, but I rewatched them in 2024 and rated them on Trakt, so they&amp;#39;ve appeared in this list. And there doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be a way to remove them. Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rewatches reminded me that the first Dune and the first Gladiator are both &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;. Actually, they have a lot in common. Desert-based action adventure epics about rising up against villainous emperors. Both incredibly entertaining and rewarding upon rewatch. Both featuring some of Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s most iconic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They diverge in their sequels, however. &lt;strong&gt;Gladiator II&lt;/strong&gt; wasn&amp;#39;t bad, I thought. A decent ride, maybe a bit too much of a re-tread, but an entirely competent sequel. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;Dune: Part Two&lt;/strong&gt; was one of my favourite films of 2024, and the more I&amp;#39;ve thought about it, pretty much a masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Remarkable Life of Ibelin&lt;/strong&gt; was also high on my list. A tragic, uplifting documentary about horrible illness and unlikely community. The way it depicts found family in World of Warcraft really, really, really worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught &lt;strong&gt;Anatomy of a Fall&lt;/strong&gt; at the very start of the year, and it was one of my most thrilling cinematic experiences in recent memory. Astoundingly engaging courtroom drama. And like Shōgun, the way it uses different languages to convey interesting things about the characters is something I&amp;#39;m so fascinated by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew nothing about &lt;strong&gt;Wicked&lt;/strong&gt; before seeing this movie, and like so many others I got completely swept up in it and I can&amp;#39;t wait for part two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caddo Lake&lt;/strong&gt; came out of nowhere. It&amp;#39;s such a cool little drama with a twist. I don&amp;#39;t want to say anything about the concept, it&amp;#39;s wonderful to learn all about it in real-time. Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it has something to do with the mood I was in on the day, but &lt;strong&gt;Twisters&lt;/strong&gt; is the most fun I had at the cinema in 2024. There&amp;#39;s nothing too surprising about the movie, but the cast is so loveable and I was completely along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challengers&lt;/strong&gt; is a thrill ride and a half. I was so delighted by the propulsive, twisting and turning games of passion and ambition. Shakespearean and all that. I watched this at home and when the credits rolled I was jumping on the couch, punching the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;strong&gt;The Last Stop at Yuma County&lt;/strong&gt;. On the face of it, this could be a pretty generic Coen Brothers rip-off. But it&amp;#39;s so much better than that. It makes a completely absurd situation feel immediate and true and plays out one of the most shocking, terrifying, hilarious rides of the year. And it doesn&amp;#39;t just fall apart into a mindless shootout at the end! So good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have huge appreciation for the importance of reading and (like many people) I&amp;#39;m trying to increase my time spent reading each year. I didn&amp;#39;t quite make it to my 24 book goal in 2024, but I&amp;#39;m optimistic about my 25 book goal for 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasbooksstorygraph2024.BGKOyod2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll highlight three books I read in 2024. Not necessarily my favourites, but worth a mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kill Your Husbands by Jack Heath&lt;/strong&gt;
This is a proper page-turning mystery that I consumed within a few short days. It has so many twists and turns — every time I started to worry I&amp;#39;d figured out all of the mysteries, there was still more to come. And it leaned further into horror than I&amp;#39;d anticipated... gave me some shivers before bed! For pure entertainment, this may have been my favourite thing I read this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edgedancer by Brandon Sanderson&lt;/strong&gt;
I didn&amp;#39;t love this, but I was tickled by some of the ideas. It&amp;#39;s a breezy little novella in Sanderson&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Stormlight Archive&lt;/em&gt;, which I find myself somewhat begrudgingly committed to (once you&amp;#39;ve read four books in a series, how can you stop!). There are few things as painful as spending too much time with a character who&amp;#39;s supposed to be constantly witty (think Steven Moffat protagonists), but hey, sometimes Lift is genuinely witty and that makes it worth it (again, think Steven Moffat protagonists).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who: Scratchman by Tom Baker&lt;/strong&gt;
A messy Doctor Who adventure with a severe lack of stakes and character development. However, this is a brilliant ode to Tom Baker, particularly when listening to the audiobook read by the man himself. His winks and laughs and sighs through the story in that way that only Tom Baker can. And more than anything in the story himself, his reading of &amp;quot;a letter from Sarah Jane&amp;quot; at the end was extremely endearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to a LOT of music in 2024. I&amp;#39;m a soundtrack fiend and here&amp;#39;s a little Last.fm overview of the things I was into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/Screenshot%202025-01-27%20213529.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giacchino, McCreary and Williams being my top three composers makes a lot of sense. They&amp;#39;ve been up there for a long time and will probably stay there for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from my top albums and tracks, I got deep into some video game scores this year. Later this week I&amp;#39;ll be posting my annual &lt;em&gt;Favourite Soundtracks of the Year&lt;/em&gt; video, so I won&amp;#39;t discuss any of these here, but those Last.fm stats might give you a little teaser...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it&amp;#39;s been such a really great year across popular media. And considering the sheer quantity of huge movies and shows that are coming soon, things aren&amp;#39;t gonna be slowing down in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>games</category><category>music</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>That fresh new website feeling</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/fresh-new-website/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/fresh-new-website/</guid><description>I&apos;ve built a lot of personal websites in the past, but this one is my favourite! (obvs)</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenanewsite.DTrWJe8t.png&quot; alt=&quot;That fresh new website feeling&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Smells pretty good right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually yeah, don&amp;#39;t sniff too hard. Knowing how I&amp;#39;ve thrown it together, this website probably has errant links that take you directly to my bank account or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had many personal websites over the years. Making them is something that I&amp;#39;ve always been very interested in and only mildly good at. Putting them together feels like its slightly beyond my skills, slightly beyond what I&amp;#39;m capable of – which is the most fun space to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the earliest sites I remember putting together used &lt;em&gt;Freewebs&lt;/em&gt;. Which later changed its name to Webs, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/l2jzib/webscom_aka_freewebscom_deleting_tens_of_millions/&quot;&gt;shut down completely, apparently deleting everything&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early websites featured my projects under the moniker &amp;quot;Lcm Film&amp;quot;. Here&amp;#39;s one of the final forms of that Freewebs site (which went through a ridiculous number of regenerations... every few months I was like &amp;quot;Let&amp;#39;s remake the website!&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/lcmfilmsite.Dhq_COK3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much as changed, has it? Get rid of the dated Google+ link and the ear-searingly grey background, and this website could pretty much do the trick for me today. Actually, now that I think about it, I don&amp;#39;t know why I&amp;#39;ve spent so much time on the new site. Could&amp;#39;ve just re-published this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s even got a &amp;quot;Brand New Website!&amp;quot; blurb there, just like the one I&amp;#39;m writing right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you look closely, my favourite bit is the little &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s going on!?&amp;quot; image on the left, with a link to go back to the previous version of the website. How thoughtful of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My websites were actually much more fancy back then. I mean, each of those menu links lights up when you hover over them. I put functions like that together manually, designing lit-up versions of each image and programming the hover effect. And the Library has links to separate pages for each short film I was hosting at the time. Yes, actually hosting. Videos weren&amp;#39;t all just hosted on YouTube back then, like they are now (for better and worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My websites went through quite a few different stages after that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenaogsite.DM9dCCyv.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looked like when I was just starting to get into minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was using my own name, a picture of myself, and starting to base everything around my YouTube Channel. Exciting times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenarefinedsite.CM7FVuWe.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I had this site. Which again, in hindsight I&amp;#39;m pretty impressed by, and I wonder why I got rid of it. It&amp;#39;s pretty elegant for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t take all the credit for this one though. It was created with help from my mate &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewcollins.me/&quot;&gt;Drew Collins&lt;/a&gt;. Who was and I have to assume absolutely still is an absolute legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But according to the laws of balance, after this relatively minimalistic phase, I went a bit loopy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Thomas_websitebanner_v3.DDZs91Pp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a little while I had a website that looked like this. Holey moley. We all go through design phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then and in-between I&amp;#39;ve had various other sites, hosted with Blogger, Squarespace, Wordpress, Drupal, and I think at one point in my teens I lost my mind and went pure CSS. Or went pure CSS and lost my mind. It&amp;#39;s a chicken and egg situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;#39;s the website I&amp;#39;ve had for the last few years. A very basic Wordpress page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenawordpresssite.B7bwPskt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to go proper minimal with that one. No icons, only a few lines of text, one image. And I think it has served me well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#39;ve been wanting for something a little more robust. A little cleaner. A little better at communicating everything I&amp;#39;m up to. And with a blog built in, so that I can write &lt;em&gt;stuff like this&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was choosing a platform to build with. I don&amp;#39;t like Wordpress, it&amp;#39;s a clunky mess to me. I wanted to find something that was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open source,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modern and widely-used,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;affordable (or free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and highly customisable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t take long to discover that there are more great options out there than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could use something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpublii.com/&quot;&gt;Publii&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s got everything I want, and even has an easy to use GUI. But after trying it for a little while, I quickly realised that unless there was a template that I really liked, it was going to be frustrating to customise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at others: Ghost, Hugo, Zola, Eleventy. So many good options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately, it came down to the availability of templates. Even though I intend to customise a lot, I wanted a very solid base to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, in the end, this new website is built on Astro. Which ticks all the right boxes, in terms of being modern and open source. It also appears to be very popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, I really love &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devaradise/devolio&quot;&gt;this template by Muhammad Syakirurohman&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s clean and elegant, putting projects and blog posts at the forefront. And since it&amp;#39;s built on Astro, the potential for customisation is unending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also a great boon that platforms like Astro integrate beautifully with markdown files. I&amp;#39;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; a lot over the past year for extensive note-taking, and being able to write blog posts the same way is very intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tricky part is, of course, learning Astro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding is something I&amp;#39;ve always dabbled in but never really become proficient at. So it&amp;#39;s only with the help of language model chat bots like ChatGPT and (most helpfully of all) Claude that I&amp;#39;ve been able to stuck into designing this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as helpful as AI bots are for getting started on something you don&amp;#39;t understand, it sucks to rely on them too much for too long. After a while, you want to ditch the training wheels and fly on your own, ya know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s the journey I have ahead of me! And that&amp;#39;s what makes it fun! Sure, I could fork out however much money each month for Squarespace and have a great website in minutes (or so all the podcast ads tell me). But then I wouldn&amp;#39;t feel like I am &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; the master of the website. This way, as long as I don&amp;#39;t absolutely tank the code into a scorching mess, nothing is holding me back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the key themes of 2024 has been not getting locked in. Not getting locked into a bad habit, or a particular way of thinking, or a single digital app or service. I&amp;#39;ve done enough of that in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s it, that&amp;#39;s my new site, and this has been the first blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the internet becoming &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; fragmented all the time, it&amp;#39;s wonderful to have my own independent space to bring together everything that relates to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hey, if you do find a link to my bank account... eh, you&amp;#39;re welcome to whatever&amp;#39;s there.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>web design</category><category>open source</category></item><item><title>My favourite soundtracks of 2023</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2023/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2023/</guid><description>My top original scores from TV, movies and games</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Brian-Tyler-conducting-an-orchestra.COTJUC-G.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite soundtracks of 2023&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Welcome! It&amp;#39;s high time we did this. Today, I’m sharing &lt;strong&gt;the definitive list of the 23 best soundtracks from 2023.&lt;/strong&gt; Objectively. Unequivocally. Indisputably. Agree or not, this is &lt;em&gt;the list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ranking covers a variety of soundtracks from films, TV shows, and video games—anything released as a musical album in 2023 counts, regardless of when the project itself came out. Those are the rules I’ve made up, and I’m sticking to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex justify-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ltGSqrqeN8Q?si=p93AjAhzE_qJLVh8&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video above, or read on below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflections on the Year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list was pretty challenging to put together—it’s already February, and here I sit, locking it all in. Does listening to more soundtracks each year make it easier? Nope. The more you hear, the harder it gets to narrow it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this year, my &lt;strong&gt;top dozen or so picks&lt;/strong&gt; were easy choices—they were shoe-ins for the list. But the &lt;strong&gt;bottom half&lt;/strong&gt;? That’s where things got tricky. I’ve been shuffling, adding, and trimming entries up until the very last week, constantly second-guessing. However, the time has come to finalize everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, let&amp;#39;s dive in—starting from #23 and counting all the way down to the #1 soundtrack of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grab some water, and let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23. &lt;em&gt;Wonderwell&lt;/em&gt; – Angelo Badalamenti &amp;amp; William Ross&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonderwell is a gentle and lush little film soundtrack that I find very easy to like. It&amp;#39;s got this really beautiful and delicate main theme by the late and great Angelo Badalamenti, and it&amp;#39;s used well throughout—you know I love when a score is bathed in its main theme. It captures a really effective sadness in just a few well-placed notes. The flutes and strings are very inviting. It&amp;#39;s played by the London Symphony Orchestra, so of course it sounds good. This one is the newest/latest addition to my list; I only just came across it recently, but it&amp;#39;s been growing on me rapidly, so I&amp;#39;m very glad to have squeezed it in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22. &lt;em&gt;Napoleon&lt;/em&gt; – Martin Phipps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Phipps brings his dynamic baroque kinda sound he&amp;#39;s always so good at to this Ridley Scott epic. And it&amp;#39;s placed somewhere between elegant drama and comic farce, which is quite a balance to maintain. But between godfather-ish mournful horns, elegant cultured strings, and opulent sophisticated choirs, the balance is something I find wonderful to listen to. I often find music by Martin Phipps to be really good to do other work to, like writing and things, when you need to focus. I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;21. &lt;em&gt;The Devil Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt; – Anne-Kathrin Dern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite a unique score by a composer I&amp;#39;m not familiar with for a film I know absolute nothing about. Weepy large dramatic choirs are joined by cool synths to create an enormous gothic flavour. I don&amp;#39;t know what this movie&amp;#39;s about, but the music&amp;#39;s certainly got a sci-fi futuristic flavour. Baroque choirs, pipe organ, electric guitar... it’s quite a mix. Sometimes it gets a bit noisy— for every beautiful classical choir piece there&amp;#39;s something disturbing and messy and sound designy. It certainly leans into horror at points. There are some great moments where the future synth and the gorgeous choirs come together, and it reminds me of &lt;em&gt;Warhammer Darktide&lt;/em&gt; from last year, and it’s pretty cool. I wish there was a little more recognisable melody, a little more shape, but I do enjoy what this is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20. &lt;em&gt;Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora&lt;/em&gt; – Pinar Toprak&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a large and expansive video game score by Pinar Toprak and a team of contributing composers, all continuing James Horner&amp;#39;s original &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; sound. So you can bet there are strong woodwinds and optimistic chanting choirs. And really there&amp;#39;s actually a lot of pleasant music here that creates a great atmosphere; a lot of it seems to be describing the lush natural world of Pandora. It does leave me wanting for some more memorable moments, like defined action setpieces or something. It just doesn&amp;#39;t do anything quite as striking as James Horner or Simon Franglen have done for the films. But that&amp;#39;s alright. This strikes me more as a gentle worldbuilding exercise, and in that it succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19. &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; – Joseph Shirley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year, Joseph Shirley took the reins from Ludwig Göransson on two big franchises—&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt;. And for what it&amp;#39;s worth, I think he&amp;#39;s done a much better than adequate job on both. In fact, they&amp;#39;re both really good. It must be so hard to take over from someone else who has famously given these stories such a unique musical style... and then what can you do? You can either respect that musical style and keep it going or change it up. Well, in both cases, Joseph Shirley has continued the established musical style, and it&amp;#39;s really genuinely good. I mean, I&amp;#39;m saying all this just to say, I don&amp;#39;t know why &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t higher on my list. And why &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t on the list. It was just a very competitive year, and I suppose it doesn&amp;#39;t feel like either of these scores did anything very bold or new that we haven&amp;#39;t heard in the respective previous entries. They&amp;#39;re just super solid. I mean that&amp;#39;s not to say uninteresting or boring or anything—&lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; continues in Ludwig Göransson&amp;#39;s template of really punchy, cool, rousing music, with unexpected uses of the human voice throughout. I&amp;#39;m super into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18. &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a bleak, anxious world of despair. &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; is a macabre atmospheric soundtrack that makes me feel like there are bugs crawling up my legs. It&amp;#39;s extremely evocative. The whole score is drenched in the reverb of a shadowy church—they found a great sound for this one. It really speaks to that medieval fantasy horror featuring the most evil of demons. It&amp;#39;s got this great sense of history too, like each piece is telling the story of ancient creatures and places. This music just makes me so restless and uncomfortable. So you may ask why I put it on here. Maybe I like being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17. &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt; – Benjamin Wallfisch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really solid superhero soundtrack and has some of my favourite music by Benjamin Wallfisch. It&amp;#39;s doing an awful lot of work in some setpieces in particular, bringing a lot of gravitas to a film that I&amp;#39;m otherwise quite reluctant to care about. There&amp;#39;s some really nice use of piano in some of the sweeping action tracks that has stuck with me. And there are some huge moments of grandeur. I mean, some of them, like the one you&amp;#39;ve just heard, I kinda think is honestly too grand and wonderful for the movie and the scene it scored. But I don&amp;#39;t mind, as a listener outside of the movie; it&amp;#39;s a great piece. It&amp;#39;s also got a bunch of Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s Batman theme, and that doesn&amp;#39;t hurt either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact - Fountain of Belleau&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music of &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt; is a relatively recent discovery for me. There&amp;#39;s a lot of music out there already, and this latest expansion release is full of wonderful music. It&amp;#39;s bright, colourful, and very playful. Playful is the big word I think. Throughout the album, the music dabbles with a whole range of styles and modes, but doesn&amp;#39;t forget to hold onto some lovely themes. There&amp;#39;s over 3 hours of music here, so I&amp;#39;m hoping to spend a lot more time in the future delving into this world, including the scores from the previous expansions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;15. &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3&lt;/em&gt; – John Murphy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back into the superhero realm with the third &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; . John Murphy is composing this time round, and the music has been taken in a very different direction to the previous soundtracks. This is a really emotional score, really. John Murphy leans into the tragedy and sadness at the heart of the film, and I love that about it. Although there&amp;#39;s a bit less action fun, it&amp;#39;s still quite space operatic, and there&amp;#39;s much more heartbreak and sentimentality. I didn&amp;#39;t expect to like it as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Survivor&lt;/em&gt; – Stephen Barton &amp;amp; Gordy Haab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; in dark mode. Everything&amp;#39;s rather bleak and grim and hard and overbearing. There&amp;#39;s more spooky, creepy, shadowy stuff in here than I expected. And a lot of the 4-hour runtime of the score is atmospheric, painting a range of scary, foreboding backdrops. But when the action kicks in, it&amp;#39;s thrilling. There&amp;#39;s just nothing like &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music. That descriptive brass and those rich agile strings. I swear with &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music you can always see these worlds so clearly— the empires and the blasters and the lightsabers. And like all of the best &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music, &lt;em&gt;Jedi Survivor&lt;/em&gt; does push a bit outside the established template, with some unique orchestrations and styles we haven&amp;#39;t heard in this world before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13. &lt;em&gt;Godzilla Minus One&lt;/em&gt; – Naoki Sato&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big wow, this soundtrack. It kinda blew me away. In some areas, it&amp;#39;s deceptively simple, but then it really just hits you. Especially inside the movie—this is one of the best scores for picture on my list. It really imbues each scene of the film with... energy. Often anxious energy. It&amp;#39;s got absolutely thrilling moments, but the thing I was most struck by was how incredibly anxious this score is. It elevates my heart rate; it&amp;#39;s physically effective and affecting. I&amp;#39;m in awe. As well as scoring significant setpieces with memorable original music, Naoki Sato also brings back the original Godzilla Main Title theme, as Bear McCreary did a few years ago in his &lt;em&gt;Godzilla&lt;/em&gt; score, for some pretty incredible &amp;quot;wow godzilla is wild&amp;quot; moments. But yeah, this is really engrossing stuff. Play it loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12. &lt;em&gt;Fast X&lt;/em&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m honestly really not a fan of the &lt;em&gt;Fast and Furious&lt;/em&gt; movies at all, but Brian Tyler knows what he&amp;#39;s doing. This is really impressive action scoring. It aims to be pretty grand and epic, with some choral punctuations and what I assume is a villain theme that dominates throughout the score, going head to head with Tyler&amp;#39;s heroic themes, some of which are now several years old. But what&amp;#39;s so important about the success of this music is that it doesn&amp;#39;t forget to have fun. It could easily be too serious, and at a couple of points, maybe it is. But for the most part, it&amp;#39;s just a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;em&gt;Migration&lt;/em&gt; – John Powell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s John Powell doing a colourful animated score, of course, it&amp;#39;s good. I mean, it&amp;#39;s not &lt;em&gt;How To Train Your Dragon&lt;/em&gt; , but not much is. This one is also about flying creatures—they&amp;#39;re just ducks, right? I think that&amp;#39;s right. And what a perfect provocation the concept of flight is for music, no matter the composer, but especially for John Powell. Anyway, this is tremendously enjoyable light adventure scoring with several good action cues and a few of those flourishes of wonder, awe, and delight that Powell is just the master of. His music is just so dextrous and always sounds good—the particular quality and texture of his orchestra is definitely one of my favourites out there. It&amp;#39;s always very creative too; there are surprises in here, like a bit of electric guitar at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson and the Olympians&lt;/em&gt; – Bear McCreary &amp;amp; Sparks &amp;amp; Shadows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right at the end of the year, we got this new adventure score by Bear McCreary and his Sparks &amp;amp; Sounds team. And it&amp;#39;s really just what you&amp;#39;d expect, which is a great thing. A memorable and noble main theme on French horn. Rich strings to build out the world. All imbued with the sense of wonder and magic that you need for a &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; story. The only damning thing to say about this score is that it&amp;#39;s really not that exciting compared to &lt;em&gt;Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; or other recent Bear McCreary scores. But that&amp;#39;s just because they&amp;#39;ve been so constantly terrific. Honestly, this really is great too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;em&gt;The Orville: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any sense of nostalgia for the great classical inspired sci-fi scores, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, etc., this is like a warm blanket. A 72-track, 4 and a half hour-long warm blanket, packed end-to-end with classical orchestral adventure film score writing. It&amp;#39;s almost too much to comprehend, really. But it does everything you&amp;#39;d expect: bold brassy &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; -y themes, expressive string ostinatos for &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; -like action cues, and all sorts of overt classical references to stuff like Holst&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Planets&lt;/em&gt; . And the cues are long—I love long setpiece cues, where the music really just gets to tell the story. Anyway, &lt;em&gt;The Orville&lt;/em&gt; has wonderful music. How lucky are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse&lt;/em&gt; – Daniel Pemberton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This score is absolutely genius. It&amp;#39;s so fast and clever and tight, and it absolutely has to be to keep up with the vivid torrent of ideas on screen throughout the movie. Daniel Pemberton&amp;#39;s themes for this world are so distinct and memorable. Just like the different frame rates and animation styles used for characters from different worlds, Pemberton uses such diverse musical styles to represent each theme and idea. It&amp;#39;s a miracle that it all comes together into something cohesive at the end. Top stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;em&gt;Forspoken&lt;/em&gt; – Gary Schyman &amp;amp; Bear McCreary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ultracool video game score by Gary Schyman and Bear McCreary really drew me in with some ear-catching melodies, often led by a dynamic female voice. It&amp;#39;s very much in that McCreary world of moody, appealingly shaped themes riddled throughout a heavy but not exhausting fantasy world. From track 1, it&amp;#39;s so instantly full of heartfelt, striving character. Great incorporation of some trap beats, some heavy drums, and agile piano amongst the swirling strings. I also love how cohesive and distinct its style is—you only need to hear the start of a track to go, ah, this must be &lt;em&gt;Forspoken&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny&lt;/em&gt; – John Williams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maestro is back! With &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt;! Expectations were high. I wasn&amp;#39;t disappointed. Of course, a lot of this album is retreads of &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; of the past. Or some action writing that is so similar to things we&amp;#39;ve heard before that it may as well be a needle drop. But there&amp;#39;s still so much new magic here. Helena&amp;#39;s Theme is the grand new concert piece, and the way it instantly dives straight back into that romantic classical writing, with large, shameless melodic leaps... Everything from John Williams is such a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; – Ludwig Göransson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;#39;s already been talked about so much in the soundtrack community; I don&amp;#39;t know that there&amp;#39;s much more to say. Not everyone loves it, that&amp;#39;s for sure, but I&amp;#39;m totally on board. I think &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; is an incredible followup to Ludwig Göransson&amp;#39;s first Christopher Nolan collaboration, &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt; . It creates such a gloomy tragic vibe with closely recorded expressive strings that sketch out these intricate patterns that feel like human thoughts. It succeeds at creating this atmosphere of an existential fairy tale, a bit like another one of my favourites of recent years, Justin Hurwitz&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;First Man&lt;/em&gt;. Beauty and dread, horror and wonder, all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;em&gt;Baldur&amp;#39;s Gate 3&lt;/em&gt; – Borislav Slavov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just jaw-droppingly beautiful. That is my primary reaction to most of &lt;em&gt;Baldur&amp;#39;s Gate 3&lt;/em&gt; by Borislav Slavov. This is the power of melodic music. Like a worm that crawls into your brain and lives there. This music immediately got deep under my skin. And yeah, it&amp;#39;s all about the melodies here. Just stunningly beautiful lyrical melodies. Sometimes performed unexpectedly simply, unexpectedly quietly, unexpectedly soulfully. These are some of the best themes of the year, and they&amp;#39;re done so much justice across the score. It&amp;#39;s got some of the best songs on a soundtrack in 2023 as well. &lt;em&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2&lt;/em&gt; from a few years back was great, but this is a new level. Borislav Slavov has received a lot of praise this year, and I think it&amp;#39;s all deserved and then some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;The Super Mario Bros. Movie&lt;/em&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never expected to be so very charmed by this, but I absolutely was and am. Brian Tyler went all out on this one. Not only does it cleverly incorporate heaps of previous Mario musical material, it makes it new and fresh and consistent and tight. It&amp;#39;s filled with such visceral joy; it makes you feel like you could fly. Even the villain theme is fun! And again, the orchestra just sounds so good in this. It&amp;#39;s a classic case of Brian Tyler featuring drums in a big orchestra, and his sound is so perfected at this point; I can&amp;#39;t believe how punchy it sounds. I&amp;#39;m so happy to have something that&amp;#39;s this colourful and fun near the top of my list—it&amp;#39;s not all just doom and gloom this year. I haven&amp;#39;t seen the movie, but I&amp;#39;ve certainly spent many hours of the past year listening to this amazing score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible - Dead Reckoning Part One&lt;/em&gt; – Lorne Balfe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; has always had good music. I mean it started with the brilliant themes by Lalo Schifrin in the 1960s, and for the movies, Danny Elfman, Hans Zimmer, Michael Giacchino, Joe Kramer, and Lorne Balfe have all put in stellar work. But I think this latest soundtrack is my favourite of the bunch. Lorne Balfe returns to take the melodrama to the next level. And he so perfectly musically represents the feeling of racing against time, of trying to go faster, of being pushed to your limits, of being up against impossible odds. And it&amp;#39;s all done in this larger-than-life romantic style, where everything is turned up to 11 and every emotion is the biggest thing you&amp;#39;ve ever felt. It&amp;#39;s much more emotional than any previous &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; score. It feels like this dark, exciting nightmare swirling all around you. I still don&amp;#39;t know how some of these tracks make me feel what they do. And the bongos! The coolest bongos of 2023! &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible: Dead Reckoning&lt;/em&gt; is an enormous and epic work by Lorne Balfe. And make sure you check out the expanded release, with about 3 hours of music. It&amp;#39;s glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a wrap on my &lt;strong&gt;fifth annual soundtrack list&lt;/strong&gt;! I’m so grateful to share this passion for scores and soundtracks with you every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Interesting Trends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 film scores&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2 TV scores&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;7 game scores&lt;/strong&gt; made this year’s list. TV scores dropped significantly from last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The diversity of composers is stronger—fewer repeating names, except Bear McCreary (3 times) and Brian Tyler (2 times).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading—see you next year!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>music</category><category>soundtracks</category></item><item><title>Performing in Black Comedy &amp; Love&apos;s Labour&apos;s Lost</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/performing-in-black-comedy-loves-labours-lost/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/performing-in-black-comedy-loves-labours-lost/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;In November and December 2018 I was ecstatic to be given the opportunity to act in two bright, lively and hilarious plays. Both were directed by Tony Rive and presented in Darwin&amp;#39;s Browns Mart Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First came Darwin Theatre Company&amp;#39;s Black Comedy, a tight and fast piece of British absurdity with some really fun physical gags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/45150055_912849388906359_7093587459455320064_o.BxjK5PC5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/46318028_315579192595919_4478786566214385664_n.DuoQ4vXS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s production of Love&amp;#39;s Labour&amp;#39;s Lost, a strange little Shakespeare, which was presented at Browns Mart alongside an excellent production of Animal Farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/48369142_2113532815371094_3019856140780437504_o.DdVXoRwS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_20181202_152330.DORv9V86.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also honoured to be given the opportunity to create the television advertisement for Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s shows, which you can view here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/300628614&quot;&gt;Animal Farm and Love&amp;#39;s Labour&amp;#39;s Lost TVC&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/corroiron&quot;&gt;Corrugated Iron Youth Arts&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreal amounts of fun making these shows with so many cool people.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>Darwin Fringe Show Vaudeville Knockout</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-knockout/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-knockout/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Yes, this was the sequel to the 2017 Fringe show I was a part of, &amp;quot;Vaudeville Variety&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was several months ago now, but better late than never! Vaudeville Knockout took the production to new heights for two evenings of wacky old-fashioned humour at Darwin&amp;#39;s Brown&amp;#39;s Mart Theatre. Many of the same cast and crew returned, but the characters were honed and polished a little further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_20180630_141828.JREND-fk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Russell (Charlie Chaplin) practising his boxing with new co-star Josh (Buster Keaton)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell and myself performed Who&amp;#39;s on first again, just like last year. And of course there were songs and there was comedy and a big silent comedy set piece in which I played the villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Screenshot_2018-07-13_at_22.23.20__25281_2529.BGvSNvXL.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m the one with the massive cape and hat and pirate cat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the lovely cast and crew, and of course everyone who came along to see the show. In many ways these ambitious little Fringe shows with a lightning-fast turnaround and little-to-no external support are more exciting than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>You Do You (Darwin International Film Festival Spark Film 2018)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/you-do-you-darwin-international-film-festival-spark-film-2018/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/you-do-you-darwin-international-film-festival-spark-film-2018/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;This year I was lucky enough to produce and co-direct one of the Darwin International Film Festival&amp;#39;s five &amp;quot;Spark&amp;quot; films. These are five ten minute scripts that are picked to be produced over a short three months and screened as a part of the festival in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180708_105408.BKJMdSG3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was a hoot having all these actual school kids play fake school kids in the film. The magic of cinema.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered several project ideas into the program this year, and the one that was picked to be produced was &amp;quot;You Do You&amp;quot;. This is a short film I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about, vaguely, since late last year. When I tried to write it earlier this year however, I found myself to be not very confident with the voice of the main character, a teenage girl. So I asked long-time collaborator Lexie Gregory to write it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180710_154235.BbamScb7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;#39;s Lexie herself, with DOP Nathaniel Kelly and star Koko Lawton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that was a great decision. Because what Lexie wrote was quite unlike my original plans, and quite unlike the films I&amp;#39;ve made before, but felt genuine and personal. The story is a little more honest than the stories I usually write myself. I was very excited to work on something that wasn&amp;#39;t my usual speed though. This experience was unique. The first time I&amp;#39;ve directed a film I didn&amp;#39;t write myself, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/IMG_5612.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Koko, me, and hey look it&amp;#39;s Max Conaghan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we shot the film in July. Worked with a bunch of lovely people. Shooting had its many challenges, as shooting always does. We had to be pretty disciplined about schedules because most of the crew currently resides interstate and were only in Darwin for a couple of weeks. There were some difficult times but overall it was actually one of the smoothest shoots I&amp;#39;ve been involved with. Co-directing with Lexie was lovely not least because it took some of that crazy pressure off my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180709_102608.s3NwoW2t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Koko, Joseph Baronio (beautiful producer), Nathaniel, Johanna Hayes (beautiful assistant producer) and Lexie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional shout-outs to Joseph Baronio and Johanna Hayes for being good producers. Oh man don&amp;#39;t you just love producers? Also Koko Lawton, who starred as the character Mickey. Koko &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; You Do You. If You Do You is anything it is because of Koko. The boppin&amp;#39; soundtrack is by my favourite music-wizards, Natalie Gall and Thomas Field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You Do You, and the four other DIFF Spark films, will be screening this Friday evening at the Deckchair Cinema. Nervous-excited to see what people think of what we&amp;#39;ve made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here&amp;#39;s the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dirOQQVYbyE&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>writing</category></item><item><title>We&apos;re Family Now showing at Deckchair Cinema</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/were-family-now-showing-at-deckchair-cinema/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/were-family-now-showing-at-deckchair-cinema/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Nathaniel Kelly&amp;#39;s debut feature film, which I had several key roles on, will be screening thrice at Darwin&amp;#39;s wonderful outdoor Deckchair Cinema in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/maxresdefault.DRi_JtpU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re Family now is about a lovable little suburban family. It was shot entirely in Darwin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/family-now-presented-nathaniel-kelly/&quot;&gt;12 May&lt;/a&gt; (with Q&amp;amp;A), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/were-family-now/&quot;&gt;18 May&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/were-family-now/&quot;&gt;26 May&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>world</category></item><item><title>Corrugated Iron&apos;s Whiplash</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/corrugated-irons-whiplash/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/corrugated-irons-whiplash/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;This week I attended a talk by Indonesian film director Garin Nugroho. One of the many things he talked about was a kind of theatre in which the actors rock up 30 minutes before the show and are given the story and characters there and then. There is extremely little preparation time, but the director briefly shares their plan, then the actors make the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Corrugated Iron skit show, &amp;quot;Whiplash Theatre&amp;quot;, has felt a little like that, as preparation time has been sparse. But like the theatre Garin Nugroho was talking about, it hasn&amp;#39;t been a bad thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180417_103327.CIbEnf3Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show is a collection of disconnected scenes and skits, most of which centre around a bit of a &amp;quot;road safety&amp;quot; theme. I really enjoyed working with these two excellent young performers (above), who brought to life a really wacky skit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_0559.WveQkCp2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a picture from a skit I appeared in myself, which included a video projection of me which keeps distracting the live actors who are trying to perform Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final show (of three) tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>creative</category><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>Books out for Courting 101</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/books-out-for-courting-101/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/books-out-for-courting-101/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago it was a delight to be a part of Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s little production of the short comedy play, Courting 101, in Malak&amp;#39;s Chambers Crescent Theatre. I played a crazy professor teaching a class (the audience) how to go on a date and basically succeed in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/24831194_1659967474060966_9058484353739540601_o.D82BrtQe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done and thanks for a great time director Kate and dramaturge Phil and actors Isaac, Amy, Jack, Lily, Michael and Haylee.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>A Very Bedroom Farce</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-very-bedroom-farce/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-very-bedroom-farce/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Last week I got to play an idiot called Trevor in Alan Ayckbourn&amp;#39;s very-rather-British 70&amp;#39;s comedy, &lt;em&gt;Bedroom Farce&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s a very understated play featuring particularly unique staging: three beds. The characters move between these three separate beds/bedrooms throughout the play, which takes place over one night, getting twisted up in all kinds of hilarious (but again, very understated!) hi-jinx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22550556_10155447919084017_2095557514036549656_o.BZH1uSy8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s Malcolm (Andrew) talking to Trevor (me). He comes to hate Trevor by the end. Everyone hates Trevor. Trevor hates Trevor. Poor Trevor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22688446_10214204836094570_6192755053270949281_n.DOvH8OGQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sniffing a prop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22780442_10155070967828366_4430284862911395921_n.RQAMZ5Ds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s Kate (Lizzy), Malcolm (still Andrew), Susannah (Haylee), Trevor (me again) and the wonderful behind-the-scenes duo who made it all happen: Tony Rive and Tania Lieman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22637187_137964010161712_6800881611417059328_n.Bf0dBNYp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally the full cast. Candid. Thanks for a fun time!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>comedy</category><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>Danny Elfman scored my short films</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/danny-elfman-scored-my-short-films/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/danny-elfman-scored-my-short-films/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a lie, of course. Rather, I made short films for Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of them. It was for a competition held on indi.com earlier this year. The brief: simply make a short film with a piece from Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s wonderful ballet score, &lt;em&gt;Rabbit &amp;amp; Rogue&lt;/em&gt;, as the soundtrack. Elfman is obviously one of my favourite composers of all time, so this was an opportunity I couldn&amp;#39;t pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two films I made were quite a challenge to produce. They were both shot over about a week, in Darwin&amp;#39;s unpredictable wet season, with many first-time actors and an absolutely bone-thin skeleton crew. In order to make production achievable I decided not to record sound on set. So every single sound you hear in both of these films, every piece of dialogue, every footstep, was added in post. It&amp;#39;s quite funny to think that just about everything you hear was either composed by Danny Elfman or recorded in my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is a fast-paced fantasy-comedy-adventure about a boy who summons an imaginary friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x1B_eI1ghBs&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the second is a strange little story about someone who cannot see the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GL3cYI_dMqU&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>original</category><category>fiction</category></item><item><title>Bamboo Moon The Tale of Princess Kaguya</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/bamboo-moon-the-tale-of-princess-kaguya/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/bamboo-moon-the-tale-of-princess-kaguya/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I loved Studio Ghibli&amp;#39;s 2013 film, &lt;em&gt;The Tale of Princess Kaguya,&lt;/em&gt; based on the ancient Japanese folktale, &lt;em&gt;The Tale of the Bamboo Cutter&lt;/em&gt;. What a beautiful, honest and tragic—yet equally uplifting—fairytale about love and loss. And told with a particularly delicate minimalism which only Studio Ghibli can make sexy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/hero_TheTaleOfPrincessKaguya-2014-1.BYYfUtCX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I heard local Darwin youth theatre company &lt;em&gt;Corrugated Iron&lt;/em&gt; was putting on a new adaptation of the very same &lt;em&gt;Tale of the Bamboo Cutter&lt;/em&gt;, I obviously got myself up in that hotness. &lt;strong&gt;Bamboo Moon&lt;/strong&gt; was the title of the production, and it reshaped the classic story into a dynamic short live show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_1c44a42c49b94065a4f7f677e0732b3d-mv2_d_3000_2001_s_2.ZnpnZICF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was put on as a free show with a three night run at the start of August. It was also staged outdoors in the wonderful dry season air, at the George Brown Botanic Gardens, and with excellent set design, props and costumes; it was a visually spectacular show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19264461_1498468726877509_7303060439500758941_o.-FKKAoHK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a snap from a rehearsal. I played Haru, the son of the Emperor, a very important and pretty cool guy, whose only real flaw is that he enjoys a wee bit of violence and war. Doh! There also is Taylor who played the eponymous Princess Kaguya and Tahlia who was my guard and lieutenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_737c7bfacdeb4e32ad38a1090241ade8-mv2_d_1334_2000_s_2.DgadTmF8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s me on the night. In character. Feeling things. Emotions. Drama. Acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_536be53651ed4c9eaa3c88314962c2ef-mv2_d_3000_2001_s_2.lxjYHEPS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s some of the other actors being funny on stage. Don&amp;#39;t worry, they were also in character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a dynamic outdoor youth performance, this show of course also included music, dance and circus! Look bamboo spirits on stilts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_3e76e6482be44198ad253bb2e2bfdb85-mv2_d_2000_1334_s_2.uCpfRaAC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And aerialist moon people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_43f13c91b1b6435880bc551193e045a3-mv2_d_2000_1333_s_2.D01v-lwL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are far more wonderful images of all these people than I can include here, but you can have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.corrugatediron.org.au/bamboo-moon-gallery&quot;&gt;the show&amp;#39;s photo gallery on the &lt;em&gt;Corrugated Iron&lt;/em&gt; website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I want to congratulate the dedicated crew, some of whom can be seen here...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/20622216_1547315035326211_3441157654226793550_n.uZDi-t16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the enormously friendly extended cast, some of whom can be seen here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_40b010241f784e10a25a88edaf9c7526-mv2_d_2000_1333_s_2.rH9VPXyH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>Darwin Fringe Show Vaudeville Variety starring Chaplin</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-variety-starring-chaplin/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-variety-starring-chaplin/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Darwin Fringe Festival was a month ago. It was good. I got to perform in two shows. One of them was &amp;quot;VAUDEVILLE VARIETY STARRING CHAPLIN&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19424371_10203367029492756_8291523085095684753_n.CZYJti_w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was... well, it was what it sounds like. A madhat Vaudeville-inspired couple of hours of comedy, song, slapstick and skits. It was produced by an insane chap who I shall refer to simply as Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith, and directed by a terrific gentleman called Tony Rive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19905157_127441441192012_6067102042981737728_n.BQIIdt-t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith (shown above) was the centrepiece of the evening, singing and larking through a variety of comedy bits. One of these was a slapstick restaurant skit starring the titular, aforementioned and again shown above Charlie Chaplin, played by Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19961263_127441531192003_1935005011975562630_n.C1Fxhwme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That photo displays a few other characters from the very same skit: (left to right) Haylee the gangster, Isaac the waiter, Damon the gangster, and me! I was the generically named &amp;quot;Male Lover&amp;quot;. In this case referring to the facts that I was A) a lover and B) of the male gender, as opposed to my defining character feature being that I &amp;quot;love males&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/VAUDEVILLE_VARIETY_SHOW_STARRING_CHAPLIN.mp4.00_45_43_09.Still010.CZpqNzEh.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;#39;s a snap from the night itself (thanks videographer Nathaniel Kelly!) in which Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith and I can be seen performing the famous Abbott and Costello skit, &lt;em&gt;Who&amp;#39;s on first&lt;/em&gt;. Beast of a piece to learn, but it&amp;#39;s mega funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all of the wonderful cast and crew and brilliant musicians and everyone who came to see it. A great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>La La Land Worst thing ever or best thing ever?</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/la-la-land-worst-thing-ever-or-best-thing-ever/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/la-la-land-worst-thing-ever-or-best-thing-ever/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;La La Land is a fun musical and an optimistic fairytale about the entertainment industry. I would have thought it&amp;#39;d be an unlikely target for critical controversy, but here we are. People love to hate La La Land just as much as others love to love it. Most audiences and critics I&amp;#39;ve come across are firmly on one side or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/rs-248320-emma-stone-ryan-goseling-la-la-land-sing-dance-trailer1.BcTM8p02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like a lame division to me. Firstly, haters: you&amp;#39;re wrong. The film just wants to be pure joy. How can you hate pure joy? Or even an attempt at pure joy? Are you Hitler? Hitler probably didn&amp;#39;t hate joy, so who do you think you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, lovers: I love your love, but you know those hugs that are painful? Like, bear hugs, you know? Many of you are hugging La La Land to death! It&amp;#39;s a movie, an imperfect movie, possibly a great imperfect movie, but there&amp;#39;s no need to stab its critics in the face. I mean, are you Hitler? I don&amp;#39;t think Hitler stabbed people in the face, so who do you think you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, I get it. It&amp;#39;s emotional. It&amp;#39;s a movie about a glowing spirit in the face of adversity. A song and a dance in hard times. The other day I was in a lovely casual conversation when one guy said he walked out of La La Land. WALKED OUT. Hated it that much. Yes, that triggered me. My lips wanted to scream-forth: &amp;quot;BUT THAT OPENING NUMBER WAS IT NOT MAGICAL?&amp;quot; But I held strong. I extracted myself from the conversation, taking deep breaths, thinking about simpler times. Then I got a knife and ran back and stabbed the idiot in the face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiddin&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/lalalandcinema_-_Edited.CuI_cN0f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;#39;s going to win too many Oscars, but we simply ought not start a war over La La Land. La La Land wouldn&amp;#39;t want that. Respect La La Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people just don&amp;#39;t know how wonder-filled this movie (and soundtrack) is. Are they wrong? Yes. Are they Hitler? Probably not. They&amp;#39;re just not La La.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>anecdote</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>ramble</category><category>review</category></item><item><title>Michael Giacchino King of Composers?</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/michael-giacchino-king-of-composers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/michael-giacchino-king-of-composers/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;If, like me, you&amp;#39;re a fan of film, TV or video game soundtracks, then &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/&quot;&gt;The Soundcast&lt;/a&gt; is one of the podcasts you should be listening to. Not just because it&amp;#39;s a high quality show, or because &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2015/03/episode-80-cue-awards-2014.html&quot;&gt;I appear on it as a guest from time to time&lt;/a&gt;, or because it&amp;#39;s one of the not-many soundtrack-related podcasts out there, but because regular hosts Christopher Coleman and Erik Woods frequently do a great job of discussing the state of scores and soundtracks in a broad sense. Their show stands out because they don&amp;#39;t just debate whether &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is the worst thing ever or the best thing ever (one of the most over-discussed topics of recent months), but also attempt to dive into interesting, original and timely subjects such as &lt;em&gt;is modern Hollywood music &amp;quot;dumbed down&amp;quot;?&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;what actually makes a popular theme great?&lt;/em&gt; They&amp;#39;re interested by what it means to be a soundtrack fan, and how that meaning is ever-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their latest episode Chris and Erik discuss the concept of composer dominance. They cite John Williams and Hans Zimmer as dominant film composers of the past, and note that Michael Giacchino - through the abundance and prominence of his recent projects - is clearly next in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-ep-15-composer.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/soundcast_stereo_15.CKlSD-H4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-ep-15-composer.html&quot;&gt;Have a listen to the episode&lt;/a&gt; for their discussion, including their thoughts on whether composer dominance is a bad thing (spoiler: they decide it probably isn&amp;#39;t (sub-spoiler: I agree with them)). Here, I want to briefly jot down some thoughts I have about Michael Giacchino being the latest head honcho in the film music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me five years ago: &lt;em&gt;hey Thomas, in five years who do you want to be the composer Hollywood uses for like everything?&lt;/em&gt;, I probably would have mentioned Giacchino. If you&amp;#39;d asked me who I wanted to score &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; (other than Williams of course), same answer. Sure, Giacchino has his fair share of critics, but on the whole he is a champion for many classic film music fans. I mean, his music is clearly Williams-esque (even when he isn&amp;#39;t charged with mimicking Williams - which, granted, happens fairly often), and who doesn&amp;#39;t love (former Composer King) John Williams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[... rest of the text continues in similar format ...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/giacchino.Cu9Xwnm6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (12/02/2017):&lt;/strong&gt; Wowzeedooza, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tracksounds.com/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-listener-reaction-3.html&quot;&gt;Soundcast Stereo did a response to my response&lt;/a&gt;. Response-ception.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>ramble</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>#HeWillNotDivideUs First Impressions</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/hewillnotdivideus-first-impressions/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/hewillnotdivideus-first-impressions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A single video camera hangs from a wall on 37th Street in New York, beaming live pictures around planet Earth, for anyone to see. It was activated last week and shall continue for the next four years. But what is the significance of this one shot; what is this little camera hoping to capture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He Will Not Divide Us&amp;quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hewillnotdivide.us/&quot;&gt;#hewillnotdivideus&lt;/a&gt;) is the latest experimental social art project published under the name of anti-celebrity Shia Saide LaBeouf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Shia LaBeouf. Once the uninteresting star of Michael Bay&amp;#39;s TRANSFORMERS trilogy, now one of the weirdest and most unpredictable contemporary celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/1.BYQDqLaP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaBeouf has been a strange fellow, neck deep in drama and run-ins with police for over a decade, but the turning point in the LaBeouf saga, in my view, was Rob Cantor&amp;#39;s music video from a few years back about the &amp;quot;Actual Cannibal Shia LaBeouf&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o0u4M6vppCI&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that point on, LaBeouf was no longer just a Hollywood performer, but also a man with a mythic aura. Shia surprise, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came his stunts, of which there are many. Most notable are probably &lt;a href=&quot;http://newhive.com/allmymovies&quot;&gt;#ALLMYMOVIES&lt;/a&gt; and I AM NOT FAMOUS ANYMORE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/2.3zSKtSu7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes Shia&amp;#39;s latest, and most ambitious, livestream project. A four year long livestream in protest of the presidency of Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. The guy does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like all of Shia&amp;#39;s livestreams, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hewillnotdivide.us/&quot;&gt;#HEWILLNOTDIVIDEUS&lt;/a&gt; is weird. Really weird. In some ways it&amp;#39;s difficult to see the point. And I can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if it will cause more harm than good. Will this project against division in fact carve a deeper divide?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[... rest of the text continues in a similar format ...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (12/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Welp, that didn&amp;#39;t last long. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2017/02/10/he-will-not-divide-us-livestream-shut-down/?sr_source=Facebook&quot;&gt;Shia LaBeouf&amp;#39;s anti-Trump livestream has been shut down for public safety&lt;/a&gt;. Unsurprising, and sounds very fair, but it&amp;#39;s hard not to be a little disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (21/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaaand it&amp;#39;s back. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2017/2/18/14659164/he-will-not-divide-us-exhibit-el-rey-theater-albuquerque-shia-labeouf&quot;&gt;Relocated to New Mexico&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty close to a road. Think I just saw some people nearly get run down by a car. What is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (25/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaaaaaaaaaaaand &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pedestrian.tv/news/entertainment/shia-labeoufs-live-steam-shut-down-again-after-gun/da2b58cc-dd22-4795-bca5-8711e44bb5c6.htm&quot;&gt;it&amp;#39;s gone again, after gunshots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>world</category><category>ramble</category></item><item><title>A Prequel to Conductor of Earth</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-prequel-to-conductor-of-earth/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-prequel-to-conductor-of-earth/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had a fair bit of fun making the short film Conductor of Earth, and since it won&amp;#39;t be publicly viewable for a while yet I decided to follow in the footsteps of George Lucas and Peter Jackson, and do a prequel. And that prequel is called Miracle Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/SquareCover_MiracleMan2_smaller.BF7-ese-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miracle Man&lt;/em&gt; introduces &lt;em&gt;Conductor of Earth&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s titular character, Aidan, and explores some of the activities he got up to before the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s available both as an eBook and an Audio Drama (read by some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; cool people). &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/film/miracle-man&quot;&gt;Jump over to the project page to get it now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy! And huge thanks to everyone who helped make it!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>podcast</category><category>films</category><category>creative</category><category>original</category></item><item><title>New Website (Again)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-again/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Feels like only last year that I had a brand new website (it was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website you&amp;#39;re currently looking at (unless you&amp;#39;re pretty far into the future, in which case hi can mobile phones do 3d printing yet?) is the latest website I&amp;#39;ll be using to share with you whatever trouble I get up to so that you can feel like a co-conspirator (or alert the authorities). It was built with blood, sweat and &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewcollins.me/&quot;&gt;Drew Collins&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s nice and green and makes it very easy to see my latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like last year though, I feel the need to tip my hat to my previous website. It had charm. Its existence was marvellous and, like all great things, brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/FireShot_Capture.CxnnopHp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is good unless it&amp;#39;s bad.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>website</category><category>technology</category></item><item><title>A Student Film Conclusion</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-conclusion/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-conclusion/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Six days remain before we have to submit a cut of this short film to the university. Sinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we&amp;#39;ve picture-locked, the sound edit is half done, the original score is nearly final (woot!) and the colour grade is coming along nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keen readers may have noticed the way I wooted at only one of the items in that list. Yeah, it&amp;#39;s all good stuff but the score is my favourite. Music is what inspires me to make films, so it&amp;#39;s extremely important to me for the final product to have something good. I&amp;#39;m very glad to have accidentally stumbled across the YouTube channel of one English gentlemen called Thomas Field earlier this year. From his videos I could quickly determine that I liked his style and his sensibilities. Luckily he agreed to compose for Conductor of Earth, and despite giving him very little time to actually pull it together, he has seemingly effortlessly produced a wonderful thematic score for the film. It&amp;#39;s a very particular and magical sensation the first time you hear music someone has created to accompany a story and characters you made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway that&amp;#39;s going well. And we&amp;#39;ve done lots of editing on the film, obviously. We&amp;#39;ve also had many watch it and they&amp;#39;ve given us lots of feedback. Much of the feedback is conflicting and therefore frustrating and difficult to process, but that&amp;#39;s to be expected. We live in such a subjective world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has brought us to crafting quite a streamlined, cut-down version of the film, which is all good and fine, but in typical director fashion I look forward to playing around with an expanded cut in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A new poster featuring the handsome lead and a bunch of names.&quot; height=&quot;356&quot; src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSMXJKOWg3eDFSRk0&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;A new poster featuring the handsome lead and a bunch of really great names&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Sorry to pull a twist on you but the title of this blog post was a lie. This isn&apos;t really the conclusion of this production journey. I mean, we&apos;re not even out of post-production yet, let alone getting the film out there and seen by people. And you! You should most certainly have a watch. I like you.

&lt;p&gt;Anyway ta ta for now.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category><category>original</category></item></channel></rss>