<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Thomas Midena</title><description>Generally genuinely enthusiastic</description><link>https://thomid.me/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 04:04:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>My favourite soundtracks of 2024</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2024/</guid><description>My top original scores from TV, movies and games</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thumbnail_v3.D3oXGXiW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite soundtracks of 2024&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For the sixth year in a row, I&amp;#39;ve created a list of my favourite soundtrack music of the year. This year I present my &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; top original scores released in the year 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex justify-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ujTxANp-6FA?si=7YNg_xTN2kIV7kzm&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video above presents this list with short clips from each score, but below you can find my list in written form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;24. &lt;strong&gt;IF&lt;/strong&gt; – Michael Giacchino&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/24IF.tfl0gwun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;#39;s a colourful and delightful Michael Giacchino score! He&amp;#39;s very much in his Pixar mode here; cutesy melodies with playful instrumentation, whistling and upbeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never really gets very complicated or intricate, but it&amp;#39;s very pleasant and in places effectively touching and nostalgic. The only downside is that on album it struggles to really get going. There are great statements of themes, but even on the suite tracks they somehow struggle to take off into a really satisfying cue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, beautiful short statements are better than no statements at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23. &lt;strong&gt;RED ROOMS&lt;/strong&gt; – Dominique Plante&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/23RedRooms.hEzu5G5p.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of this score is this courtly sort of baroque canon, lulling us into a sense of security and order. It sounds like progress, but underneath there&amp;#39;s certainly a sense of irony, of farce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other places, this film score also features some strange, twisted material with modulating strings and trance-inducing percussion. Plus some distorted screams in places, to make sure you&amp;#39;re really discomforted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a memorable score for a disturbing film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22. &lt;strong&gt;THE DRY 2: FORCE OF NATURE&lt;/strong&gt; – Peter Raeburn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22TheDry2.Cc7iX_9h.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a surprisingly sweet and tender score that—actually, no, the sweetness and tenderness wasn&amp;#39;t the surprising part about &lt;em&gt;The Dry 2&lt;/em&gt; . What surprised me is how epic and sweeping it can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relatively contained mystery movie here didn&amp;#39;t necessarily beg for such scope, but this music leans into a heightened sense of melodrama in a way that I absolutely love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m also delighted to have something Australian on the list this year. Rare for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;21. &lt;strong&gt;WOODWALKERS&lt;/strong&gt; – Anne-Kathrin Dern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/21Woodwalkers.DeghGM6W.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne-Kathrin Dern has been on my radar since &lt;em&gt;The Devil Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt;, and this was my favourite score of hers I heard in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;#39;s done well here working with a film that was clearly using temp tracks from things like &lt;em&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean&lt;/em&gt; and maybe some other Remote Control scores. And when I hear something that&amp;#39;s clearly following a temp, emulating the pattern of a cue I&amp;#39;m much more familiar with, I become very interested in how this composer has made their music different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even in those temp-y places, &lt;em&gt;Woodwalkers&lt;/em&gt; is plenty original. Its main themes are full and rich, blanketing the whole score in magic. I love the warm, heavy strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, &lt;em&gt;Woodwalkers&lt;/em&gt; is rather wondrous and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20. &lt;strong&gt;THE PENGUIN&lt;/strong&gt; – Mick Giacchino&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/20Penguin.CFZeEa1y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had Michael Giacchino, now let&amp;#39;s have his son, Mick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;#39;t a massive orchestra on this score, but the instruments sound so good. Mick Giacchino is clearly benefiting from some family expertise in giving character to the orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But yeah, this is deliberately more intimate and smaller in scale than &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;, though it continues many of the same musical ideas. Disturbing psycho-esque strings, for example, are used to great effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main motif for &lt;em&gt;The Penguin&lt;/em&gt; is a simple little two-note riff, like Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s Batman theme. It&amp;#39;s an instantly iconic identifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all culminates in a really wonderful frantic, chaotic, powerful main theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19. &lt;strong&gt;WICKED&lt;/strong&gt; – John Powell and Stephen Schwartz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19Wicked.BySbvtJB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting one, because since it&amp;#39;s a musical we kind of need to clarify: am I talking about the score, or the songs, or both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;#39;m here doing this because I&amp;#39;m primarily a fan of orchestral music, so that&amp;#39;s where my focus is. And John Powell and Stephen Schwartz have made a really luscious colourful score in that regard. It has really wonderful moments of incredibly detailed expansive composition—some of the most beautiful &lt;em&gt;moments&lt;/em&gt; in a score this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that doesn&amp;#39;t let it reach really great heights, in my opinion, is the fact that it&amp;#39;s clearly connected to a musical. So anytime the orchestral score feels like it&amp;#39;s building to something... it doesn&amp;#39;t quite get there, because it&amp;#39;s been building to a song, which is over on the other soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That handicaps it a little bit. But still, some of these tracks are pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18. &lt;strong&gt;CALL OF DUTY: BLACK OPS 6&lt;/strong&gt; – Jack Wall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/18BlackOps6.lJA5-gAi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m still pretty new to being a fan of the music of this series, but a couple years ago Bear McCreary&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; was my favourite score of the whole year, so I&amp;#39;m pretty on board for each new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;Black Ops 6&lt;/em&gt; by Jack Wall reminded me in some ways of how entertaining I found that Bear McCreary one. This is a big and propulsive score... lots of musical ideas, really energetic and pulse-pounding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally that becomes too much, a bit of a Wall of sound (so to speak), but throughout the album there are points where I think that mix is just right, and it feels like a big action blockbuster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17. &lt;strong&gt;CONCORD&lt;/strong&gt; – Daniel Pemberton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/16Concord.DmdWtDiO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to a much less popular game, to say the least. A game that failed so spectacularly you can&amp;#39;t even play it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we get to keep Daniel Pemberton&amp;#39;s score, which is super charming and energetic. It sort of does the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; thing, of having contemporary rhythms and some classical heroic motifs on top, but I&amp;#39;d say &lt;em&gt;Concord&lt;/em&gt; actually leans a little more cool and modern compared to &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s sometimes kooky retro style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, it&amp;#39;s certainly good at hyping me up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. &lt;strong&gt;WE WERE THE LUCKY ONES&lt;/strong&gt; – Rachel Portman &amp;amp; Jon Ehrlich&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/17WeWereTheLuckyOnes.BzbgrJuo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing like a bit of Rachel Portman to tug on your heartstrings. Here with Jon Ehrlich too, we have a classy drama score that I really enjoyed, especially when it goes big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it soars, it&amp;#39;s really something. When that main theme kicks in, your heart explodes. That&amp;#39;s just Rachel Portman, that&amp;#39;s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;15. &lt;strong&gt;THAT CHRISTMAS&lt;/strong&gt; – John Powell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/15ThatChristmas.DNb4jeOa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting this above &lt;em&gt;Wicked&lt;/em&gt; is probably a little controversial, but for me, &lt;em&gt;That Christmas&lt;/em&gt; was the John Powell music that most delighted me this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s whimsical and Christmas-y and gets just as playful as any of the best John Powell scores from over the years. It&amp;#39;s yet another reminder, as if we needed it, of just how agile John Powell&amp;#39;s writing can be, with cues that jump from idea to idea without ever feeling too busy or directionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, as all John Powell fans know very well, when it comes to melody and leitmotif, he&amp;#39;s one of the best in the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14. &lt;strong&gt;ARK: THE ANIMATED SERIES&lt;/strong&gt; – Gareth Coker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/14ARKAnimatedSeries.CJ8qdqk8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gareth Coker has created a lot of music for the &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; series of games over the years, but now here he is doing a score to an &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; animated series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#39;s brought over many of his great existing themes, and he continues to flesh out this bombastic soundscape. I just find all of the music in this series so listenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to contrast with the bombast, there&amp;#39;s some really delicate, gentle, romantic material in here too, which surprised me a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically this release is labelled as Volume 1, but I don&amp;#39;t believe there&amp;#39;s been a Volume 2... yet? Which is fine. This release is uh... over 3 hours long. There&amp;#39;s so much to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13. &lt;strong&gt;FINAL FANTASY VII REBIRTH&lt;/strong&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/13FinalFantasy.BvPyqKDl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those soundtracks that&amp;#39;s kind of impossible to summarise. It is many hours of music. Not all of it is great, and a lot of it is in styles of music I don&amp;#39;t really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But so much more of it is great than needs to be, and some of it is out of this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as a re-imagining of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;, this sees the return and reinvigoration of some of the greatest themes in the history of video games. Many of the reiterations are beautiful beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only worry is finding the time to listen properly to all of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12. &lt;strong&gt;PRINCE OF PERSIA: THE LOST CROWN&lt;/strong&gt; – Mentrix &amp;amp; Gareth Coker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/12PrinceofPersia.Coz1L4tr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game score has a little bit of &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; about it, with some electrifying high-tempo beats. It&amp;#39;s got some really cool tracks, and when it comes to the main theme, which is my favourite part of the soundtrack, its presentation can be so huge and enormous, like the example you&amp;#39;ve just heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t expect &lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; to sound like &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt;, but thanks to Gareth Coker, that&amp;#39;s sometimes the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; is higher than &lt;em&gt;ARK&lt;/em&gt; on my list because overall I just found it to be a newer and fresher experience in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11. &lt;strong&gt;MASTERS OF THE AIR&lt;/strong&gt; – Blake Neely&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/11MastersoftheAir.B6cWSQBh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blake Neely has big shoes to fill in this follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Band of Brothers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Pacific&lt;/em&gt;. And I think he really pulls it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the sort of sentimental World War II soundtrack that I was hoping for. It combines some gloriously wistful, patriotic sop with some really tense and exciting action cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s really what it says on the tin, and that&amp;#39;s a great thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;HOUSE OF THE DRAGON SEASON 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Ramin Djawadi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/10HouseoftheDragon.B2KeLaao.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dark and brooding score here for a season of &lt;em&gt;House of the Dragon&lt;/em&gt; that&amp;#39;s all about the inevitable escalation of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;#39;s actually a recurring motif that exactly represents that theme, sometimes in the form of this foreboding wailing female vocal. It&amp;#39;s really raw and tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this soundtrack is quite bleak, similar to previous Ramin Djawadi &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; music, but it&amp;#39;s still full of standout pieces of beautiful montage and intense action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;TALES OF KENZERA: ZAU&lt;/strong&gt; – Nainita Desai&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/9TalesofKenzera.JiZ5ezau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one came out of nowhere for me. I&amp;#39;m not familiar with the game or the composer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s really exciting though. Brilliant musical storytelling—you don&amp;#39;t need anything but the music to start seeing vivid images. There are clearly a lot of inspirations here, but what immediately jumped out to me is some very big Ludwig Goransson &lt;em&gt;Black Panther&lt;/em&gt; inspiration, particularly on a couple of action cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, again, being able to see a clear line between this and its inspirations doesn&amp;#39;t negatively impact my enjoyment in the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a gorgeous and vibrant soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;TRANSFORMERS ONE&lt;/strong&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/8TransformersOne.0dIf_I6t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never thought a spiritual sequel to Brian Tyler&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Transformers Prime&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack from 2012 is something we&amp;#39;d get. But here it is. Brian Tyler even references those great old themes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, even if you don&amp;#39;t already love the music of &lt;em&gt;Transformers Prime&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Transformers One&lt;/em&gt; is so great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Tyler gives the Transformers such profound nobility in his iconic long-winded melodies. There are few things that I love more than a big melodic Brian Tyler blockbuster score, and this really is another good one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some really, really big heavy brass here too, and that always gets me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;YOUNG WOMAN AND THE SEA&lt;/strong&gt; – Amelia Warner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/7YoungWoman.Dy_Vv1BB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between &lt;em&gt;Transformers One&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Young Woman and the Sea&lt;/em&gt;, this is definitely the most uplifting, inspirational section of my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This score is really wonderful, magical and beautiful. It&amp;#39;s got a bit of Enya DNA in there, and there aren&amp;#39;t many 2024 scores I can say that about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a couple of brief little moments, the orchestration even reminded me of Justin Hurwitz&amp;#39; &lt;em&gt;First Man&lt;/em&gt;, and that&amp;#39;s just an all-timer for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, solidly entertaining album, end to end. It only gets better with each listen, and that&amp;#39;s why it&amp;#39;s this high on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;DUNE: PART TWO&lt;/strong&gt; – Hans Zimmer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/6Dune2.oY_Hy9tQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s funny, these days Zimmer&amp;#39;s presence is felt so keenly across the board, on film scores he had no direct hand in, so it feels strange to actually come to one that&amp;#39;s got his name on the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the thing is, and what&amp;#39;s clear in &lt;em&gt;Dune Part Two&lt;/em&gt; , is that the Hans Zimmer of today is quite different to the Hans Zimmer we&amp;#39;ve heard in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses many of the same elements and techniques, but &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; is much more minimalistic and experiential than a lot of his most famous scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from interviews how passionate he is about this particular story, and how personal the experience of creating this music is for him. And that really comes through in the music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s full of so much feeling, saying so much with, at times, so little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piece you just heard is for me the most heartbreaking piece of the year. Zimmer&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Dune: Part Two&lt;/em&gt; may not be eligible for an Oscar, but it&amp;#39;s eligible to be high on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;HELLDIVERS 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Wilbert Roget, II; Ross Tregenza&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/5Helldivers2.CSoPE8RF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helldivers&lt;/em&gt; is mad fun! Talk about &lt;em&gt;Starship Troopers&lt;/em&gt; on steroids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s an upbeat, rousing action blockbuster, with a cheeky sense of irony that never gets in the way of just being FUN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murray Gold once talked about comedic music, and that tough balance of knowing when to lean into the comedy, and when to play it straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for the most part, Wilbert Roget II plays this perfectly straight, and I think that&amp;#39;s the right approach. He gives himself full permission to lean into the naïve capitalistic heroism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This album is on the shorter side of things, but it&amp;#39;s just some of the most fist-pumping fun I&amp;#39;ve heard all year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;WORLD OF WARCRAFT: THE WAR WITHIN&lt;/strong&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/4TheWarWithin.md8WuhUJ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know much about my musical tastes, you know I can never get enough &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; in my ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s just one of the great musical landscapes, inspired by all of the greatest epic fantasy music of decades past, and taking it in bold new directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after a couple of slightly disappointing soundtrack releases, I think &lt;em&gt;The War Within&lt;/em&gt; is a return to form for the series. It&amp;#39;s packed full of new ideas, and it&amp;#39;s beautifully recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to this album on repeat for a couple of months in 2024, and it helped me get through some challenging work. I find that music with this much character, magic, and heart is just a perfect companion through difficult times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;STAR WARS OUTLAWS&lt;/strong&gt; – Wilbert Roget, II; Kazuma Jinnouchi; Jon Everist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/3StarWarsOutlaws.BZrrcKPa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, it&amp;#39;s another game score by Wilbert Roget II!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m obviously a sucker for some &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music, but its combination with contemporary styles in recent years has been hit and miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not one of the people who thinks &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; always needs to sound like John Williams, but I do think many attempts to leave that classical romantic style behind have been fairly disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here however, I think they found a great balance. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Outlaws&lt;/em&gt; references some Williams themes, surprisingly appropriately, like its use of the Imperial theme from &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt; . But for the most part, it&amp;#39;s original and exciting, taking us into new areas of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one thing it does so well is keeping a sound that&amp;#39;s a little unusual, a little alien, a little not of our world. That allows the composers to incorporate modern elements without it losing all of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars-y-ness&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&amp;#39;s so cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;DRAGON AGE: THE VEILGUARD&lt;/strong&gt; – Hans Zimmer &amp;amp; Lorne Balfe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/2DragonAge.iLsD732Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; game score!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a little surprising to have the new &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; this high on the list. I mean, the series has always had great music, particularly &lt;em&gt;Inquisition&lt;/em&gt;. But I liked this entry by Hans Zimmer and Lorne Balfe (well, let&amp;#39;s be real, mostly Lorne Balfe) way more than I anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in terms of measuring a score by how much fun I&amp;#39;ve had with it, how much enjoyment I&amp;#39;ve gotten out of it—well, from that perspective, &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age: The Veilguard&lt;/em&gt; deserves to be here at number 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main title theme, which is heaps of fun, and probably where Zimmer&amp;#39;s influence is most prominent, actually sounds a lot like Junkie XL. And not in a bad way. It&amp;#39;s like Junkie XL&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Mortal Engines&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s pretty over-the-top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of recognisable modes of Lorne Balfe here... some &lt;em&gt;His Dark Materials&lt;/em&gt; in the thematic shapes, a bit of &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; grandiosity, and a whole lot of &lt;em&gt;Skylanders&lt;/em&gt;. This really is basically &lt;em&gt;Skylanders&lt;/em&gt; with a bigger, darker sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And overall, it&amp;#39;s much more upbeat than I&amp;#39;d expect from &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt;. In the end, this score just has a whole lot of tracks that I really really enjoyed. Many times, on repeat. And I was thoroughly entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;RINGS OF POWER SEASON 2&lt;/strong&gt; – Bear McCreary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;float-left mr-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/1RingsofPower.DXCaEMpp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It almost feels like a cop out. I tried to find anything that could knock this off the number one spot, but I couldn&amp;#39;t. For me, &lt;em&gt;The Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; is just head and shoulders above everything else out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scores for the first season blew everything else away. Some come-down was to be expected in this follow-up, and yes, it re-treads a lot of the same territory, which isn&amp;#39;t quite as novel this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the leitmotif writing on this is still just so good, and it&amp;#39;s full of wondrous new ideas, like the powerful theme for Rhûn and the delicate sounds of Eregion. Meanwhile, themes from the previous season are refreshed with some of their best presentations yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so good, and just like last time, there&amp;#39;s so much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of strong themes, great orchestration, and satisfying cohesive cues, &lt;em&gt;Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; continues to be my favourite music of recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew! There we are, another year of this down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, I feel bad about all the things I couldn&amp;#39;t fit on the list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t even put on the &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; movie, or the &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; game, or the &lt;em&gt;Gladiator&lt;/em&gt; sequel. There were about half a dozen scores that during the year I felt super sure would be on the list, so I even wrote up a little blurb about them for this video. But they ended up not fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a pretty even split across categories this year—I had 6 TV shows, 9 movies, and 9 video games. But the top of the list leaned heavily into the video games. I guess that&amp;#39;s largely where I found the most musical entertainment this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movies were down big-time from last year, when I had 14 film scores. And only one score on my list this year was nominated at the Academy Awards—&lt;em&gt;Wicked&lt;/em&gt;. Though that&amp;#39;s not unusual, I can&amp;#39;t remember ever really agreeing with the Oscar picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a couple of double-up composers this time around... having John Powell twice isn&amp;#39;t surprising. Wilbert Roget II at spots 3 and 5 is a little. Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s name is there twice, on &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt;, but really I do think of &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; as a Lorne Balfe score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always love to see the surprises that come out of nowhere for me each year. Like, I had never heard of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Kenzera&lt;/em&gt; until a couple months ago, and even now I know nothing about it except that I like the music. It&amp;#39;s so much fun to expand the pool of things you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next year!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>music</category><category>soundtracks</category></item><item><title>My favourite media of 2024</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-media-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-media-2024/</guid><description>The things I watched, read and listened to most (and what they say about my year)</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/trakt2024.BMftwwmy.png&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite media of 2024&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Like most humans, I just can&amp;#39;t get enough stories in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TV Shows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024 was a great year for TV. My top 10 features a range of things I loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomastvshowstrakt2024.DDl_6Dzl.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom end is &lt;strong&gt;The Curse&lt;/strong&gt;, which was divisive but completely enthralled me. And it proved that I don&amp;#39;t only love Nathan Fielder for his provocative reality TV satire, but also for his fiction! And bloody hell, Emma Stone is good. I know the finale didn&amp;#39;t work for a lot of people, but I think about it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;#39;s &lt;strong&gt;Fallout&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Blue Eye Samurai&lt;/strong&gt; — colourful genre shows that are widely acclaimed, and I can see why. These shows make their lore-rich worlds perfectly accessible for any old shmuck, without dumbing things down too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we&amp;#39;ve got the shows that brought me deep into the spy game. I caught up on all of &lt;strong&gt;Slow Horses&lt;/strong&gt; in 2024, and I&amp;#39;m now a massive fan. I thought the 2nd season in particular was just delightful. The latest season was probably the weakest, but still a lot of fun. I hadn&amp;#39;t yet finished &lt;strong&gt;The Agency&lt;/strong&gt; when I scored it 8/10, but I was so enjoying the early episodes that it felt like an easy call to make. It stumbled a little towards the end of the season, but oh well. Honourable mention for &lt;strong&gt;Black Doves&lt;/strong&gt;, which must have just missed my top 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evil&lt;/strong&gt; had its series finale in 2024, and it&amp;#39;s really sad to say goodbye to that show. You know when you feel like something is made &lt;em&gt;just for you&lt;/em&gt;? Well for me, that was Evil. I&amp;#39;ve loved many TV Shows by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/06/20/the-couple-behind-tvs-boldest-shows&quot;&gt;the Kings&lt;/a&gt;, but this was my favourite. It had all the cleverness of The Good Wife, all the genre thrills of BrainDead, all the contemporary relevance of The Good Fight... plus, it was about angels and demons! I had an absolute hoot. It&amp;#39;s one of my favourite shows ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had a good time following the horrible exploits of sociopathic narcissists in &lt;strong&gt;RIPLEY&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;The Penguin&lt;/strong&gt;. Both walked that line of making the horrible protagonists likeable enough that it was never a pain to hang out with them. But hey, when you have Andrew Scott and Colin Farrell, that&amp;#39;s not too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then at the top of the list, the shows I enjoyed most in 2024, we have &lt;strong&gt;Shōgun&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;House of the Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; Season 2. Thoughtful, character-focused examinations of pre-war tensions. Both had the best performances I saw all year. And particular props to Shogun for such a thrilling use of language and translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some new seasons I absolutely loved, like &lt;strong&gt;The Rings of Power&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s second outing. I couldn&amp;#39;t get it to show up on my Trakt list above because, well, sometimes Trakt is weird. Speaking of which...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmoviestrakt2024.pAapz4yk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d already seen the first &lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Gladiator&lt;/strong&gt;, but I rewatched them in 2024 and rated them on Trakt, so they&amp;#39;ve appeared in this list. And there doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be a way to remove them. Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rewatches reminded me that the first Dune and the first Gladiator are both &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;. Actually, they have a lot in common. Desert-based action adventure epics about rising up against villainous emperors. Both incredibly entertaining and rewarding upon rewatch. Both featuring some of Hans Zimmer&amp;#39;s most iconic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They diverge in their sequels, however. &lt;strong&gt;Gladiator II&lt;/strong&gt; wasn&amp;#39;t bad, I thought. A decent ride, maybe a bit too much of a re-tread, but an entirely competent sequel. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;Dune: Part Two&lt;/strong&gt; was one of my favourite films of 2024, and the more I&amp;#39;ve thought about it, pretty much a masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Remarkable Life of Ibelin&lt;/strong&gt; was also high on my list. A tragic, uplifting documentary about horrible illness and unlikely community. The way it depicts found family in World of Warcraft really, really, really worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught &lt;strong&gt;Anatomy of a Fall&lt;/strong&gt; at the very start of the year, and it was one of my most thrilling cinematic experiences in recent memory. Astoundingly engaging courtroom drama. And like Shōgun, the way it uses different languages to convey interesting things about the characters is something I&amp;#39;m so fascinated by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew nothing about &lt;strong&gt;Wicked&lt;/strong&gt; before seeing this movie, and like so many others I got completely swept up in it and I can&amp;#39;t wait for part two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caddo Lake&lt;/strong&gt; came out of nowhere. It&amp;#39;s such a cool little drama with a twist. I don&amp;#39;t want to say anything about the concept, it&amp;#39;s wonderful to learn all about it in real-time. Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it has something to do with the mood I was in on the day, but &lt;strong&gt;Twisters&lt;/strong&gt; is the most fun I had at the cinema in 2024. There&amp;#39;s nothing too surprising about the movie, but the cast is so loveable and I was completely along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challengers&lt;/strong&gt; is a thrill ride and a half. I was so delighted by the propulsive, twisting and turning games of passion and ambition. Shakespearean and all that. I watched this at home and when the credits rolled I was jumping on the couch, punching the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;strong&gt;The Last Stop at Yuma County&lt;/strong&gt;. On the face of it, this could be a pretty generic Coen Brothers rip-off. But it&amp;#39;s so much better than that. It makes a completely absurd situation feel immediate and true and plays out one of the most shocking, terrifying, hilarious rides of the year. And it doesn&amp;#39;t just fall apart into a mindless shootout at the end! So good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have huge appreciation for the importance of reading and (like many people) I&amp;#39;m trying to increase my time spent reading each year. I didn&amp;#39;t quite make it to my 24 book goal in 2024, but I&amp;#39;m optimistic about my 25 book goal for 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasbooksstorygraph2024.BGKOyod2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll highlight three books I read in 2024. Not necessarily my favourites, but worth a mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kill Your Husbands by Jack Heath&lt;/strong&gt;
This is a proper page-turning mystery that I consumed within a few short days. It has so many twists and turns — every time I started to worry I&amp;#39;d figured out all of the mysteries, there was still more to come. And it leaned further into horror than I&amp;#39;d anticipated... gave me some shivers before bed! For pure entertainment, this may have been my favourite thing I read this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edgedancer by Brandon Sanderson&lt;/strong&gt;
I didn&amp;#39;t love this, but I was tickled by some of the ideas. It&amp;#39;s a breezy little novella in Sanderson&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Stormlight Archive&lt;/em&gt;, which I find myself somewhat begrudgingly committed to (once you&amp;#39;ve read four books in a series, how can you stop!). There are few things as painful as spending too much time with a character who&amp;#39;s supposed to be constantly witty (think Steven Moffat protagonists), but hey, sometimes Lift is genuinely witty and that makes it worth it (again, think Steven Moffat protagonists).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who: Scratchman by Tom Baker&lt;/strong&gt;
A messy Doctor Who adventure with a severe lack of stakes and character development. However, this is a brilliant ode to Tom Baker, particularly when listening to the audiobook read by the man himself. His winks and laughs and sighs through the story in that way that only Tom Baker can. And more than anything in the story himself, his reading of &amp;quot;a letter from Sarah Jane&amp;quot; at the end was extremely endearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to a LOT of music in 2024. I&amp;#39;m a soundtrack fiend and here&amp;#39;s a little Last.fm overview of the things I was into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/Screenshot%202025-01-27%20213529.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giacchino, McCreary and Williams being my top three composers makes a lot of sense. They&amp;#39;ve been up there for a long time and will probably stay there for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from my top albums and tracks, I got deep into some video game scores this year. Later this week I&amp;#39;ll be posting my annual &lt;em&gt;Favourite Soundtracks of the Year&lt;/em&gt; video, so I won&amp;#39;t discuss any of these here, but those Last.fm stats might give you a little teaser...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it&amp;#39;s been such a really great year across popular media. And considering the sheer quantity of huge movies and shows that are coming soon, things aren&amp;#39;t gonna be slowing down in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>games</category><category>music</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>That fresh new website feeling</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/fresh-new-website/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/fresh-new-website/</guid><description>I&apos;ve built a lot of personal websites in the past, but this one is my favourite! (obvs)</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenanewsite.DTrWJe8t.png&quot; alt=&quot;That fresh new website feeling&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Smells pretty good right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually yeah, don&amp;#39;t sniff too hard. Knowing how I&amp;#39;ve thrown it together, this website probably has errant links that take you directly to my bank account or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had many personal websites over the years. Making them is something that I&amp;#39;ve always been very interested in and only mildly good at. Putting them together feels like its slightly beyond my skills, slightly beyond what I&amp;#39;m capable of – which is the most fun space to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the earliest sites I remember putting together used &lt;em&gt;Freewebs&lt;/em&gt;. Which later changed its name to Webs, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/l2jzib/webscom_aka_freewebscom_deleting_tens_of_millions/&quot;&gt;shut down completely, apparently deleting everything&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early websites featured my projects under the moniker &amp;quot;Lcm Film&amp;quot;. Here&amp;#39;s one of the final forms of that Freewebs site (which went through a ridiculous number of regenerations... every few months I was like &amp;quot;Let&amp;#39;s remake the website!&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/lcmfilmsite.Dhq_COK3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much as changed, has it? Get rid of the dated Google+ link and the ear-searingly grey background, and this website could pretty much do the trick for me today. Actually, now that I think about it, I don&amp;#39;t know why I&amp;#39;ve spent so much time on the new site. Could&amp;#39;ve just re-published this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s even got a &amp;quot;Brand New Website!&amp;quot; blurb there, just like the one I&amp;#39;m writing right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you look closely, my favourite bit is the little &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s going on!?&amp;quot; image on the left, with a link to go back to the previous version of the website. How thoughtful of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My websites were actually much more fancy back then. I mean, each of those menu links lights up when you hover over them. I put functions like that together manually, designing lit-up versions of each image and programming the hover effect. And the Library has links to separate pages for each short film I was hosting at the time. Yes, actually hosting. Videos weren&amp;#39;t all just hosted on YouTube back then, like they are now (for better and worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My websites went through quite a few different stages after that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenaogsite.DM9dCCyv.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looked like when I was just starting to get into minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was using my own name, a picture of myself, and starting to base everything around my YouTube Channel. Exciting times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenarefinedsite.CM7FVuWe.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I had this site. Which again, in hindsight I&amp;#39;m pretty impressed by, and I wonder why I got rid of it. It&amp;#39;s pretty elegant for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t take all the credit for this one though. It was created with help from my mate &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewcollins.me/&quot;&gt;Drew Collins&lt;/a&gt;. Who was and I have to assume absolutely still is an absolute legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But according to the laws of balance, after this relatively minimalistic phase, I went a bit loopy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Thomas_websitebanner_v3.DDZs91Pp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a little while I had a website that looked like this. Holey moley. We all go through design phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then and in-between I&amp;#39;ve had various other sites, hosted with Blogger, Squarespace, Wordpress, Drupal, and I think at one point in my teens I lost my mind and went pure CSS. Or went pure CSS and lost my mind. It&amp;#39;s a chicken and egg situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;#39;s the website I&amp;#39;ve had for the last few years. A very basic Wordpress page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/thomasmidenawordpresssite.B7bwPskt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to go proper minimal with that one. No icons, only a few lines of text, one image. And I think it has served me well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#39;ve been wanting for something a little more robust. A little cleaner. A little better at communicating everything I&amp;#39;m up to. And with a blog built in, so that I can write &lt;em&gt;stuff like this&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was choosing a platform to build with. I don&amp;#39;t like Wordpress, it&amp;#39;s a clunky mess to me. I wanted to find something that was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open source,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modern and widely-used,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;affordable (or free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and highly customisable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t take long to discover that there are more great options out there than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could use something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpublii.com/&quot;&gt;Publii&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s got everything I want, and even has an easy to use GUI. But after trying it for a little while, I quickly realised that unless there was a template that I really liked, it was going to be frustrating to customise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at others: Ghost, Hugo, Zola, Eleventy. So many good options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately, it came down to the availability of templates. Even though I intend to customise a lot, I wanted a very solid base to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, in the end, this new website is built on Astro. Which ticks all the right boxes, in terms of being modern and open source. It also appears to be very popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, I really love &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devaradise/devolio&quot;&gt;this template by Muhammad Syakirurohman&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s clean and elegant, putting projects and blog posts at the forefront. And since it&amp;#39;s built on Astro, the potential for customisation is unending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also a great boon that platforms like Astro integrate beautifully with markdown files. I&amp;#39;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; a lot over the past year for extensive note-taking, and being able to write blog posts the same way is very intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tricky part is, of course, learning Astro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding is something I&amp;#39;ve always dabbled in but never really become proficient at. So it&amp;#39;s only with the help of language model chat bots like ChatGPT and (most helpfully of all) Claude that I&amp;#39;ve been able to stuck into designing this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as helpful as AI bots are for getting started on something you don&amp;#39;t understand, it sucks to rely on them too much for too long. After a while, you want to ditch the training wheels and fly on your own, ya know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s the journey I have ahead of me! And that&amp;#39;s what makes it fun! Sure, I could fork out however much money each month for Squarespace and have a great website in minutes (or so all the podcast ads tell me). But then I wouldn&amp;#39;t feel like I am &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; the master of the website. This way, as long as I don&amp;#39;t absolutely tank the code into a scorching mess, nothing is holding me back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the key themes of 2024 has been not getting locked in. Not getting locked into a bad habit, or a particular way of thinking, or a single digital app or service. I&amp;#39;ve done enough of that in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s it, that&amp;#39;s my new site, and this has been the first blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the internet becoming &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; fragmented all the time, it&amp;#39;s wonderful to have my own independent space to bring together everything that relates to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hey, if you do find a link to my bank account... eh, you&amp;#39;re welcome to whatever&amp;#39;s there.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>web design</category><category>open source</category></item><item><title>My favourite soundtracks of 2023</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2023/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/my-favourite-soundtracks-2023/</guid><description>My top original scores from TV, movies and games</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Brian-Tyler-conducting-an-orchestra.COTJUC-G.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My favourite soundtracks of 2023&quot; /&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Welcome! It&amp;#39;s high time we did this. Today, I’m sharing &lt;strong&gt;the definitive list of the 23 best soundtracks from 2023.&lt;/strong&gt; Objectively. Unequivocally. Indisputably. Agree or not, this is &lt;em&gt;the list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ranking covers a variety of soundtracks from films, TV shows, and video games—anything released as a musical album in 2023 counts, regardless of when the project itself came out. Those are the rules I’ve made up, and I’m sticking to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex justify-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ltGSqrqeN8Q?si=p93AjAhzE_qJLVh8&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video above, or read on below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflections on the Year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list was pretty challenging to put together—it’s already February, and here I sit, locking it all in. Does listening to more soundtracks each year make it easier? Nope. The more you hear, the harder it gets to narrow it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this year, my &lt;strong&gt;top dozen or so picks&lt;/strong&gt; were easy choices—they were shoe-ins for the list. But the &lt;strong&gt;bottom half&lt;/strong&gt;? That’s where things got tricky. I’ve been shuffling, adding, and trimming entries up until the very last week, constantly second-guessing. However, the time has come to finalize everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, let&amp;#39;s dive in—starting from #23 and counting all the way down to the #1 soundtrack of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grab some water, and let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23. &lt;em&gt;Wonderwell&lt;/em&gt; – Angelo Badalamenti &amp;amp; William Ross&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonderwell is a gentle and lush little film soundtrack that I find very easy to like. It&amp;#39;s got this really beautiful and delicate main theme by the late and great Angelo Badalamenti, and it&amp;#39;s used well throughout—you know I love when a score is bathed in its main theme. It captures a really effective sadness in just a few well-placed notes. The flutes and strings are very inviting. It&amp;#39;s played by the London Symphony Orchestra, so of course it sounds good. This one is the newest/latest addition to my list; I only just came across it recently, but it&amp;#39;s been growing on me rapidly, so I&amp;#39;m very glad to have squeezed it in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22. &lt;em&gt;Napoleon&lt;/em&gt; – Martin Phipps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Phipps brings his dynamic baroque kinda sound he&amp;#39;s always so good at to this Ridley Scott epic. And it&amp;#39;s placed somewhere between elegant drama and comic farce, which is quite a balance to maintain. But between godfather-ish mournful horns, elegant cultured strings, and opulent sophisticated choirs, the balance is something I find wonderful to listen to. I often find music by Martin Phipps to be really good to do other work to, like writing and things, when you need to focus. I mean that as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;21. &lt;em&gt;The Devil Conspiracy&lt;/em&gt; – Anne-Kathrin Dern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite a unique score by a composer I&amp;#39;m not familiar with for a film I know absolute nothing about. Weepy large dramatic choirs are joined by cool synths to create an enormous gothic flavour. I don&amp;#39;t know what this movie&amp;#39;s about, but the music&amp;#39;s certainly got a sci-fi futuristic flavour. Baroque choirs, pipe organ, electric guitar... it’s quite a mix. Sometimes it gets a bit noisy— for every beautiful classical choir piece there&amp;#39;s something disturbing and messy and sound designy. It certainly leans into horror at points. There are some great moments where the future synth and the gorgeous choirs come together, and it reminds me of &lt;em&gt;Warhammer Darktide&lt;/em&gt; from last year, and it’s pretty cool. I wish there was a little more recognisable melody, a little more shape, but I do enjoy what this is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20. &lt;em&gt;Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora&lt;/em&gt; – Pinar Toprak&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a large and expansive video game score by Pinar Toprak and a team of contributing composers, all continuing James Horner&amp;#39;s original &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; sound. So you can bet there are strong woodwinds and optimistic chanting choirs. And really there&amp;#39;s actually a lot of pleasant music here that creates a great atmosphere; a lot of it seems to be describing the lush natural world of Pandora. It does leave me wanting for some more memorable moments, like defined action setpieces or something. It just doesn&amp;#39;t do anything quite as striking as James Horner or Simon Franglen have done for the films. But that&amp;#39;s alright. This strikes me more as a gentle worldbuilding exercise, and in that it succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19. &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; – Joseph Shirley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year, Joseph Shirley took the reins from Ludwig Göransson on two big franchises—&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt;. And for what it&amp;#39;s worth, I think he&amp;#39;s done a much better than adequate job on both. In fact, they&amp;#39;re both really good. It must be so hard to take over from someone else who has famously given these stories such a unique musical style... and then what can you do? You can either respect that musical style and keep it going or change it up. Well, in both cases, Joseph Shirley has continued the established musical style, and it&amp;#39;s really genuinely good. I mean, I&amp;#39;m saying all this just to say, I don&amp;#39;t know why &lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t higher on my list. And why &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t on the list. It was just a very competitive year, and I suppose it doesn&amp;#39;t feel like either of these scores did anything very bold or new that we haven&amp;#39;t heard in the respective previous entries. They&amp;#39;re just super solid. I mean that&amp;#39;s not to say uninteresting or boring or anything—&lt;em&gt;Creed III&lt;/em&gt; continues in Ludwig Göransson&amp;#39;s template of really punchy, cool, rousing music, with unexpected uses of the human voice throughout. I&amp;#39;m super into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18. &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a bleak, anxious world of despair. &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; is a macabre atmospheric soundtrack that makes me feel like there are bugs crawling up my legs. It&amp;#39;s extremely evocative. The whole score is drenched in the reverb of a shadowy church—they found a great sound for this one. It really speaks to that medieval fantasy horror featuring the most evil of demons. It&amp;#39;s got this great sense of history too, like each piece is telling the story of ancient creatures and places. This music just makes me so restless and uncomfortable. So you may ask why I put it on here. Maybe I like being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17. &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt; – Benjamin Wallfisch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really solid superhero soundtrack and has some of my favourite music by Benjamin Wallfisch. It&amp;#39;s doing an awful lot of work in some setpieces in particular, bringing a lot of gravitas to a film that I&amp;#39;m otherwise quite reluctant to care about. There&amp;#39;s some really nice use of piano in some of the sweeping action tracks that has stuck with me. And there are some huge moments of grandeur. I mean, some of them, like the one you&amp;#39;ve just heard, I kinda think is honestly too grand and wonderful for the movie and the scene it scored. But I don&amp;#39;t mind, as a listener outside of the movie; it&amp;#39;s a great piece. It&amp;#39;s also got a bunch of Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s Batman theme, and that doesn&amp;#39;t hurt either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact - Fountain of Belleau&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music of &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt; is a relatively recent discovery for me. There&amp;#39;s a lot of music out there already, and this latest expansion release is full of wonderful music. It&amp;#39;s bright, colourful, and very playful. Playful is the big word I think. Throughout the album, the music dabbles with a whole range of styles and modes, but doesn&amp;#39;t forget to hold onto some lovely themes. There&amp;#39;s over 3 hours of music here, so I&amp;#39;m hoping to spend a lot more time in the future delving into this world, including the scores from the previous expansions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;15. &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3&lt;/em&gt; – John Murphy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back into the superhero realm with the third &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; . John Murphy is composing this time round, and the music has been taken in a very different direction to the previous soundtracks. This is a really emotional score, really. John Murphy leans into the tragedy and sadness at the heart of the film, and I love that about it. Although there&amp;#39;s a bit less action fun, it&amp;#39;s still quite space operatic, and there&amp;#39;s much more heartbreak and sentimentality. I didn&amp;#39;t expect to like it as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Survivor&lt;/em&gt; – Stephen Barton &amp;amp; Gordy Haab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; in dark mode. Everything&amp;#39;s rather bleak and grim and hard and overbearing. There&amp;#39;s more spooky, creepy, shadowy stuff in here than I expected. And a lot of the 4-hour runtime of the score is atmospheric, painting a range of scary, foreboding backdrops. But when the action kicks in, it&amp;#39;s thrilling. There&amp;#39;s just nothing like &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music. That descriptive brass and those rich agile strings. I swear with &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music you can always see these worlds so clearly— the empires and the blasters and the lightsabers. And like all of the best &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; music, &lt;em&gt;Jedi Survivor&lt;/em&gt; does push a bit outside the established template, with some unique orchestrations and styles we haven&amp;#39;t heard in this world before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13. &lt;em&gt;Godzilla Minus One&lt;/em&gt; – Naoki Sato&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big wow, this soundtrack. It kinda blew me away. In some areas, it&amp;#39;s deceptively simple, but then it really just hits you. Especially inside the movie—this is one of the best scores for picture on my list. It really imbues each scene of the film with... energy. Often anxious energy. It&amp;#39;s got absolutely thrilling moments, but the thing I was most struck by was how incredibly anxious this score is. It elevates my heart rate; it&amp;#39;s physically effective and affecting. I&amp;#39;m in awe. As well as scoring significant setpieces with memorable original music, Naoki Sato also brings back the original Godzilla Main Title theme, as Bear McCreary did a few years ago in his &lt;em&gt;Godzilla&lt;/em&gt; score, for some pretty incredible &amp;quot;wow godzilla is wild&amp;quot; moments. But yeah, this is really engrossing stuff. Play it loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12. &lt;em&gt;Fast X&lt;/em&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m honestly really not a fan of the &lt;em&gt;Fast and Furious&lt;/em&gt; movies at all, but Brian Tyler knows what he&amp;#39;s doing. This is really impressive action scoring. It aims to be pretty grand and epic, with some choral punctuations and what I assume is a villain theme that dominates throughout the score, going head to head with Tyler&amp;#39;s heroic themes, some of which are now several years old. But what&amp;#39;s so important about the success of this music is that it doesn&amp;#39;t forget to have fun. It could easily be too serious, and at a couple of points, maybe it is. But for the most part, it&amp;#39;s just a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. &lt;em&gt;Migration&lt;/em&gt; – John Powell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s John Powell doing a colourful animated score, of course, it&amp;#39;s good. I mean, it&amp;#39;s not &lt;em&gt;How To Train Your Dragon&lt;/em&gt; , but not much is. This one is also about flying creatures—they&amp;#39;re just ducks, right? I think that&amp;#39;s right. And what a perfect provocation the concept of flight is for music, no matter the composer, but especially for John Powell. Anyway, this is tremendously enjoyable light adventure scoring with several good action cues and a few of those flourishes of wonder, awe, and delight that Powell is just the master of. His music is just so dextrous and always sounds good—the particular quality and texture of his orchestra is definitely one of my favourites out there. It&amp;#39;s always very creative too; there are surprises in here, like a bit of electric guitar at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson and the Olympians&lt;/em&gt; – Bear McCreary &amp;amp; Sparks &amp;amp; Shadows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right at the end of the year, we got this new adventure score by Bear McCreary and his Sparks &amp;amp; Sounds team. And it&amp;#39;s really just what you&amp;#39;d expect, which is a great thing. A memorable and noble main theme on French horn. Rich strings to build out the world. All imbued with the sense of wonder and magic that you need for a &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; story. The only damning thing to say about this score is that it&amp;#39;s really not that exciting compared to &lt;em&gt;Rings of Power&lt;/em&gt; or other recent Bear McCreary scores. But that&amp;#39;s just because they&amp;#39;ve been so constantly terrific. Honestly, this really is great too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. &lt;em&gt;The Orville: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; – Various Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any sense of nostalgia for the great classical inspired sci-fi scores, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, etc., this is like a warm blanket. A 72-track, 4 and a half hour-long warm blanket, packed end-to-end with classical orchestral adventure film score writing. It&amp;#39;s almost too much to comprehend, really. But it does everything you&amp;#39;d expect: bold brassy &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; -y themes, expressive string ostinatos for &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; -like action cues, and all sorts of overt classical references to stuff like Holst&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Planets&lt;/em&gt; . And the cues are long—I love long setpiece cues, where the music really just gets to tell the story. Anyway, &lt;em&gt;The Orville&lt;/em&gt; has wonderful music. How lucky are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse&lt;/em&gt; – Daniel Pemberton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This score is absolutely genius. It&amp;#39;s so fast and clever and tight, and it absolutely has to be to keep up with the vivid torrent of ideas on screen throughout the movie. Daniel Pemberton&amp;#39;s themes for this world are so distinct and memorable. Just like the different frame rates and animation styles used for characters from different worlds, Pemberton uses such diverse musical styles to represent each theme and idea. It&amp;#39;s a miracle that it all comes together into something cohesive at the end. Top stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;em&gt;Forspoken&lt;/em&gt; – Gary Schyman &amp;amp; Bear McCreary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ultracool video game score by Gary Schyman and Bear McCreary really drew me in with some ear-catching melodies, often led by a dynamic female voice. It&amp;#39;s very much in that McCreary world of moody, appealingly shaped themes riddled throughout a heavy but not exhausting fantasy world. From track 1, it&amp;#39;s so instantly full of heartfelt, striving character. Great incorporation of some trap beats, some heavy drums, and agile piano amongst the swirling strings. I also love how cohesive and distinct its style is—you only need to hear the start of a track to go, ah, this must be &lt;em&gt;Forspoken&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny&lt;/em&gt; – John Williams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maestro is back! With &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt;! Expectations were high. I wasn&amp;#39;t disappointed. Of course, a lot of this album is retreads of &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; of the past. Or some action writing that is so similar to things we&amp;#39;ve heard before that it may as well be a needle drop. But there&amp;#39;s still so much new magic here. Helena&amp;#39;s Theme is the grand new concert piece, and the way it instantly dives straight back into that romantic classical writing, with large, shameless melodic leaps... Everything from John Williams is such a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; – Ludwig Göransson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;#39;s already been talked about so much in the soundtrack community; I don&amp;#39;t know that there&amp;#39;s much more to say. Not everyone loves it, that&amp;#39;s for sure, but I&amp;#39;m totally on board. I think &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; is an incredible followup to Ludwig Göransson&amp;#39;s first Christopher Nolan collaboration, &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt; . It creates such a gloomy tragic vibe with closely recorded expressive strings that sketch out these intricate patterns that feel like human thoughts. It succeeds at creating this atmosphere of an existential fairy tale, a bit like another one of my favourites of recent years, Justin Hurwitz&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;First Man&lt;/em&gt;. Beauty and dread, horror and wonder, all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;em&gt;Baldur&amp;#39;s Gate 3&lt;/em&gt; – Borislav Slavov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just jaw-droppingly beautiful. That is my primary reaction to most of &lt;em&gt;Baldur&amp;#39;s Gate 3&lt;/em&gt; by Borislav Slavov. This is the power of melodic music. Like a worm that crawls into your brain and lives there. This music immediately got deep under my skin. And yeah, it&amp;#39;s all about the melodies here. Just stunningly beautiful lyrical melodies. Sometimes performed unexpectedly simply, unexpectedly quietly, unexpectedly soulfully. These are some of the best themes of the year, and they&amp;#39;re done so much justice across the score. It&amp;#39;s got some of the best songs on a soundtrack in 2023 as well. &lt;em&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2&lt;/em&gt; from a few years back was great, but this is a new level. Borislav Slavov has received a lot of praise this year, and I think it&amp;#39;s all deserved and then some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;The Super Mario Bros. Movie&lt;/em&gt; – Brian Tyler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never expected to be so very charmed by this, but I absolutely was and am. Brian Tyler went all out on this one. Not only does it cleverly incorporate heaps of previous Mario musical material, it makes it new and fresh and consistent and tight. It&amp;#39;s filled with such visceral joy; it makes you feel like you could fly. Even the villain theme is fun! And again, the orchestra just sounds so good in this. It&amp;#39;s a classic case of Brian Tyler featuring drums in a big orchestra, and his sound is so perfected at this point; I can&amp;#39;t believe how punchy it sounds. I&amp;#39;m so happy to have something that&amp;#39;s this colourful and fun near the top of my list—it&amp;#39;s not all just doom and gloom this year. I haven&amp;#39;t seen the movie, but I&amp;#39;ve certainly spent many hours of the past year listening to this amazing score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible - Dead Reckoning Part One&lt;/em&gt; – Lorne Balfe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; has always had good music. I mean it started with the brilliant themes by Lalo Schifrin in the 1960s, and for the movies, Danny Elfman, Hans Zimmer, Michael Giacchino, Joe Kramer, and Lorne Balfe have all put in stellar work. But I think this latest soundtrack is my favourite of the bunch. Lorne Balfe returns to take the melodrama to the next level. And he so perfectly musically represents the feeling of racing against time, of trying to go faster, of being pushed to your limits, of being up against impossible odds. And it&amp;#39;s all done in this larger-than-life romantic style, where everything is turned up to 11 and every emotion is the biggest thing you&amp;#39;ve ever felt. It&amp;#39;s much more emotional than any previous &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/em&gt; score. It feels like this dark, exciting nightmare swirling all around you. I still don&amp;#39;t know how some of these tracks make me feel what they do. And the bongos! The coolest bongos of 2023! &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible: Dead Reckoning&lt;/em&gt; is an enormous and epic work by Lorne Balfe. And make sure you check out the expanded release, with about 3 hours of music. It&amp;#39;s glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a wrap on my &lt;strong&gt;fifth annual soundtrack list&lt;/strong&gt;! I’m so grateful to share this passion for scores and soundtracks with you every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Interesting Trends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 film scores&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2 TV scores&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;7 game scores&lt;/strong&gt; made this year’s list. TV scores dropped significantly from last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The diversity of composers is stronger—fewer repeating names, except Bear McCreary (3 times) and Brian Tyler (2 times).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading—see you next year!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>music</category><category>soundtracks</category></item><item><title>Performing in Black Comedy &amp; Love&apos;s Labour&apos;s Lost</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/performing-in-black-comedy-loves-labours-lost/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/performing-in-black-comedy-loves-labours-lost/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;In November and December 2018 I was ecstatic to be given the opportunity to act in two bright, lively and hilarious plays. Both were directed by Tony Rive and presented in Darwin&amp;#39;s Browns Mart Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First came Darwin Theatre Company&amp;#39;s Black Comedy, a tight and fast piece of British absurdity with some really fun physical gags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/45150055_912849388906359_7093587459455320064_o.BxjK5PC5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/46318028_315579192595919_4478786566214385664_n.DuoQ4vXS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s production of Love&amp;#39;s Labour&amp;#39;s Lost, a strange little Shakespeare, which was presented at Browns Mart alongside an excellent production of Animal Farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/48369142_2113532815371094_3019856140780437504_o.DdVXoRwS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_20181202_152330.DORv9V86.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also honoured to be given the opportunity to create the television advertisement for Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s shows, which you can view here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/300628614&quot;&gt;Animal Farm and Love&amp;#39;s Labour&amp;#39;s Lost TVC&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/corroiron&quot;&gt;Corrugated Iron Youth Arts&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreal amounts of fun making these shows with so many cool people.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>You Do You (Darwin International Film Festival Spark Film 2018)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/you-do-you-darwin-international-film-festival-spark-film-2018/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/you-do-you-darwin-international-film-festival-spark-film-2018/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;This year I was lucky enough to produce and co-direct one of the Darwin International Film Festival&amp;#39;s five &amp;quot;Spark&amp;quot; films. These are five ten minute scripts that are picked to be produced over a short three months and screened as a part of the festival in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180708_105408.BKJMdSG3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was a hoot having all these actual school kids play fake school kids in the film. The magic of cinema.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered several project ideas into the program this year, and the one that was picked to be produced was &amp;quot;You Do You&amp;quot;. This is a short film I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about, vaguely, since late last year. When I tried to write it earlier this year however, I found myself to be not very confident with the voice of the main character, a teenage girl. So I asked long-time collaborator Lexie Gregory to write it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180710_154235.BbamScb7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;#39;s Lexie herself, with DOP Nathaniel Kelly and star Koko Lawton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that was a great decision. Because what Lexie wrote was quite unlike my original plans, and quite unlike the films I&amp;#39;ve made before, but felt genuine and personal. The story is a little more honest than the stories I usually write myself. I was very excited to work on something that wasn&amp;#39;t my usual speed though. This experience was unique. The first time I&amp;#39;ve directed a film I didn&amp;#39;t write myself, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/IMG_5612.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Koko, me, and hey look it&amp;#39;s Max Conaghan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we shot the film in July. Worked with a bunch of lovely people. Shooting had its many challenges, as shooting always does. We had to be pretty disciplined about schedules because most of the crew currently resides interstate and were only in Darwin for a couple of weeks. There were some difficult times but overall it was actually one of the smoothest shoots I&amp;#39;ve been involved with. Co-directing with Lexie was lovely not least because it took some of that crazy pressure off my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180709_102608.s3NwoW2t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Koko, Joseph Baronio (beautiful producer), Nathaniel, Johanna Hayes (beautiful assistant producer) and Lexie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional shout-outs to Joseph Baronio and Johanna Hayes for being good producers. Oh man don&amp;#39;t you just love producers? Also Koko Lawton, who starred as the character Mickey. Koko &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; You Do You. If You Do You is anything it is because of Koko. The boppin&amp;#39; soundtrack is by my favourite music-wizards, Natalie Gall and Thomas Field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You Do You, and the four other DIFF Spark films, will be screening this Friday evening at the Deckchair Cinema. Nervous-excited to see what people think of what we&amp;#39;ve made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here&amp;#39;s the trailer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dirOQQVYbyE&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>writing</category></item><item><title>Darwin Fringe Show Vaudeville Knockout</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-knockout/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-knockout/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Yes, this was the sequel to the 2017 Fringe show I was a part of, &amp;quot;Vaudeville Variety&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was several months ago now, but better late than never! Vaudeville Knockout took the production to new heights for two evenings of wacky old-fashioned humour at Darwin&amp;#39;s Brown&amp;#39;s Mart Theatre. Many of the same cast and crew returned, but the characters were honed and polished a little further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_20180630_141828.JREND-fk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Russell (Charlie Chaplin) practising his boxing with new co-star Josh (Buster Keaton)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell and myself performed Who&amp;#39;s on first again, just like last year. And of course there were songs and there was comedy and a big silent comedy set piece in which I played the villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Screenshot_2018-07-13_at_22.23.20__25281_2529.BGvSNvXL.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m the one with the massive cape and hat and pirate cat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the lovely cast and crew, and of course everyone who came along to see the show. In many ways these ambitious little Fringe shows with a lightning-fast turnaround and little-to-no external support are more exciting than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>We&apos;re Family Now showing at Deckchair Cinema</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/were-family-now-showing-at-deckchair-cinema/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/were-family-now-showing-at-deckchair-cinema/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Nathaniel Kelly&amp;#39;s debut feature film, which I had several key roles on, will be screening thrice at Darwin&amp;#39;s wonderful outdoor Deckchair Cinema in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/maxresdefault.DRi_JtpU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re Family now is about a lovable little suburban family. It was shot entirely in Darwin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/family-now-presented-nathaniel-kelly/&quot;&gt;12 May&lt;/a&gt; (with Q&amp;amp;A), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/were-family-now/&quot;&gt;18 May&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deckchaircinema.com/films/were-family-now/&quot;&gt;26 May&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>films</category><category>world</category></item><item><title>Corrugated Iron&apos;s Whiplash</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/corrugated-irons-whiplash/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/corrugated-irons-whiplash/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;This week I attended a talk by Indonesian film director Garin Nugroho. One of the many things he talked about was a kind of theatre in which the actors rock up 30 minutes before the show and are given the story and characters there and then. There is extremely little preparation time, but the director briefly shares their plan, then the actors make the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Corrugated Iron skit show, &amp;quot;Whiplash Theatre&amp;quot;, has felt a little like that, as preparation time has been sparse. But like the theatre Garin Nugroho was talking about, it hasn&amp;#39;t been a bad thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/MVIMG_20180417_103327.CIbEnf3Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show is a collection of disconnected scenes and skits, most of which centre around a bit of a &amp;quot;road safety&amp;quot; theme. I really enjoyed working with these two excellent young performers (above), who brought to life a really wacky skit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/IMG_0559.WveQkCp2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a picture from a skit I appeared in myself, which included a video projection of me which keeps distracting the live actors who are trying to perform Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final show (of three) tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>creative</category><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>Books out for Courting 101</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/books-out-for-courting-101/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/books-out-for-courting-101/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago it was a delight to be a part of Corrugated Iron&amp;#39;s little production of the short comedy play, Courting 101, in Malak&amp;#39;s Chambers Crescent Theatre. I played a crazy professor teaching a class (the audience) how to go on a date and basically succeed in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/24831194_1659967474060966_9058484353739540601_o.D82BrtQe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done and thanks for a great time director Kate and dramaturge Phil and actors Isaac, Amy, Jack, Lily, Michael and Haylee.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category><category>comedy</category></item><item><title>A Very Bedroom Farce</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-very-bedroom-farce/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-very-bedroom-farce/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Last week I got to play an idiot called Trevor in Alan Ayckbourn&amp;#39;s very-rather-British 70&amp;#39;s comedy, &lt;em&gt;Bedroom Farce&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s a very understated play featuring particularly unique staging: three beds. The characters move between these three separate beds/bedrooms throughout the play, which takes place over one night, getting twisted up in all kinds of hilarious (but again, very understated!) hi-jinx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22550556_10155447919084017_2095557514036549656_o.BZH1uSy8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s Malcolm (Andrew) talking to Trevor (me). He comes to hate Trevor by the end. Everyone hates Trevor. Trevor hates Trevor. Poor Trevor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22688446_10214204836094570_6192755053270949281_n.DOvH8OGQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sniffing a prop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22780442_10155070967828366_4430284862911395921_n.RQAMZ5Ds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s Kate (Lizzy), Malcolm (still Andrew), Susannah (Haylee), Trevor (me again) and the wonderful behind-the-scenes duo who made it all happen: Tony Rive and Tania Lieman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/22637187_137964010161712_6800881611417059328_n.Bf0dBNYp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally the full cast. Candid. Thanks for a fun time!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>comedy</category><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>Danny Elfman scored my short films</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/danny-elfman-scored-my-short-films/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/danny-elfman-scored-my-short-films/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a lie, of course. Rather, I made short films for Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of them. It was for a competition held on indi.com earlier this year. The brief: simply make a short film with a piece from Danny Elfman&amp;#39;s wonderful ballet score, &lt;em&gt;Rabbit &amp;amp; Rogue&lt;/em&gt;, as the soundtrack. Elfman is obviously one of my favourite composers of all time, so this was an opportunity I couldn&amp;#39;t pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two films I made were quite a challenge to produce. They were both shot over about a week, in Darwin&amp;#39;s unpredictable wet season, with many first-time actors and an absolutely bone-thin skeleton crew. In order to make production achievable I decided not to record sound on set. So every single sound you hear in both of these films, every piece of dialogue, every footstep, was added in post. It&amp;#39;s quite funny to think that just about everything you hear was either composed by Danny Elfman or recorded in my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is a fast-paced fantasy-comedy-adventure about a boy who summons an imaginary friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x1B_eI1ghBs&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the second is a strange little story about someone who cannot see the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GL3cYI_dMqU&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>original</category><category>fiction</category></item><item><title>Bamboo Moon The Tale of Princess Kaguya</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/bamboo-moon-the-tale-of-princess-kaguya/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/bamboo-moon-the-tale-of-princess-kaguya/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I loved Studio Ghibli&amp;#39;s 2013 film, &lt;em&gt;The Tale of Princess Kaguya,&lt;/em&gt; based on the ancient Japanese folktale, &lt;em&gt;The Tale of the Bamboo Cutter&lt;/em&gt;. What a beautiful, honest and tragic—yet equally uplifting—fairytale about love and loss. And told with a particularly delicate minimalism which only Studio Ghibli can make sexy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/hero_TheTaleOfPrincessKaguya-2014-1.BYYfUtCX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I heard local Darwin youth theatre company &lt;em&gt;Corrugated Iron&lt;/em&gt; was putting on a new adaptation of the very same &lt;em&gt;Tale of the Bamboo Cutter&lt;/em&gt;, I obviously got myself up in that hotness. &lt;strong&gt;Bamboo Moon&lt;/strong&gt; was the title of the production, and it reshaped the classic story into a dynamic short live show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_1c44a42c49b94065a4f7f677e0732b3d-mv2_d_3000_2001_s_2.ZnpnZICF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was put on as a free show with a three night run at the start of August. It was also staged outdoors in the wonderful dry season air, at the George Brown Botanic Gardens, and with excellent set design, props and costumes; it was a visually spectacular show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19264461_1498468726877509_7303060439500758941_o.-FKKAoHK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s a snap from a rehearsal. I played Haru, the son of the Emperor, a very important and pretty cool guy, whose only real flaw is that he enjoys a wee bit of violence and war. Doh! There also is Taylor who played the eponymous Princess Kaguya and Tahlia who was my guard and lieutenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_737c7bfacdeb4e32ad38a1090241ade8-mv2_d_1334_2000_s_2.DgadTmF8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s me on the night. In character. Feeling things. Emotions. Drama. Acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_536be53651ed4c9eaa3c88314962c2ef-mv2_d_3000_2001_s_2.lxjYHEPS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s some of the other actors being funny on stage. Don&amp;#39;t worry, they were also in character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a dynamic outdoor youth performance, this show of course also included music, dance and circus! Look bamboo spirits on stilts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_3e76e6482be44198ad253bb2e2bfdb85-mv2_d_2000_1334_s_2.uCpfRaAC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And aerialist moon people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_43f13c91b1b6435880bc551193e045a3-mv2_d_2000_1333_s_2.D01v-lwL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are far more wonderful images of all these people than I can include here, but you can have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.corrugatediron.org.au/bamboo-moon-gallery&quot;&gt;the show&amp;#39;s photo gallery on the &lt;em&gt;Corrugated Iron&lt;/em&gt; website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I want to congratulate the dedicated crew, some of whom can be seen here...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/20622216_1547315035326211_3441157654226793550_n.uZDi-t16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the enormously friendly extended cast, some of whom can be seen here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/a8f101_40b010241f784e10a25a88edaf9c7526-mv2_d_2000_1333_s_2.rH9VPXyH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>Darwin Fringe Show Vaudeville Variety starring Chaplin</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-variety-starring-chaplin/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/darwin-fringe-show-vaudeville-variety-starring-chaplin/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Darwin Fringe Festival was a month ago. It was good. I got to perform in two shows. One of them was &amp;quot;VAUDEVILLE VARIETY STARRING CHAPLIN&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19424371_10203367029492756_8291523085095684753_n.CZYJti_w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was... well, it was what it sounds like. A madhat Vaudeville-inspired couple of hours of comedy, song, slapstick and skits. It was produced by an insane chap who I shall refer to simply as Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith, and directed by a terrific gentleman called Tony Rive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19905157_127441441192012_6067102042981737728_n.BQIIdt-t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith (shown above) was the centrepiece of the evening, singing and larking through a variety of comedy bits. One of these was a slapstick restaurant skit starring the titular, aforementioned and again shown above Charlie Chaplin, played by Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/19961263_127441531192003_1935005011975562630_n.C1Fxhwme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That photo displays a few other characters from the very same skit: (left to right) Haylee the gangster, Isaac the waiter, Damon the gangster, and me! I was the generically named &amp;quot;Male Lover&amp;quot;. In this case referring to the facts that I was A) a lover and B) of the male gender, as opposed to my defining character feature being that I &amp;quot;love males&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/VAUDEVILLE_VARIETY_SHOW_STARRING_CHAPLIN.mp4.00_45_43_09.Still010.CZpqNzEh.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;#39;s a snap from the night itself (thanks videographer Nathaniel Kelly!) in which Russell &amp;quot;Rusty Rhubarb&amp;quot; Smith and I can be seen performing the famous Abbott and Costello skit, &lt;em&gt;Who&amp;#39;s on first&lt;/em&gt;. Beast of a piece to learn, but it&amp;#39;s mega funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all of the wonderful cast and crew and brilliant musicians and everyone who came to see it. A great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>La La Land Worst thing ever or best thing ever?</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/la-la-land-worst-thing-ever-or-best-thing-ever/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/la-la-land-worst-thing-ever-or-best-thing-ever/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;La La Land is a fun musical and an optimistic fairytale about the entertainment industry. I would have thought it&amp;#39;d be an unlikely target for critical controversy, but here we are. People love to hate La La Land just as much as others love to love it. Most audiences and critics I&amp;#39;ve come across are firmly on one side or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/rs-248320-emma-stone-ryan-goseling-la-la-land-sing-dance-trailer1.BcTM8p02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like a lame division to me. Firstly, haters: you&amp;#39;re wrong. The film just wants to be pure joy. How can you hate pure joy? Or even an attempt at pure joy? Are you Hitler? Hitler probably didn&amp;#39;t hate joy, so who do you think you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, lovers: I love your love, but you know those hugs that are painful? Like, bear hugs, you know? Many of you are hugging La La Land to death! It&amp;#39;s a movie, an imperfect movie, possibly a great imperfect movie, but there&amp;#39;s no need to stab its critics in the face. I mean, are you Hitler? I don&amp;#39;t think Hitler stabbed people in the face, so who do you think you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, I get it. It&amp;#39;s emotional. It&amp;#39;s a movie about a glowing spirit in the face of adversity. A song and a dance in hard times. The other day I was in a lovely casual conversation when one guy said he walked out of La La Land. WALKED OUT. Hated it that much. Yes, that triggered me. My lips wanted to scream-forth: &amp;quot;BUT THAT OPENING NUMBER WAS IT NOT MAGICAL?&amp;quot; But I held strong. I extracted myself from the conversation, taking deep breaths, thinking about simpler times. Then I got a knife and ran back and stabbed the idiot in the face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiddin&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/lalalandcinema_-_Edited.CuI_cN0f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;#39;s going to win too many Oscars, but we simply ought not start a war over La La Land. La La Land wouldn&amp;#39;t want that. Respect La La Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people just don&amp;#39;t know how wonder-filled this movie (and soundtrack) is. Are they wrong? Yes. Are they Hitler? Probably not. They&amp;#39;re just not La La.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>anecdote</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>ramble</category><category>review</category></item><item><title>Michael Giacchino King of Composers?</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/michael-giacchino-king-of-composers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/michael-giacchino-king-of-composers/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;If, like me, you&amp;#39;re a fan of film, TV or video game soundtracks, then &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/&quot;&gt;The Soundcast&lt;/a&gt; is one of the podcasts you should be listening to. Not just because it&amp;#39;s a high quality show, or because &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2015/03/episode-80-cue-awards-2014.html&quot;&gt;I appear on it as a guest from time to time&lt;/a&gt;, or because it&amp;#39;s one of the not-many soundtrack-related podcasts out there, but because regular hosts Christopher Coleman and Erik Woods frequently do a great job of discussing the state of scores and soundtracks in a broad sense. Their show stands out because they don&amp;#39;t just debate whether &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is the worst thing ever or the best thing ever (one of the most over-discussed topics of recent months), but also attempt to dive into interesting, original and timely subjects such as &lt;em&gt;is modern Hollywood music &amp;quot;dumbed down&amp;quot;?&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;what actually makes a popular theme great?&lt;/em&gt; They&amp;#39;re interested by what it means to be a soundtrack fan, and how that meaning is ever-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their latest episode Chris and Erik discuss the concept of composer dominance. They cite John Williams and Hans Zimmer as dominant film composers of the past, and note that Michael Giacchino - through the abundance and prominence of his recent projects - is clearly next in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-ep-15-composer.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/soundcast_stereo_15.CKlSD-H4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesoundcast.blogspot.com.au/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-ep-15-composer.html&quot;&gt;Have a listen to the episode&lt;/a&gt; for their discussion, including their thoughts on whether composer dominance is a bad thing (spoiler: they decide it probably isn&amp;#39;t (sub-spoiler: I agree with them)). Here, I want to briefly jot down some thoughts I have about Michael Giacchino being the latest head honcho in the film music business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me five years ago: &lt;em&gt;hey Thomas, in five years who do you want to be the composer Hollywood uses for like everything?&lt;/em&gt;, I probably would have mentioned Giacchino. If you&amp;#39;d asked me who I wanted to score &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; (other than Williams of course), same answer. Sure, Giacchino has his fair share of critics, but on the whole he is a champion for many classic film music fans. I mean, his music is clearly Williams-esque (even when he isn&amp;#39;t charged with mimicking Williams - which, granted, happens fairly often), and who doesn&amp;#39;t love (former Composer King) John Williams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[... rest of the text continues in similar format ...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/giacchino.Cu9Xwnm6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (12/02/2017):&lt;/strong&gt; Wowzeedooza, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tracksounds.com/2017/02/soundcast-stereo-listener-reaction-3.html&quot;&gt;Soundcast Stereo did a response to my response&lt;/a&gt;. Response-ception.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>ramble</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>#HeWillNotDivideUs First Impressions</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/hewillnotdivideus-first-impressions/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/hewillnotdivideus-first-impressions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A single video camera hangs from a wall on 37th Street in New York, beaming live pictures around planet Earth, for anyone to see. It was activated last week and shall continue for the next four years. But what is the significance of this one shot; what is this little camera hoping to capture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He Will Not Divide Us&amp;quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hewillnotdivide.us/&quot;&gt;#hewillnotdivideus&lt;/a&gt;) is the latest experimental social art project published under the name of anti-celebrity Shia Saide LaBeouf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Shia LaBeouf. Once the uninteresting star of Michael Bay&amp;#39;s TRANSFORMERS trilogy, now one of the weirdest and most unpredictable contemporary celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/1.BYQDqLaP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaBeouf has been a strange fellow, neck deep in drama and run-ins with police for over a decade, but the turning point in the LaBeouf saga, in my view, was Rob Cantor&amp;#39;s music video from a few years back about the &amp;quot;Actual Cannibal Shia LaBeouf&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o0u4M6vppCI&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that point on, LaBeouf was no longer just a Hollywood performer, but also a man with a mythic aura. Shia surprise, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came his stunts, of which there are many. Most notable are probably &lt;a href=&quot;http://newhive.com/allmymovies&quot;&gt;#ALLMYMOVIES&lt;/a&gt; and I AM NOT FAMOUS ANYMORE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/2.3zSKtSu7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes Shia&amp;#39;s latest, and most ambitious, livestream project. A four year long livestream in protest of the presidency of Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. The guy does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like all of Shia&amp;#39;s livestreams, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hewillnotdivide.us/&quot;&gt;#HEWILLNOTDIVIDEUS&lt;/a&gt; is weird. Really weird. In some ways it&amp;#39;s difficult to see the point. And I can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if it will cause more harm than good. Will this project against division in fact carve a deeper divide?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[... rest of the text continues in a similar format ...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (12/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Welp, that didn&amp;#39;t last long. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2017/02/10/he-will-not-divide-us-livestream-shut-down/?sr_source=Facebook&quot;&gt;Shia LaBeouf&amp;#39;s anti-Trump livestream has been shut down for public safety&lt;/a&gt;. Unsurprising, and sounds very fair, but it&amp;#39;s hard not to be a little disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (21/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaaand it&amp;#39;s back. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2017/2/18/14659164/he-will-not-divide-us-exhibit-el-rey-theater-albuquerque-shia-labeouf&quot;&gt;Relocated to New Mexico&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty close to a road. Think I just saw some people nearly get run down by a car. What is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (25/02/17):&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaaaaaaaaaaaand &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pedestrian.tv/news/entertainment/shia-labeoufs-live-steam-shut-down-again-after-gun/da2b58cc-dd22-4795-bca5-8711e44bb5c6.htm&quot;&gt;it&amp;#39;s gone again, after gunshots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>world</category><category>ramble</category></item><item><title>A Prequel to Conductor of Earth</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-prequel-to-conductor-of-earth/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-prequel-to-conductor-of-earth/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had a fair bit of fun making the short film Conductor of Earth, and since it won&amp;#39;t be publicly viewable for a while yet I decided to follow in the footsteps of George Lucas and Peter Jackson, and do a prequel. And that prequel is called Miracle Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/SquareCover_MiracleMan2_smaller.BF7-ese-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miracle Man&lt;/em&gt; introduces &lt;em&gt;Conductor of Earth&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s titular character, Aidan, and explores some of the activities he got up to before the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s available both as an eBook and an Audio Drama (read by some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; cool people). &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/film/miracle-man&quot;&gt;Jump over to the project page to get it now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy! And huge thanks to everyone who helped make it!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>podcast</category><category>films</category><category>creative</category><category>original</category></item><item><title>New Website (Again)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-again/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Feels like only last year that I had a brand new website (it was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website you&amp;#39;re currently looking at (unless you&amp;#39;re pretty far into the future, in which case hi can mobile phones do 3d printing yet?) is the latest website I&amp;#39;ll be using to share with you whatever trouble I get up to so that you can feel like a co-conspirator (or alert the authorities). It was built with blood, sweat and &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewcollins.me/&quot;&gt;Drew Collins&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s nice and green and makes it very easy to see my latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasmidena.me/blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like last year though, I feel the need to tip my hat to my previous website. It had charm. Its existence was marvellous and, like all great things, brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/FireShot_Capture.CxnnopHp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is good unless it&amp;#39;s bad.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>website</category><category>technology</category></item><item><title>A Student Film Conclusion</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-conclusion/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-conclusion/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Six days remain before we have to submit a cut of this short film to the university. Sinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we&amp;#39;ve picture-locked, the sound edit is half done, the original score is nearly final (woot!) and the colour grade is coming along nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keen readers may have noticed the way I wooted at only one of the items in that list. Yeah, it&amp;#39;s all good stuff but the score is my favourite. Music is what inspires me to make films, so it&amp;#39;s extremely important to me for the final product to have something good. I&amp;#39;m very glad to have accidentally stumbled across the YouTube channel of one English gentlemen called Thomas Field earlier this year. From his videos I could quickly determine that I liked his style and his sensibilities. Luckily he agreed to compose for Conductor of Earth, and despite giving him very little time to actually pull it together, he has seemingly effortlessly produced a wonderful thematic score for the film. It&amp;#39;s a very particular and magical sensation the first time you hear music someone has created to accompany a story and characters you made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway that&amp;#39;s going well. And we&amp;#39;ve done lots of editing on the film, obviously. We&amp;#39;ve also had many watch it and they&amp;#39;ve given us lots of feedback. Much of the feedback is conflicting and therefore frustrating and difficult to process, but that&amp;#39;s to be expected. We live in such a subjective world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has brought us to crafting quite a streamlined, cut-down version of the film, which is all good and fine, but in typical director fashion I look forward to playing around with an expanded cut in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A new poster featuring the handsome lead and a bunch of names.&quot; height=&quot;356&quot; src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSMXJKOWg3eDFSRk0&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;A new poster featuring the handsome lead and a bunch of really great names&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Sorry to pull a twist on you but the title of this blog post was a lie. This isn&apos;t really the conclusion of this production journey. I mean, we&apos;re not even out of post-production yet, let alone getting the film out there and seen by people. And you! You should most certainly have a watch. I like you.

&lt;p&gt;Anyway ta ta for now.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category><category>original</category></item><item><title>Ditching Social Media for Good Ol&apos; Blogs</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/ditching-social-media-for-good-ol-blogs/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/ditching-social-media-for-good-ol-blogs/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t worry, this isn&amp;#39;t a Twitter-hating, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m leaving social media forever because I&amp;#39;m more enlightened than you&amp;quot; story. I&amp;#39;m not deleting any accounts or pleading for some kind of social change. I am however, in my own small way, attempting a small step away from the increasingly chaotic social networks of Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two primary reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Algorithms = Mayhem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is becoming increasingly non-linear, and I don&amp;#39;t like it. I&amp;#39;m not sure whether I&amp;#39;m in the minority on this. I enjoyed Facebook a lot back when the most recent content was always displayed at the top of the page. It was so easy to comprehend, easy to stay up to date, easy to check if you&amp;#39;d missed anything. Cut to today, and there&amp;#39;s no sense of control over one&amp;#39;s Facebook timeline. It&amp;#39;s a madhouse. Facebook presents content in whichever order its mysterious algorithms believe to be most pleasing to me. Not only does this ruin my pleasurable sense of continuity, but if Facebook one&amp;#39;s primary source of information, I see this system as socially damaging. Where is the learning in consuming only content that is pleasing to the reader? If I see only posts I like, by people that I agree with, am I not limiting my capacity for growth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, maybe it&amp;#39;s perfectly logical for Facebook to use these algorithms. It&amp;#39;s a website designed primarily for people to interact with their friends, and in that respect it&amp;#39;s helpful for the site to understand which friends I genuinely want to see in my timeline and which I don&amp;#39;t. Okay. But Twitter—that&amp;#39;s a different story. Twitter has always been set apart by its free and simple nature. 140 character tweets, always displaying the most recent at the top, follow whoever you like. It&amp;#39;s a design capable for great stories, interactions and discussions. But Twitter hasn&amp;#39;t been doing so well financially, and they think they ought to become more like Facebook. So they&amp;#39;re throwing away all of their fundamental rules. Soon Twitter will be non-linear and will have a greater focus on graphical content. Just like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also contributing to the chaos is the increasing volume of advertising on both Facebook and Twitter, but that&amp;#39;s a whole nother thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSbGItSEN5S1k4QkU&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a patchy analogy for you. These social networks want to be like sitcoms, with long 24 episode seasons and no continuous plot, so you can jump into any episode at any time. That&amp;#39;s fair thinking, the sitcom is a very successful genre. But personally I want my social media to be like serious, serialised TV. If I like content I want to see it all, in order, without missing anything. And this is why I&amp;#39;m preferring the blog format to people&amp;#39;s Facebook posts which forever pounce around my Facebook feed, impossible to pin-down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this would be perfectly palatable if not for my second grievance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. A Desire for Effort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty obvious, but Facebook and Twitter don&amp;#39;t demand much from their content-providers/users. At the top of both websites rests a variety of the insatiable question, &amp;quot;What are you thinking?&amp;quot;, which implies a valuable property in the answer, whatever it may be. Thus, the user is encouraged to contribute crap. Certainly, it doesn&amp;#39;t have to be crap, and there&amp;#39;s loads of brilliant content on both social networks, but the very nature of this permanent question, &amp;quot;What are you thinking?&amp;quot;, suggests that whatever you&amp;#39;ve got right now will do. Feed me, it says. Anything. Right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSVVQzLXdNZjVGVXc&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is between these heaving masses of thoughtless crap that we wade to find the brilliant content that Facebook and Twitter have to offer. I don&amp;#39;t know about you, but years of scrolling through such brain vomit has elicited within my a strong desire for good-old considered publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even a personal blog, as an individually-owned and permanent home of the posts within it, demands far more thought and meditation from its author than anything on the big social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trakt.tv is currently one of my current favourite social media networks, and this is partly because it works to foster effort from its users. On Trakt, a thoughtful user review of any length can not only receive likes from peers, but looks really good on the platform. In the chaotic clutter of Facebook and Twitter, people don&amp;#39;t care as much about making themselves and their content look smashing. Perhaps these social networks are simply not designed to be fonts of useful content anymore. But many people do use them as precisely that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSY2hXdWFBbzhsc2M&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this may never have been an issue for you, if you&amp;#39;ve always stayed true to official news media. But for people of my generation, social networks have replaced formal news formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#39;s all gonna be okay though, as long as we don&amp;#39;t forget about the humble blog. (He said, on his blog.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;em&gt;hip&lt;/em&gt; new working setup for online information consumption is &amp;quot;the Google Reader method&amp;quot;. Google Reader was a big RSS feed catching app back in the day, til Google ended it (RIP). Now there are a bunch of apps populating that void, the most popular being GReader, Inoreader and Feedly. After some research I have decided to use the latter of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=0B3n2EA9xVbsSUnhiZWJxYnBwNW8&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so this weekend I&amp;#39;ve slowly been punching in the RSS feeds of my friends&amp;#39; blogs, favourite news sites, authors I like and hey-why-the-hell-not the BBC. Feedly then produces my new go-to timeline, filled with a variety of thoughtful articles with real sweat and grease behind their creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always struggled with the concepts of Snapchat more than any other social app, primarily due to the temporary nature of its content. If something&amp;#39;s good, and really connects with me, I want to be able to hang on to it. So I like that with Feedly you can easily save and keep your favourite articles or blogposts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I&amp;#39;ll still be using Facebook and Twitter as communication tools and to see what people I know are up to lately, but I&amp;#39;m excited about this new setup. I&amp;#39;ll let you know how it&amp;#39;s going in a few weeks&amp;#39; time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like an old man.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>website</category><category>world</category><category>technology</category><category>idea</category></item><item><title>A Student Film Complication</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-complication/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-complication/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;It has now been several weeks since we finished shooting Conductor of Earth. It was a big 6 days made smooth and fun by our lovely cast &amp;amp; crew, who really stepped up to the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Just a few cast &amp;amp; crew posing in our elevator set&quot; id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3658&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/565e611ae4b0298e19c0c71b/t/57d64dc3893fc0cb7a1175ac/1473662697856/?format=750w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3673&quot;&gt;
Many people have asked me how the shoot went, and if I&apos;m happy with the footage. I have mostly replied with an empty non-answer (&quot;Yeah, good&quot;) because I don&apos;t currently feel equipped to judge it. I&apos;m not really going to feel confident in our footage until he have a working edit.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3676&quot;&gt;
But by the fact that extremely little went awry, the shoot was a good shoot. Only some props were damaged and we mostly didn&apos;t go too far overtime and we only had one really tough shoot (finishing around 4am in extreme cold with patchy rain is not fun for anyone).&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3679&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/565e611ae4b0298e19c0c71b/t/57d64e3d1b631b0de893a3a5/1473662607971/?format=750w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3681&quot;&gt;
I felt incredibly lucky to direct such a dedicated and independent crew. As much as it&apos;s great when the crew ask me questions about things, the fact that each department was cool and confident enough to make decisions and keep working on their own propelled the whole production forward. The lighting team and production designer were so important and efficient throughout the shoot that I was allowed to consider the action and characters. From the inspiring actors to the diligent script supervisor to the ARRI ALEXA camera, it was a treat to be a part of such a professional film production.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3711&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/565e611ae4b0298e19c0c71b/t/57d64e9b579fb3b9b0808591/1473662689659/?format=750w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3713&quot;&gt;
It was certainly surreal to see scenes come alive which I&apos;ve imagined so much for nearly a year. I&apos;m delighted that so much of it looks just like I imagined it, and some even better.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_3_1480309160769_3706&quot;&gt;
At this stage I&apos;m pretty excited about having a working edit by the end of the month. Then we can start putting in magical dressings like music. It&apos;s usually when I add music that I start to admire my films. I&apos;ll write about that in a few weeks.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>anecdote</category><category>ramble</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>So Very Much Wonderful Ado About Nothing</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/so-very-much-wonderful-ado-about-nothing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/so-very-much-wonderful-ado-about-nothing/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the final performance of Third Door Theatre&amp;#39;s production of Shakespeare&amp;#39;s Much Ado About Nothing, in which I had the juxtaposed joy of playing the melancholy villain, Don John. It&amp;#39;s always strange when a production like this comes to an end; suddenly there&amp;#39;s no great practical reason to see all the cast and crew you&amp;#39;ve spent a huge chunk of your life with for months. This one&amp;#39;s a particularly bittersweet goodbye however, because it really was a cluster bomb of awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/cwy_4323_29284544886_o.FFDNt1Fr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always been a huge fan of Shakespeare, so it&amp;#39;s been enormously fulfilling to be a part of this big, thoughtful, fully-fledged and &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; fun production of one of the bard&amp;#39;s best works. And to be the villain was never something I anticipated, as I&amp;#39;ve certainly leaned towards comedic roles in the past. The role of Don John ended up being a wonderful challenge with intriguing themes. It was often kinda cathartic to delve into that dark melancholy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/cwy_4432_29318285905_o.CJ1BUNpk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I was surrounded by the most exceptional cast. I&amp;#39;ve seen a fair few productions of Much Ado in film and theatre, and it&amp;#39;s such a joy to be able to honestly say I think the characters were all portrayed better in this show than anywhere else I&amp;#39;ve seen them. From Benedick and Beatrice to Hero and Claudio to Leonato and Don Pedro to Margaret and Ursula to Dogberry and Verges and the rest - these characters were so funny and real that I feel like they truly existed. After months of rehearsals and ten shows I wasn&amp;#39;t tired of watching any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/cwy_4191_29318204245_o.BGrp9Hib.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, hard to believe that it&amp;#39;s possible, but these actors were just cool off-stage as on-stage. The overflow of camaraderie can be attributed to director Cale MacLaren, who undertook nurturing this big theatre family with the utmost sincerity and encouragement. Cale&amp;#39;s talents as an actor, director, wordsmith and builder of bonds made this production special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deliciously sentimental thing about the nature of theatre is that this production is now little more than memories. But these ones are gonna last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/cwy_4088_29318173695_o.WT2qffUy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>comedy</category><category>creative</category><category>theatre</category></item><item><title>A Student Film Introduction</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-introduction/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/a-student-film-introduction/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;#39;ll be shooting the centrepiece of my final year at film school: a fantasy short film called Conductor of Earth. I first began working on this project almost a year ago, so the many stages of pre-production have been long and extensive, particularly for a&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;film. And as I will examine to some degree in this post and to a greater extent in future posts, therein lies the primary challenge—maintaining interest and enthusiasm in a single, short narrative for an entire year. As someone with little patience for perfection (a concept I think to be undesirable anyway), and who idealises the rapid production pace of television, this process has at times been—to employ a healthy dose of hyperbole—torturous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conductorofearth.com/&quot; id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_8_1480300752438_539&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_8_1480300752438_2386&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/565e611ae4b0298e19c0c71b/t/57b3ab30893fc0bed59a6dd6/1471392618910/?format=750w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As alluded, I&amp;#39;ll be delving into these thoughts more in future posts, as in addition to not having processed them,&amp;nbsp;I don&amp;#39;t want to risk my wavering uncertainties in any way hampering or undermining the commitment and excitement of my cast &amp;amp; crew, who are doing brilliant work to heave this film through production. I also don&amp;#39;t mean to imply that I&amp;#39;m negative about this production at all. There are simply elements of it I will avoid in future. Like, last week I put zucchini in a beef stew, and I just don&amp;#39;t think it tasted very good in the ecosystem of the meal, so in future I&amp;#39;ll avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so far I&amp;#39;ve written more about what I&amp;#39;m not going to write about than what I will. Here&amp;#39;s some real stuff. A very brief history of Conductor of Earth till now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_8_1480300752438_2423&quot;&gt;1. Many Drafts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been dozens of drafts of the script over the past year. Obviously this is the norm, and to be expected. Kill your darlings and all that. It&amp;#39;s not supposed to be easy. But a painful truth is that I do still miss my very early drafts. This script has changed a lot, you see. The first draft and our locked shooting script &amp;nbsp;of today really are totally different stories, with totally different themes. The only common denominator is an angel character named Aidan. As much as I am pleased with the shooting script, which is shorter and tighter and simpler and more straightforward, I look forward to one day recycling the ideas of the first draft, which were raw and sprawling and still excite me the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Many Pitches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to pitch the film a lot this year, both casually and formally, alone and with a group. I don&amp;#39;t want to go into this, as it was just never-ending and I don&amp;#39;t like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Teaser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key assessed deliverable of this process was a short teaser trailer for the film, which had to be produced months ago, before we shoot the film actual. This was a nice exercise in trying to capture a bit of the tone of the film, and it&amp;#39;s therefore somewhat grating when people say they are confused by the projected world or narrative of the teaser. If I could fit the narrative in a teaser video I wouldn&amp;#39;t be making a 12 minute film. I don&amp;#39;t mean to sound like a stereotypical grouchy &amp;quot;angry-at-the-audience&amp;quot; storyteller, but sometimes I wish for viewers to relax more. Don&amp;#39;t worry if you don&amp;#39;t understand everything, just drink in what you can.&amp;nbsp;Anyhow, here is that very teaser for you to misunderstand as it please you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; id=&quot;yui_3_17_2_8_1480300752438_512&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-KPw_d44qdk?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&quot; width=&quot;854&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, despite the grouch, I generally don&amp;#39;t mind negative feedback. It&amp;#39;s the only kind of feedback that&amp;#39;s easier to process than positive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Crowdfunding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve known for years that one day I&amp;#39;d find myself on the &amp;quot;wrong end&amp;quot; (the needing-money end) of crowdfunding. In many cases it is now an unavoidable facet of small-time arts ventures. So we put a lot of thought into the Conductor of Earth crowdfunding campaign, and tried to have a lot of fun with it. And in the end we did reach our goal, so it was all a success, but this definitely reminds me of the zucchini in my beef stew. It&amp;#39;s a bit slimy and mushy and not to my liking. I genuinely hope not to crowdfund ever again. (We&amp;#39;ll see how that goes.)&amp;nbsp;I hate money, particularly spending it, and particularly spending it on filmmaking which I see as (at best and by design) a terribly risky venture. Anyhow, you can&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pozible.com/project/conductor-of-earth&quot;&gt;give the Conductor of Earth Pozible campaign a squiz here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abruptly and with some disatisfaction, so ends my first ramble about my 2016 student filmmaking experience. More to come after we shoot, when there&amp;#39;s an actual film for me to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>anecdote</category><category>ramble</category><category>creative</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Warcraft Soundtracks</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-warcraft-soundtracks/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-warcraft-soundtracks/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obligatory disclaimer that listicles like this are intrinsically subjective and fallible and don&amp;#39;t mean much.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warcraft is a grand series of video games about to make its way to the big screen. In anticipation of this film (and Ramin Djawadi&amp;#39;s score!) I&amp;#39;ve decided to look back at the many Warcraft soundtracks over the years. And hey, why not try to rank them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Warcraft series differs from other extended fantasy franchises like The Lord of the Rings/The Hobbit because it&amp;#39;s simply much bigger. Whereas the Tolkien films were all scored by Howard Shore, Warcraft has seen contributions from dozens of composers over the years. And with many games over the years with many different styles and huge amounts of content, the sheer amount of musical material in Warcraft is just enormous. For most of the World of Warcraft releases there is around 10 hours (!) of music available to listen to on YouTube (for this article I&amp;#39;m really only looking at the official releases though). And it&amp;#39;s all incredibly varied, as Warcraft has touched on genres of fantasy, war, science fiction, melodrama, romance, horror and even comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much brilliant music to get through! Here&amp;#39;s my ranking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10) Warcraft: Orcs &amp;amp; Humans (1994) by Gregory Alper, Rick Jackson, Chris Palmer, Glenn Stafford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original WarCraft may not have many lasting themes, but it&amp;#39;s a high energy soundtrack that forges a path for what&amp;#39;s to come. The fast marching drums and taut, dancing brass define the WarCraft style to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZxXsbbs0teI&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9) Taverns of Azeroth (2007) by David Arkenstone, Jason Hayes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A change of pace: gentle, hearty and warm shanties from the Warcraft world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J7c-2q_GcZk?list=PL5D9FD5315F388983&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8) WarCraft II (1995) by Glenn Stafford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Orcs &amp;amp; Humans, but brings Tauren-sized bucket loads of fun. Electronic, but oozing with rhythmic marches and fist-pumping motifs. Lots of attitude and personality. Highly memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGl4slGxY8U&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7) WarCraft III (2002) by Tracy W. Bush, Derek Duke, Jason Hayes, Glenn Stafford, Victor Crews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diverse; often ethereal, intermittently creepy, sometimes grand. Enormous and rich, it builds upon some WarCraft II themes, and is the origin for some of the greatest in the series. While it may not be wall-to-wall fun like WarCraft II, Warcraft III is when the series began to become beautiful and sentimental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xPoSAo7YFsw&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6) World of Warcraft: The Burning Crusade (2007) by Russell Brower, Derek Duke, Matt Uelmen, Jason Hayes, David Arkenstone, Brian David Farr, Neal Acree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding some terrifying sting to the vanilla World of Warcraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MVmk7VthBQo&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5) World of Warcraft: Cataclysm (2010) by Russell Brower, Derek Duke, Glenn Stafford, Neal Acree, David Arkenstone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the best themes from the series are vividly re-imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k4Pberbn2po&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4) World of Warcraft: Wrath of the Lich King (2008) by Russell Brower, Derek Duke, Glenn Stafford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cold, operatic despair harks the terror of the Lich King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Nwj29zCxzI&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3) World of Warcraft: Mists of Pandaria (2012) by Russell Brower, Neal Acree, Sam Cardon, Edo Guidotti, Jeremy Soule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warcraft meets Eastern styles. It works ridiculously well. And Jeremy Soule&amp;#39;s flourishes are fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WZDmbz6ZXHI&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2) World of Warcraft: Warlords of Draenor (2014) by Russell Brower, Neal Acree, Clint Bajakian, Sam Cardon, Craig Stuart Garfinkle, Edo Guidotti, Eímear Noone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most powerful melodies I&amp;#39;ve ever heard, and some of the most heartbreaking. Like Pandaria and Lich King, Draenor&amp;#39;s score feels truly unified in a theme - here the Orcs&amp;#39; quest for a home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vy_v1fsYLkk&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1) World of Warcraft (2004) by Jason Hayes, Tracy W. Bush, Derek Duke and Glenn Stafford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World of Warcraft takes the fun of Warcraft II and the beauty of Warcraft III and blends them into something unforgettably glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gQFOLOur1jM&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Mentions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hearthstone: Heroes of Warcraft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet, gentle, toe-tapping music is featured in this Warcraft spinoff game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Echoes of War&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the best recordings of Warcraft pieces ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Heroes of the Storm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warcraft has a place in this mishmash of Blizzard IPs, and it&amp;#39;s pretty rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>review</category><category>games</category></item><item><title>On Battlestar Galactica</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/on-battlestar-galactica/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/on-battlestar-galactica/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;The other day I watched the final episode of Battlestar Galactica. A year ago I had never watched any Battlestar Galactica. These are some thoughts I have on Battlestar Galactica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s an amazing show. I can&amp;#39;t help but compare it to modern Doctor Who, which is also a reboot of a science-fiction show from decades ago. BSG and Doctor Who&amp;#39;s 21st Century rebirths both began around the same time (2003 &amp;amp; 2005 respectively). I wonder what I&amp;#39;d be like now if I had grown up on BSG instead of Doctor Who. I imagine I might be more grounded, with less starry-eyed optimism but greater appreciation for the fallibility of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Doctor Who, BSG is a show with huge variances in quality. But in both programmes the &amp;quot;ups&amp;quot; heavily outweigh any &amp;quot;downs&amp;quot;. At its best, BSG is a sprawling sci-fi epic, with lively characters scrambling through the moral murkiness of a world with highly-developed advanced artificial intelligence. We get so many stories of the beginnings of AI, but BSG is really about what AI could be like after existing for hundreds of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the whole show, but particularly towards the beginning, I found it difficult to know if the show wanted me to relate to the Cylons or not. They&amp;#39;re certainly initially portrayed as evil robots of destruction, but then there are many times when the viewer is supposed to root for them. Which is something I would be happy to do, but then the show would change its mind again and say they&amp;#39;re evil robots. I appreciate that they were probably aiming for some kind of &amp;quot;objective&amp;quot; portrayal, with lots of grey area, but the show really wants the viewer to feel something towards the Cylons and I was never sure what that something was. Again, maybe this was the point, but it felt clunky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of clunky - I&amp;#39;d say the whole plot is a pretty big mess. I can&amp;#39;t get my head around the Cylons&amp;#39; plans at all. Totally random things happen all the time under the guise of &amp;quot;destiny&amp;quot;. But again, this is just like Doctor Who. The plot is allowed to be a disaster because this show is all about the characters. I was pretty disinterested in the plot of most of Seasons 3 &amp;amp; 4, but it&amp;#39;s all time spent building these characters, so it was worth it. And chief among the characters in my books is none other than Mr. Gaius Baltar. A wildly interesting person, stunningly portrayed from the pilot to the finale. Gaius was often used as comic relief and, like in many stories, that allowed him to evolve into the most three-dimensional, intriguing and heartbreaking character of the lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/bsgiknowfarming.B3UpbBXJ.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I know about farming.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought the musical score by prolific TV maestro Bear McCreary was great in the show, but I think it&amp;#39;s actually even better on album. His music is so unique and rich and bold. It certainly holds up against Murray Gold&amp;#39;s Doctor Who, if I&amp;#39;m going to keep this comparison going. Here&amp;#39;s one of the most extravagant pieces in BSG, which made me suddenly sit bolt upright when it first started playing in the show. Like, I kinda didn&amp;#39;t even know strings could do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SlcUwUwjLrs&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good test of how invested I am in a show is often how I react to the finale. In BSG&amp;#39;s case I was pretty affected. It was devastating to see these characters come to terms with everything and say goodbye to one another. The finale was also loaded with a surprising amount of pointed religious and anti-technological messages, which I know have bothered some people, but I prefer a show has too much to say than not enough. And that rather sums up Battlestar Galactica for me. It&amp;#39;s a show that was too ambitious to be perfect. But where&amp;#39;s the fun in watching something that&amp;#39;s perfect?&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>ramble</category><category>review</category><category>television</category></item><item><title>New Website A Revenge Story</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-a-revenge-story/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/new-website-a-revenge-story/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Over the past few days I have been tearing down webpages, transferring domains, trawling through templates, scribbling CSS (very carefully – I ain&amp;#39;t no master coder) and basically just destroying my website so that it can be reborn. The primary goal being, to use a bunch of webdesign jargon: a more dynamic, customisable and content-rich experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is now that I say good night and good luck to my old Blogger page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/Capture.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And good morning and good luck to this new website you&amp;#39;re looking at right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new site is still pretty bare, possibly a bit too white, and lacking some pizzazz, but over time it should come to feel more &amp;quot;lived in&amp;quot;. Already I&amp;#39;m feeling pretty good about it. It&amp;#39;s clean and simple and allows me to present of a lot of my work.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>website</category></item><item><title>The Primary Instinct (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/the-primary-instinct-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/the-primary-instinct-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;As a long-time fan of prolific podcaster &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davechen.net/&quot;&gt;David Chen&lt;/a&gt;, I was rather excited to watch his debut film carefully titled &lt;strong&gt;The Primary Instinct&lt;/strong&gt;. The movie is essentially a filmic adaptation of Chen&amp;#39;s successful &lt;em&gt;The Tobolowsky Files&lt;/em&gt; podcast, in which actor Stephen Tobolowsky shares stories from his life with lightning sharp insights into the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Primary Instinct&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t take this premise much further, and is essentially a concert film. Stephen Tobolowsky tells poignant stories as he would on the podcast, but the difference here is that we get to see him do it. The question, therefore, is does this simple visual addition to the format warrant the huge jump from podcast to film? That&amp;#39;s question I will answer in the next paragraph because this one&amp;#39;s reached a decent length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i2.wp.com/bitcast-a-sm.bitgravity.com/slashfilm/wp/wp-content/images/Screen-Shot-2015-04-19-at-4.25.33-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. I do think that &lt;em&gt;The Primary Instinct&lt;/em&gt; is a success. Stephen Tobolowsky is an actor through and through, so he can&amp;#39;t help but be an interesting visual presence. In this film we get to see him prance about the stage as he imitates characters, and crumple to his knees breathlessly with the hilarious crux of a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most powerful visual is found when Stephen is in the middle of recalling events from long ago, and he grows still, and through close-ups we can see Stephen&amp;#39;s eyes visualising what he describes. The content Stephen shares in both this film and his podcast is incredibly personal. But what makes his works transcend simple storytelling is that at the centre of these tales he always discovers great truths that we can all relate to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t believe how much Stephen has managed to do this over the past few years - he harvests his own life for so many incredible stories. I used to think, &amp;quot;surely he&amp;#39;ll run out soon? There&amp;#39;ll be nothing left to tell?&amp;quot; But now I think that will never happen. A life is filled with enough stories for a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny, charming, heartbreaking... &lt;em&gt;The Primary Instinct&lt;/em&gt; is a simple story-telling concert film in construction, but is filled to the brim with fascinating pontifications. I&amp;#39;d recommend &lt;em&gt;The Tobolowsky Files&lt;/em&gt; podcast and &lt;em&gt;The Primary Instinct&lt;/em&gt; film to anyone without thinking. I can&amp;#39;t wait to see what Chen and Tobolowsky produce next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/david-chen-stephen-tobolowsky-the-primary-instinct-slice.Dg37NEYL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Top 5 Retired MMO Launchers/Patchers</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-5-retired-mmo-launcherspatchers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-5-retired-mmo-launcherspatchers/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please be advised that most of this listicle is based on memory and opinion rather than research and fact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some used sounds, some had moving graphics. Some displayed the latest patch notes, some allowed you to login, or pre-download a future patch. But whatever they were like, all kept your game updated. If you&amp;#39;ve played any MMO, you&amp;#39;ve spent a long time looking at them. Therefore its easy to feel pretty nostalgic about some of these launcher windows. And there are a bunch that have been changed over the years, or are connected to a game that&amp;#39;s been discontinued. And with Star Wars: The Old Republic recently completely redesigning its launcher, I was prompted to make this little list of a few launchers I remember the most fondly over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. World of WarCraft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/WoW_Launcher_New.Vu_BTX1T.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First on my list comes the original launcher for the biggest MMO around. It had a cool themed aesthetic, updated with each expansion to the game. As you can see I&amp;#39;ve included a picture of the Wrath of the Lich King launcher. It also came equipped with patch pre-loading. It was a cool, basic launcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Star Wars: Galaxies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/image1.E0wSeYhu.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SWG&amp;#39;s launcher was the most feature &amp;amp; information rich of any MMO I&amp;#39;ve seen. Unfortunately I can&amp;#39;t actually find an image of the real launcher, so this screenshot of the SWG EMU launcher will have to suffice. (If you do have a shot of the original SWG launcher, please let me know!) To my fallable memory I believe SWG&amp;#39;s launcher displayed server status, server selection, patch notes, and even allowed you to adjust in-game settings before you hit Play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Star Wars: The Old Republic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/swtor_beta_download.Cs852IQH.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recently abandoned launcher on my list, Star Wars: The Old Republic used to patch with this smooth, slick and cool window. Featuring the game&amp;#39;s signature orange and blue colours, it displayed patch notes, along with some basic game alerts and updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/wardownload.Cc2xjOGl.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably coloured by how excited I was for this game before it launched, WAR&amp;#39;s launcher is to me a thing of beauty. It used two golden progress bars and featured the latest patch notes in full. I believe it eventually allowed you to launch the game while you were still downloading files. And those two war hammers sticking out the top are just great design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Pirates of the Caribbean Online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/OldLauncher2.DmSwBPtd.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disney&amp;#39;s Pirates of the Caribbean Online was a small MMO with a very fun launcher. It displayed updates and patch notes, allowed you to login and could stream game files after you hit Play. One iteration of the launcher also displayed a moody looped video with a pirate ship sitting under a lightning storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, did you know Pirates of the Caribbean Online had a 3d version? Crazyness. It was awful but so wacky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/POTCO3D.B-mcne_q.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;#39;s my top five. I&amp;#39;ve tried a ridiculous number of MMOs, but unfortunately not all of them. So if you have a favourite that I haven&amp;#39;t included, I&amp;#39;d love to hear from you in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>list</category><category>games</category></item><item><title>Bridge of Spies (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/bridge-of-spies-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/bridge-of-spies-review/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Steven Spielberg is a dependably good film director. Obviously. The worst thing I can say about his filmography is that a large portion of it feels light on ambitious creativity. I would say that his films tell stories in a less stylistic, less subjective fashion than most modern storytellers (though of course, a film can never truly be objective). Perhaps I only feel this because Spielberg&amp;#39;s style has become the definite Hollywood archetype in my mind; the most movie-like of all American movies. The vanilla formula of film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that Spielberg&amp;#39;s films, and &lt;b&gt;Bridge of Spies&lt;/b&gt;, lack style. On the contrary, Spielberg&amp;#39;s latest feature is gorgeous. The cinematography (by Janusz Kaminski) ranges from great to excellent. The way some scenes use light and position the characters in frame really brings the drama alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianitytoday.com/images/64237.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.christianitytoday.com/images/64237.jpg&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
And there&amp;#39;s plenty of drama to bring alive. &lt;b&gt;Bridge of Spies&lt;/b&gt; tells a sprawling cold war story, but most importantly keeps it personal, grounded and unpredictable. The main characters really get a chance to live and change over the course of the film. It&amp;#39;s even surprisingly funny, for a film such as it is. Though they&amp;#39;re given writing credits on the film, it&amp;#39;s difficult to say specifically what areas of the screenplay can be attributed to the Coen brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Hanks is easy to get behind as the morally steadfast lead, but Mark Rylance is the standout cast member. His Russian spy is a delicately portrayed and memorable character upon whose shoulders the film&amp;#39;s plot safely rests. Oh and Jesse Plemons is there of course, because he&amp;#39;s in like every movie now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/o-BRIDGE-OF-SPIES-facebook.F8v3u6KX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;#39;t heard anyone rave about this film before seeing it, so I went in tentatively. But I had no need to worry. &lt;b&gt;Bridge of Spies&lt;/b&gt; is a very well put together cold war thriller. It&amp;#39;s a Spielberg film through and through, and therefore won&amp;#39;t be blowing any minds, but it will tell you a powerful story in a beautiful way, and that&amp;#39;s good cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>The Martian (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/the-martian-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/the-martian-review/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I really hate having such a predictable, worn-out opinion, but I think &lt;b&gt;The Martian&lt;/b&gt; novel by Andy Weir is far superior to &lt;b&gt;The Martian&lt;/b&gt; film directed by Ridley Scott. There&amp;#39;s no doubt that reading the book before seeing the film negatively impacted my views on the adaptation. Compared to the thrilling dense logic of Andy Weir&amp;#39;s against-all-odds narrative, the film feels like a bit of a melodramatic, overly-sentimental mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it isn&amp;#39;t bad. I don&amp;#39;t think Ridley Scott ever makes bad movies. But he does make movies that feel like they could have been sharper, and &lt;b&gt;The Martian&lt;/b&gt; is one of them. So although the movie gets a lot of aspects right, and delivers some exciting set-pieces, I think it butchers what makes this story great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story obviously centres around the lead character, Mark Watney. I find Matt Damon to be a great Mark Watney. Unfortunately so much of the character&amp;#39;s ingenuity that made him a great protagonist is missing from the film. This comes as a side effect of how many subplots are removed from the film&amp;#39;s narrative. Basically, a lot more stuff goes wrong in the book, thereby making Mark Watney a more impressive Mars survivor. A major message of the story is how powerful science is, how much humans can achieve when they put their mind to it, how cool this is, but by simplifying Watney&amp;#39;s challenges the film makes this a less powerful theme. Surviving Mars is depicted as a much easier feat in the movie. By leaving scientific details unexplained but highlighting Watney&amp;#39;s somewhat rebellious nature, the movie makes Watney seem more reckless than ingenious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;#39;s just the filmic dramatisation of it all. I fell in love with the novel because of how real it feels, with logical situations and not-necessarily likeable people. It&amp;#39;s probably my own fault for having so many expectations, but I was disappointed that the film lost this factor by over-emphasizing emotional beats. It just doesn&amp;#39;t feel real anymore. Most offputting is the way the film depicts communication between characters in different parts of space. In the book this is no problem, it&amp;#39;s all typed. Unfortunately the only thing the film does to make this screen-worthy is to have the characters say out loud what they are typing. That looks stupid. Here, let me try. I&amp;#39;m doing it right now. I am sitting in my room saying these words aloud. I feel like an idiot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this is a downer. The film isn&amp;#39;t bad though. I think it just stood little chance against the book it drew from, especially when it decided to simplify and dumb-down rather than adapt and explore the narrative. What should have been a taut, nail-biting outer-space &lt;i&gt;The Truman Show&lt;/i&gt; is instead a mess of half explained science fiction wrapped in a sentimental sheet of tattered NASA canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/The-Martian-viral-teaser.Bjic7sVa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category><category>books</category></item><item><title>Everest (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/everest-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/everest-review/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;When you trek into a film called &lt;b&gt;Everest&lt;/b&gt;, which is based on true events and stars of slew of well-known actors, you have a pretty good idea what to expect. Probably an expansive drama or tragedy, portraying people at the &lt;i&gt;peak&lt;/i&gt; of human endeavor, pushing themselves to the &lt;i&gt;edge&lt;/i&gt;. That, &lt;b&gt;Everest&lt;/b&gt; delivers. But we&amp;#39;ve seen that before. I feel the need to demand a little more out of this movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://redcarpetrefs.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Everest-Movie.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://redcarpetrefs.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Everest-Movie.jpg&quot; height=&quot;212&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the positive, the cast is pretty amazing. I&amp;#39;m a big fan of Jason Clarke, and he&amp;#39;s a great lead, surrounded by about a dozen other excellent actors. No trouble in this camp, they all deliver fine performances - though I&amp;#39;d argue they weren&amp;#39;t given a lot to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story progresses slowly and predictably for the first half, without a lot of conflict or drama. But in the second half, when things start to go poorly for our climbers, the chain reaction of unfortunate events &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; effective. I&amp;#39;ll tell ya, I didn&amp;#39;t want to climb a mountain before seeing this film, but now I&amp;#39;m &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; put off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wallbacks.com/walls/everest-2015-american-3d-disaster-thriller-film-wide.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.wallbacks.com/walls/everest-2015-american-3d-disaster-thriller-film-wide.jpg&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Could someone tell Gyllenhaal the mountain&apos;s a little higher on the green screen &amp;nbsp;than that?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
I think that in order to be an emotionally effective film, &lt;b&gt;Everest&lt;/b&gt; should have focused on fewer characters and streamlined dramatic stakes. Basically, tighter storytelling. There are several key sections in the film where I did find myself engrossed by a moment of tension, or elation, but it never lasted or hit me as hard as it should have. The film is juggling too much, there&apos;s no room to breathe, and we&apos;re out of oxygen tanks.

&lt;p&gt;But of course, this is a true story being told. Director Baltasar Kormákur likely juggles so much because he simply wants to portray this entire scenario with honesty. Unfortunately I just don&amp;#39;t think it makes excellent drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.awardscircuit.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/everest-trailer-movie_h.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.awardscircuit.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/everest-trailer-movie_h.jpg&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Altogether now, woooaaahh!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
The cinematography is of course excellent. Each section of the mountain is captured beautifully. There&apos;s also great sound design to match. When storms hit, you are sonically &lt;i&gt;buffeted&lt;/i&gt; by wind and snow. Which is particularly striking when contrasted with a clever cut between an Everest storm and a quiet home in Australia. Throw in Dario Marianelli&apos;s beautiful - if forgettable - score, and you&apos;ve got a lot of great filmmaking to enjoy.

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aceshowbiz.com/images/still/everest-2015-02.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;![](./everest-2015-02.jpg)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Assuming this was shot after &lt;i&gt;Nightcrawler&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Southpaw&lt;/i&gt;, Gyllenhaal must be hurtin&apos;!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
In the end, I wanted this film to explore is the &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt;. Why do these characters want to put themselves through this crippling challenge? Why climb Mount Everest? The film certainly acknowledges these questions, nods at them, flirts with them, but ultimately never brings anything satisfying to that discussion. The script simply doesn&apos;t try to say anything much interesting. Sure, the story successfully extracted some emotion from me, but it never investigated the meaning behind what happened, or told me why I should care.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Everest &lt;/b&gt;is the movie you expect it to be, but nothing more, and that left me somewhat disappointed. Good, but not great.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>The Gift (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/the-gift-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/the-gift-review/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;How can you pursue a &amp;quot;fresh start&amp;quot; when you&amp;#39;re the same person you always were?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;#39;t seen it, I&amp;#39;m going to say here - at the top - that I thoroughly enjoyed this film, and think it&amp;#39;s a particularly excellent experience if you go into it knowing very littleabout the plot and characters. So I advise that you only read on if you have either seen &lt;b&gt;The Gift&lt;/b&gt;, or you don&amp;#39;t care about me trying to care about you right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://filmfanboy.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/The-Gift-Poster.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://filmfanboy.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/The-Gift-Poster.jpg&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Gift&lt;/b&gt; depicts the slow and fascinating disruption of a married couple when they start to receive visits from an old friend. Now, that synopsis actually makes the film sound rather dull to me. But actually, the film is so laser focused on the three lead characters, on peeling away their layers, that the drama quickly becomes far more fascinating. From the opening scene it&amp;#39;s all about learning who these characters are and, before long, relearning. Very little actually occurs during the film to change them, but as a viewer, discovering more about their pasts twists your affections in shocking ways. A powerful theme of the film is the question of whether a person can change, as an adult, from who they were as a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any superb thriller, &lt;b&gt;The Gift&lt;/b&gt; plays on the audience&amp;#39;s expectations. The film builds slowly, planting small seeds, aware that they will grow and multiply in the thinking viewer&amp;#39;s mind. It reminded me of last year&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/i&gt; in this way. Between every scene I felt the desire to turn to those around me to ask, &amp;quot;What do you think about [character] now?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is thanks to the simple and relatable hook of the film (a visit from the past) that I found the audience to be pulled in very quickly. We wanted to know more about these characters, and before long the film made us regret it (in a good way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmcvariety.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/the-gift_new.jpg?w=670&amp;amp;h=377&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;https://pmcvariety.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/the-gift_new.jpg?w=670&amp;amp;h=377&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost as an experiment to test audience engagement, the middle section of the film includes a series of jump scares (some of which pop, some sizzle out, and some are red herrings). In my screening, we were all hooked. Every time the cinematography forecast a potential jump scare the whole cinema tensed up. Then when the film relieved the tension, laughs, gasps and sighs echoed from every seat. This isn&amp;#39;t a horror film, and we weren&amp;#39;t a horror audience, so we didn&amp;#39;t &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to be scared, and that&amp;#39;s why it was so effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see absolutely no flaws in Jason Bateman&amp;#39;s performance. It&amp;#39;s a similar character and performance to his great role in &lt;i&gt;Disconnect&lt;/i&gt;, although &lt;b&gt;The Gift&lt;/b&gt; goes much deeper. The audience is shown many more sides of his character than is comfortable. Like many actors known for their comedy, I have always preferred Bateman in dramatic texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peeltheorange.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/The-Gift-Trailer.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://peeltheorange.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/The-Gift-Trailer.jpg&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Hall plays a complex role with a wealth of honesty. For the most part, her character is the closest we&amp;#39;ve got to an audience surrogate. Therefore it is extremely satisfying that she is portrayed with so much intelligence and agency. Many similar characters in other films are ignorant of danger or poorly perceive the events around them, but Hall&amp;#39;s character does everything I would have done in her situation - and that&amp;#39;s fantastic to watch. The frustrating horror in which the victims never call the police, this is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/TheGiftReviewStill21.DWxX6LkE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this point goes across the board. There are half a dozen side characters who appear throughout the film who all seem like such realistic, living characters - even with very minimal screen time. Characters on screen are not often this perceptive of each other, this intricate. Well written, well directed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of... how Joel Edgerton wrote and directed this film while giving his incredible, subtly aggressive performance is difficult to comprehend. His became one of the scariest performances I&amp;#39;ve seen in a while, without even a creepy smile. And it&amp;#39;s frightening because it feels so true, and so tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/920x920.DFLXHsi-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The haunting soundtrack is simple and very effective. Composer Danny Bensi knows how to creep into the back of your mind and disturb you. The score keeps close to a delicate, ponderous little theme for the most part, except when sonic madness is required, which - judging by my tense muscles at the end of the film - was delivered effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overarching messages of the film are bold, challenging, devastating, but most importantly - &lt;i&gt;important&lt;/i&gt;. These are ideas worth spreading (oops hi TED). And tying it all up in a puffy red bow,&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;The Gift&lt;/b&gt; is a thrilling character drama which will haunt me forever.&amp;nbsp;Touché, Edgerton, I&amp;#39;ll see you in &lt;i&gt;Black Mass&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Me and Earl and the Dying Girl (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/me-and-earl-and-the-dying-girl-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/me-and-earl-and-the-dying-girl-review/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A fun film which is stuffed full of indie tropes, including the &lt;em&gt;makes-fun-of-indie-film-tropes&lt;/em&gt; trope. I had a great time until the third act in which the film ditches its humour (its most unique feature) in favour of an emotional ending which was good but felt fairy stereotypical and unoriginal. The first two thirds of the narrative had a quirky and unpredictable edge, whereas the resolution looked eerily like something I&amp;#39;ve seen in a lot of other movies. Big ups to the proficient-beyond-their-years cast and the determined-to-entertain cinematography. This is a film that benefits (and in my case, benefited) from a loud, emotionally invested live audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/m-e-dg-1.BRjXIYtu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Him, Earl and yes, the Dying Girl too, were a charming trio to spend several hours with, but - although they certainly tried - they didn&amp;#39;t quite change my life. The film is however finding great success around the world thus far, so I look forward to seeing some of these actors and filmmakers around the cinema more often in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>The Man from U.N.C.L.E. (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/the-man-from-uncle-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/the-man-from-uncle-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;One could say that Guy Ritchie&amp;#39;s &lt;b&gt;The Man from U.N.C.L.E.&lt;/b&gt; is all style, no substance. It&amp;#39;s a statement I&amp;#39;ve heard several times already from critics and audiences, and though personally I enjoyed the film enormously, it&amp;#39;s a sentiment I don&amp;#39;t disagree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry Cavill appears to be totally relaxed in his debonair role of American spy Solo, alongside the also cool (unless insulted) Russian spy Illya played by Armie Hammer.&amp;nbsp;Alicia Vikander completes the leading trio as a German spy called Gaby. There isn&amp;#39;t a lot for Elizabeth Debicki to do as the villain of the film, but she seems to have fun as the elegant antagonist. Pretty much everyone is putting on an accent in this film, which I think just adds to the whole crazy, brazen production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cinemablend.com/images/reviews/67027/main.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film features some rollicking fun set pieces, often making use of (surprisingly) dark humour. Ritchie makes great perspective choices, several times having violence or action sequences take place at a distance or in the background, juxtaposed with the cool, carefree confidence that is the default mindset of the leads. The film overall is very funny, and the audience in my theatre were won over by the charming characters by around halfway through the first scene. It helps that the leading men and their heated relationship is quickly communicated and easy for the viewer to understand; their dynamic something that the audience can latch on to from the beginning of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Man from U.N.C.L.E.&amp;#39;s period setting is a slightly heightened reality. Actions and events that are just a little bit impossible take place throughout the film, and it can be a challenge to keep the audience suspending their disbelief. Ritchie never lets the film get too grounded, however. Almost constantly there are subtle reminders of the film&amp;#39;s supernormal tilt, the best example being a scene in which a character spins a lightbulb hanging from the ceiling, and it continues to spin at the same momentum for the rest of the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://icdn1.digitaltrends.com/image/the-man-from-uncle-0030-1500x1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style oozes out into every area of this production. Scenes are edited together in a non-linear fashion, whereby we see the barebones of a conversation then flashback (often multiple times) to fill in the details that were originally withheld. This makes the twisting narrative both easier to follow than it would otherwise be, and keeps the audience engaged and on their toes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Pemberton&amp;#39;s score is the perfect combination of cool and quirky. It&amp;#39;s rare to see a film score blended so effectively with the visuals, but &lt;strong&gt;The Man from U.N.C.L.E.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s split-frame, picture-in-picture action montages are a consistent treat across all the senses. It&amp;#39;s also enhanced by fantastic song choices, which are often diegetic. For example &amp;quot;Cry to Me&amp;quot; by Solomon Burke, which is played during a intoxicatingly cute dance scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://assets.nydailynews.com/polopoly_fs/1.2113298!/img/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/article_635/man-uncle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man from U.N.C.L.E.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s run time flew by. It&amp;#39;s two hours well spent with likable characters being perfectly charming. I personally wanted to see our heroes start to get along a bit more at some point in the film, and work together as an efficient team, but alas they remained an (albeit entertaining) dysfunctional trio of bickering. Hopefully in the (likely) sequel we&amp;#39;ll see some new dynamics from team U.N.C.L.E.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Far from the Madding Crowd (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/far-from-the-madding-crowd-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/far-from-the-madding-crowd-review/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Drawn in by the familiar names (Thomas Vinterberg, Carey Mulligan, Craig Armstrong, Michael Sheen) I approached this 2015 adaptation of &lt;b&gt;Far from the Madding Crowd&lt;/b&gt; with a degree of enthusiasm. This was my first encounter with the text, which started as a novel by Thomas Hardy and has been adapted for the cinema several times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the film certainly felt to me like an adaptation. Characters made decisions that had me shaking my head, which would have been perfectly fine if I had been privy to more of their motivations and thought processes. The narrative, as I understand it, is largely about choice, and it seemed strange to me that the viewer is kept at a distance during these turning points. Often this distancing effect comes because of a montage, of great deals of time passing in the story. Perhaps a necessary evil of the novel-to-screen translation? I find the result to be a film which depicts a great story, but does not successfully plant the viewer within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pmcvariety.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/image-893f6605-3367-4059-9246-3d7965328afd.jpg?w=670&amp;h=377&amp;crop=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast are brilliant. Carey Mulligan is a brilliant lead, Matthias Schoenaerts gives a very subtle performance, Michael Sheen is the perfect tragic man, and Tom Sturridge plays his part well - assuming his part is to be despised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most confidently successful aspect of this film is its cinematography. Cinematographer Charlotte Bruus Christensen shoots the country like a fantastical place, delivering constantly stunning images of hills and sunsets and magical woods. The soldier&amp;#39;s red uniform as set against earthy green landscapes is particularly striking throughout the film, no doubt an intended thematic contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly gentle but soaring in all the right places, Crag Armstrong&amp;#39;s score plays an enormous role in building this world. It features a throat-tightening string melody reminiscent of James Newton Howard&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;The Village&lt;/em&gt;, two parts beauty one part tragedy. Armstrong also uses flutes and harps for soft beats and piano ostinatos to underline the bolder sections. Music plays an important role in heightening the narrative, best demonstrated in the beautiful scene when Mulligan and Sheen sing &amp;quot;Let No Man Steal Your Thyme&amp;quot; - my favourite part of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/far-from-madding-crowd10.B0es7xWs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is a beautiful film with characters I didn&amp;#39;t connect to intimately. And since the narrative hangs on these characters, their choices and their relationships, feeling somewhat distant from them is unfortunate. It may not be a masterpiece like Vinterberg&amp;#39;s previous film, &lt;em&gt;The Hunt&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;strong&gt;Far from the Madding Crowd&lt;/strong&gt; is nonetheless a very enjoyable period drama.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Mission Impossible - Rogue Nation (Review)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/mission-impossible---rogue-nation-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/mission-impossible---rogue-nation-review/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;The facet of the Mission Impossible franchise that keeps me fascinated with each installment is its crystal clear contract with audiences. When you sit down in front of any Mission Impossible film, you know almost precisely what kind of experience you are about to have. Which is not to say that you know what you are going to see, or that the direction of the plot will be predictable. On the contrary, Mission Impossible&amp;#39;s suspenseful, set-piece-focused, constantly twisting formula is as riveting as it is consistent. It feels like a TV series on the big screen, with all the production values of the latter but what keeps bringing you back is the characters and themes that feel like a show. (Of course, this makes sense, because the film franchise spawned from a TV series.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://p1cdn04.thewrap.com/images/2015/04/tom-cruise-mission-impossible-rogue-nation.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://p1cdn04.thewrap.com/images/2015/04/tom-cruise-mission-impossible-rogue-nation.jpg&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open a film with Tom Cruise literally hanging on to a plane as it takes off, maintaining interest for another two hours sounds like a tall order. Luckily, Christopher McQuarrie - the latest in the exciting lineup of Mission Impossible directors - is canny enough to know he doesn&amp;#39;t have to go bigger. The set pieces that follow are engaging in their intensity, their complexity and their breathlessness, and thankfully never try to do something &amp;quot;larger&amp;quot; than the opening sequence - which would surely have made this blockbuster crumble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Rogue Nation feels like a smaller film than MI:4 Ghost Protocol. But this shrinking of scale is well managed, and MI:5 feels just as thrilling in its stakes. In place of scaling skyscrapers (for example), Rogue Nation has stronger emotional threads, mostly thanks to the subplot led by Rebecca Ferguson (the first Mission Impossible heroin I thought really worked), and a couple of charged interactions between Cruise and Simon Pegg. It&amp;#39;s all very Bond-y, as well, obviously because of the London setting but also because Sean Harris&amp;#39; rather classical spy villain, Solomon Lane, is a great and mysterious opponent for Ethan Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission Impossible works because it is, figuratively and otherwise, grounded. Grounded perhaps not in reality but in &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; reality. Tom Cruise&amp;#39;s Ethan Hunt may perform the impossible, but it&amp;#39;s always a challenge for him. He&amp;#39;s no fearless superhero, which would make the whole thing rather bland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Giacchino, who scored the last two installments of the series brilliantly, is not present for Rogue Nation. But whatever tears I may have been crying over his departure are long forgotten under the flood of joyful tears when I heard Joe Kraemer&amp;#39;s effort. It&amp;#39;s an extremely classy soundtrack, which plays with opera, always drives a rhythm, and knows the power it has in the Mission Impossible theme - without overusing it. It&amp;#39;s definitely going to be in my top scores of 2015. Kraemer, you have my attention. And good luck topping this spy action in Spectre, Thomas Newman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogue Nation is another fantastic installment in one the best action franchises around.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>How to be an Intolerable Teammate in Heroes of the Storm</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/how-to-be-an-intolerable-teammate-in-heroes-of-the-storm/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/how-to-be-an-intolerable-teammate-in-heroes-of-the-storm/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Blizzard has smashed its way into the three-laned landscape of MOBAs with its new universe-blending brawler, Heroes of the Storm. It&amp;#39;s a game of intense action that requires lightning fast skill. As an online-only multiplayer game in which, unless you have a lot of friends, you&amp;#39;re going to be playing alongside many complete strangers, it quickly becomes clear that you can manipulate them as if they really exist or something. Here&amp;#39;s just a few ways to annoy your PUG teammates and be an incredibly bothersome player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Ping More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, you can not ping too much. An effective team should know what you are doing at every moment. Are you going top lane? Ping it. Are you gonna fight some mercenaries? Ping it. Are you worried someone is about to die? Ping it. Like the way a tree looks on the map? You know it, ping it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say ping, I don&amp;#39;t mean ping (singular). I mean ping (plural). Never ever ping just once. Don&amp;#39;t have enough faith in your team&amp;#39;s observational skills for that. If you want to retreat, ping it &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; eight times. Ping any less than that and it is very easy to miss and you might not have gained the complete and undivided attention of your allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ggmaster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/lol-smart-ping.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Give Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But stay in the match. Sometimes you know you&amp;#39;re on a loser team (or team of losers, depending on how you like to think of it). This happens. Even though Heroes of the Storm is designed so that dramatic come-backs are always plausible, you can just know in your gut it&amp;#39;s all over. Even if your team argues with you, you&amp;#39;ve gotta trust yourself. In these cases it is perfectly acceptible to give up and stand around your base. Don&amp;#39;t leave the match though - you still deserve your XP!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vignette3.wikia.nocookie.net/heroesofthestorm/images/3/36/Li_Li-experience.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20140624002722&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Sit Around Until You AFK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different situation: the game&amp;#39;s going fine, but you&amp;#39;ve gotta go. Real life comes first of course, but if you&amp;#39;ve gotta leave - don&amp;#39;t quit the game. Blizzard have implemented this system which makes AI take over your character when you leave, so make sure you sit your character some place relatively safe before you walk away from your computer, so your team knows you&amp;#39;re there in spirit until you time out and get automatically kicked. Even though you&amp;#39;re not there to see it, know that they will most certainly be praising your thoughtfulness in that chat. You&amp;#39;re a legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gon.cdn.on.net/uploads/2014/03/heroes_of_the_swarm_preview_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Critique Your Allies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the Hero of the Storm. Say it. &amp;quot;I am the Hero of the Storm&amp;quot;. That&amp;#39;s right. You&amp;#39;re a gamer, you know this $#!&amp;amp; backwards. If your team is having any issues, you&amp;#39;ve got to tell them why that is. If it looks like someone isn&amp;#39;t playing their character the way you would yourself, point it out. You&amp;#39;ve got to isolate the exact fault, and make sure the perpetrator knows they are costing the team everything. This game is not for carebears. If you can&amp;#39;t handle the intensity or understand the strategy then you should go play something that has a lower IQ requirement, like Life Is Strange. Tell them that. They&amp;#39;ll beg for forgiveness thank you for your honesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Curse Your Enemies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the #&amp;amp;!@&lt;em&gt;#%# @&lt;/em&gt;!&amp;amp;#&lt;em&gt;$ #&lt;/em&gt;@&amp;amp; @^!*@&amp;amp;#amp; that they are. They&amp;#39;re just overpowered glitch hackers, and every time you die you need to blame your killer. This tip goes hand in hand with the previous one; blaming the enemy in no way prevents you from also blaming your own team. It can be everyone else&amp;#39;s fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.pcgamesn.com/sites/default/files/heroes%20of%20the%20storm%20giveaway%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s it for my tips, but remember: there&amp;#39;s a whole world of irritating things you can do online. Be creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to tolerating you in the Nexus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;/facetious&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>list</category><category>ramble</category><category>comedy</category><category>games</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2009</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2009/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2009/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;My pursuit to Top-10-listify my favourite film soundtracks of the past decade has hit the late naughts. Enjoy below in both oral and written formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?episode_id=5294667&quot;&gt;Audio Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Lunar Industries&lt;/em&gt;, Moon - Clint Mansell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinite White&lt;/em&gt;, Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen - Steve Jablonsky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Married Life&lt;/em&gt;, Up - Michael Giacchino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dumbledore&amp;#39;s Farewell&lt;/em&gt;, Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince - Nicholas Hooper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Moon&lt;/em&gt;, The Twilight Saga: New Moon - Alexandre Desplat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nero Fiddles, Narada Burns&lt;/em&gt;, Star Trek - Michael Giacchino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jake Enters His Avatar World&lt;/em&gt;, Avatar - James Horner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dragonball Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, Dragonball Evolution - Brian Tyler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logan Through Time&lt;/em&gt;, X-Men Origins: Wolverine - Harry Gregson-Williams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;160 BPM&lt;/em&gt;, Angels &amp;amp; Demons - Hans Zimmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional Track:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wizard Wheezes&lt;/em&gt;, Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince - Nicholas Hooper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Christmas Carol Main Title&lt;/em&gt;, A Christmas Carol - Alan Silvestri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours outwittingly,
T&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Soundtrack Review World of WarCraft Warlords of Draenor</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/soundtrack-review-world-of-warcraft-warlords-of-draenor/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/soundtrack-review-world-of-warcraft-warlords-of-draenor/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Few franchises have musical history as magnificent as Blizzard&amp;#39;s WarCraft. From the very first WarCraft game, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u38HN6TMcgw&quot;&gt;1994&amp;#39;s Orcs and Humans&lt;/a&gt;, the series has been producing a powerful, considered soundtrack. Mostly warlike and always brooding, these early scores from the &amp;#39;90s lean heavily on marching drum rhythms and repetitive, borderline groovy melodies - a style slowly been left behind as the series progressed. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPoSAo7YFsw&quot;&gt;WarCraft III (2002)&lt;/a&gt;, the property&amp;#39;s style had expanded to include hauntingly beautiful, ethereal pieces, and an abundance of operatic choir. Not long after that World of Warcraft launched (in 2004) and the series expanded tenfold. And with WoW the sound became more cinematic than ever; big, orchestral and epic. Five expansions later and we bring this introductory overview to a close because we have reached the main subject of my review: World of Warcraft: Warlords of Draenor by composers Jason Heyes, Glenn Stafford and Tracy Bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cjs-cdkeys.com/product_images/w/wod__72301.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems pointless to wait until the end of this article to say this: Warlords of Draenor is a very good soundtrack. It is truly fantastic. The question is however, how does it stand as a &lt;em&gt;WarCraft&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack? Does it contain everything we&amp;#39;ve come to expect from the series, and does it maintain the outstanding musical qualities of past installments? In order to determine these answers, I have devised the five things that I believe make a good WarCraft score a good WarCraft score. I will now tackle each of these in relation to Warlords of Draenor. So without further ado, read on for my five essential elements of a WarCraft score:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Pathos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WarCraft must appeal to the player&amp;#39;s sense of heroism, rousing and calling them to war. Warlords of Draenor passes this test with both hands tied behind its back. War-loving orcs feature at the centre of the new story, so we&amp;#39;re in a world of deep chanting and war drums thrumming. There are tons of epic sized rousing tracks here, in fact most of the score, so there&amp;#39;s no point listing the relevant tracks. Probably chief(tan) in this area however are &amp;quot;Times Change&amp;quot; (3), which feels like a very clear introduction to grand conflict, and &amp;quot;Clan Warsong&amp;quot; (5), which uses some unique instrumentation to create a piece that could easily underscore a gathering army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We Will Be Conquerors&amp;quot; (13) is a highlight of the album. It features what I refer to as the &amp;#39;Warlords Theme&amp;#39;, a brilliant motif that provides evidence that the greatest music can be deceptively simplistic. The Warlords Theme is slow but powerful, with only a few (very predictable) ascending notes. This track features a rendition with a marching drum beat, the orchestra slowly expanding as the melody is repeated thrice. My theory is that the most engaging element of this Warlords Theme is the restraint it demonstrates - it contains the immense power of an enormous orchestra but only uses it strictly and sparingly. It gives me shivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Sentiment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With lore this big, it&amp;#39;d be silly not to call back to themes of past games/expansions/content. Luckily, WarCraft is not silly. Every release has featured a new rendition of a classic theme. A fan pleaser, if you will. Warlords of Draenor doesn&amp;#39;t feature many musical callbacks, but as always the overture is a blend of the old and the new. &amp;quot;A Siege Of Worlds&amp;quot; features many familiar motifs in its 12 minute runtime, most the most rousing is the final one. Around the 10:50 mark begins a magnificent rendition of a WarCraft III theme so glorious that I did admittedly very nearly get tears in my eyes. It feels like it brings the franchise experience full circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Shock&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every World of Warcraft expansion soundtrack has included something which, on first listen, sounds utterly insane. It is an element that captures your attention with its wild uniqueness. &amp;quot;Khadgar&amp;quot; (15) opens with several shocking orchestral stabs. This incredibly villainous piece has an impressive audacity which grabs attention effectively and holds it tightly. But again there&amp;#39;s that fantastic restraint. I find it very effective when the composers show the unleashed power of the full orchestra then proceed to use it delicately. &amp;quot;Family&amp;quot; is a heartwarming piece until the second half when it changes entirely into a proud march with deliberately jarring instrumentation including delightfully off-key brass. Actually, it&amp;#39;s really enjoyable and probably also belongs in this next section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Fun&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WarCraft can be a dauntingly serious universe. Luckily the creators understand that it can be refreshing to throw in a joke. So as synonymous as WarCraft is with war, death and conflict, immersion-shattering silliness has also become a recurring element of the series. Warlords of Draenor continues the trend. The second half of &amp;quot;Old Growth&amp;quot; (11) has a hint of farce in its sinister piano-and-güiro melody. &amp;quot;Tides Of War&amp;quot; (19) is a magnificent clincher, unexpectedly ending the soundtrack with a Musketeers-esque shanty - so different in style to anything I&amp;#39;ve heard from WarCraft before that at first it seems totally wrong. Maybe it&amp;#39;s a hint at what we&amp;#39;ll hear next time, and if so I&amp;#39;m chuffed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Beauty&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WarCraft&amp;#39;s world also contains immense beauty, and the music reflects that. These pieces are often tearjerking in their demonstrations of subtlety or fragility in a universe that is oft assume entirely &amp;#39;macho&amp;#39;. &amp;quot;Visions Of The Prophet&amp;quot; (6) is essentially a tragic string solo. It tells many stories. The true heart of the album however, can be located right at the heart. &amp;quot;Family&amp;quot; (10) is of a similiar beautiful style, conjuring imagery of campfires and noble tales. A simple drum holds the beat as the strings share the emotion. The second half of the track is a complete reversal in tone, as I&amp;#39;ve already discussed in the &amp;#39;Shock&amp;#39; section. &amp;quot;Ways Of The Ancient Ones&amp;quot; (14) is incredibly beautiful, and arguably the most magical piece. It uses a solo female vocal and a full choir for particularly emotive moments. More than most of the soundtrack this piece feels like it was created for the &amp;#39;world&amp;#39;, as opposed to characters or narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve referred to elements I love in a variety of tracks, but should also note that as with past World of Warcraft soundtracks, the first track [&amp;quot;A Siege Of Worlds&amp;quot; (1)] is an overture, featuring a taste of many of the wonders the score contains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Warlords of Draenor the best WarCraft score yet? Probably not. Mists of Pandaria gets a nose ahead in my opinion, but only a nose. This is an incredible soundtrack with an abundant display of creativity which could easily have been discarded in place of a generic sequel. WarCraft has already created one of the most impressive musical worlds ever. They don&amp;#39;t have to prove themselves anymore. They could rehash and reuse if they wanted. But no, with each release they reach higher into the glorious unknown. Draenor is magnificent, and with no clear end in sight to this wave of World of Warcraft expansion packs, I&amp;#39;m excited for where we go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/5 from me.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>music</category><category>games</category><category>writing</category><category>list</category><category>review</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2008</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2008/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2008/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Scores of Scores is back after a big weird random unexpected hiatus! Hope you enjoy my favourite film soundtracks from 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=5222274&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another Way To Die, Quantum Of Solace&lt;/em&gt; - Jack White &amp;amp; Alicia Keys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. EVE, WALL-E&lt;/em&gt; - Thomas Newman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. Watergate, Frost/Nixon&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. Favela Escape, The Incredible Hulk&lt;/em&gt; - Craig Armstrong
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. Oil Fields, Quantum Of Solace&lt;/em&gt; - David Arnold
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. The Adventures Of Mutt, Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. Bella&amp;#39;s Lullaby, Twilight&lt;/em&gt; - Carter Burwell
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Return of the Lion, The Chronicles of Narnia: Prince Caspian&lt;/em&gt; - Harry Gregson-Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Harvey Two-Face, The Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer &amp;amp; James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Hero, Kung Fu Panda&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer &amp;amp; John Powell
&lt;em&gt;Raider&amp;#39;s March, Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours dancingly,
T&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Brief Analysis of Reunion Scene from The Truman Show (1998)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-analysis-of-reunion-scene-from-the-truman-show-1998/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-analysis-of-reunion-scene-from-the-truman-show-1998/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;In his piece on the effects of music in film, &amp;quot;Corporeality, Musical Heartbeats and Cinematic Emotion&amp;quot;, Ben Winters explains that music can illicit emotion in the audience by replicating sounds we recognise our own bodies make. For example, heartbeat sounds are used to create tension and fear in &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt;. The following scene from The Truman Show has a soundtrack by Phillip Glass which features slow, drawn string notes which effectively emulate weeping or moping sounds - bringing about a subconscious physiological memory in the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/YfJc2bORFHs?rel=0&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing Winters writes about is the diegisis of the music - where it is thought to be coming from. Sometimes it emanates from a character, like the heartbeat score emanating from the alien itself in Alien. Most often soundtracks are intra-diegetic, which means we imagine the music is coming from a kind of omniscient narrator. But in this scene from The Truman Show we literally see where the music is originating. They&amp;#39;re playing it right there in front of us in order to manipulate us, and yet still it works. Even the characters in the studio in this scene, the ones creating the drama, they&amp;#39;re clearly getting emotionally affected. Therefore I&amp;#39;d argue that this scene demonstrates that the source of music doesn&amp;#39;t have to be mysterious to work, and intra-diegesis is somewhat irrelevant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two more brief points Winters writes about that I think are confirmed by this scene. First is the the mimetic hypothesis: the idea that we experience emotion by emulating what we see or hear on screen. This kinda goes back to the wailing strings. We hear something like wailing and on some level we understand how that feels, physically. And after Truman hugs his father, just about every other character in this scene starts hugging the closest person to them - mimicking Truman in order to successfully and totally empathise with his emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then all this emotion that is felt by both us as the audience and the characters watching Truman in this scene is only what Winters calls &amp;#39;cinematic-emotion&amp;#39;. It&amp;#39;s cognitive. You feel it, but you don&amp;#39;t believe it. This is confirmed by that fact that, just as in a horror film you can experience very real fear and not get up and call the police, Truman&amp;#39;s audience and creators feel his emotions - longing, sadness - but do nothing to help him. They don&amp;#39;t believe in him as a real person, even though he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a few of the ways in which I believe this scene both creates cinematic drama and demonstrates some of the genre&amp;#39;s inner-workings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winters, Ben. &amp;quot;Corporeality, Musical Heartbeats and Cinematic Emotion&amp;quot;. &lt;em&gt;Music, Sound and the Moving Image&lt;/em&gt;. Vol2, Issue 1. Spring 2006. p. 3-25.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Doctor Who Season 7 Soundtrack Review</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/doctor-who-season-7-soundtrack-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/doctor-who-season-7-soundtrack-review/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Doctor Who’s original scores by MURRAY GOLD rank among the most brilliant and rewarding soundtracks of recent years. Time-travelling along at a release rate of annually-at-least, each album so far has been jam-packed with enthusiasm and overflowing with life, love and creativity. You could almost say they’re bigger on the inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does GOLD’s new album from the show’s 7th season match the enormously high bar that has been set? Spoilers! But yes. Yes it does. Granted, with 74 tracks, adding up to well over 2 hours of music, it’s hard not to be at least a little bit impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Doctor_Who_Series_7_soundtrack_cover.CdBYgIvj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant portion of the fun of a Doctor Who soundtrack is picking out GOLD’s self-references to his previously established themes - of which there are many. Sometimes these reprises are thrillingly subtle, like the return of the Dalek’s theme in “Towards The Asylum” (1-5), and sometimes they are splendidly overt, like the 11th Doctor’s Theme at the end of “I Might Change My Mind” (1-37). GOLD is happy to dance from theme to theme at a rapid pace, often within the same track. This emotional whiplash can make your first listen exhausting. Furthermore this score has many styles sewn imperfectly together; dramatic jumps between disparate themes and genres. This makes it unclear what the central drive is for the album as a whole, probably to a greater extent than any previous Doctor Who score. But in subsequent listens, when you know what formerly unpredictable emotional rises and falls to expect, the journey becomes significantly more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other downsides to having an overwhelming 74 tracks. Many tracks clock in at under a minute, which is hardly enough time to truly immerse yourself in a great piece. Notably, “Bah Bah Biker” (1-35) and “The Speeder” (2-6) are wonderfully energetic new melodies, but they have no room to breathe. Perhaps GOLD will expand upon these in future years, as has been his custom with other motifs in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creepy first section of tracks tred us tentatively into the Asylum of the Daleks, a world dark with danger and insanity. GOLD is notorious for his maniacal cheesiness and utter bombasity, but “They Are Everywhere” (1-1) is a poignantly reserved opening to the soundtrack. Effective features are the escalating string motifs and the use of deep, sombre horn for a majestic quality.“Towards The Asylum” (1-5) is pure GOLD. Classical influences, subtle hints at past themes, a marching beat with powerful momentum, and some banging. The flute, however, is something we haven’t heard in Doctor Who previously, and proves an effective new instrumental style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/asylum-of-the-daleks-promo-pic-b-5.C1B35vL2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They Are Everywhere” (1-1) foreshadows the two-note bass rhythm of “Together or Not at All - The Song of Amy and Rory” (1-28), a tense and emotional piece which begins to farewell the characters of Amy and Rory. There’s so much tragedy built into the rising melody. By the end of the piece percussion and vocals have joined the mix, in case you didn’t already have something in your eye. “Goodbye Pond” (1-29) is the true goodbye, though. It begins with a slight, tortured rendition of Amy’s signature melody before exploding into an orchestra-encompassing interpretation so powerful and breathless that it can only mean the end of a character. The track doubles as a wonderful goodbye to the melody itself, which certainly shall be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dabble your tears, let’s materialise into some other recurring melodies. Geronimo! The catchy fan favourite no one can get enough of, the 11th Doctor’s theme, makes several fresh appearances. It’s the highlight of “I Might Change My Mind” (1-37) and “Some Wednesday” (2-29). It also appears in “My Husband’s Home” (1-25), which evolves into a beautiful rendition of Series 5’s “The Sad Man With a Box”. All of these are fragmented crumbs compared to “Up The Shard” (1-36), which is the most complete reprise of the theme, heavily accented with loud orchestral banging, wailing and tumbling. It’s glorious. The most important recurring theme in this score however, is a new one. Accompanying the mystical and adventurous new companion, Clara’s theme is fluttering, lightweight, romantic and magical. It has a gentleness that goes back to Rose’s Theme of Series 1. This new melody is introduced at a basic level in “Oswin Oswald” (1-4) and reprised briefly in “A Probe in the Snow (1-6), but it is not until “Clara?” (1-33) that we get a complete rendition. At this point one might get nervous about overuse, but there is just enough variation in “The Leaf” (2-1) and “A Letter to Clara” (2-31) to keep the candle burning on Clara’s theme. I am glad it wasn’t spread any more thinly than that, it’s such a light melody it just might disintegrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn2us.denofgeek.com/sites/denofgeekus/files/styles/main_wide/public/tumblr_m9ovf1lvbl1qzhxrto1_1280.png?itok=6okMox-F&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn2us.denofgeek.com/sites/denofgeekus/files/styles/main_wide/public/tumblr_m9ovf1lvbl1qzhxrto1_1280.png?itok=6okMox-F&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOLD has fun playing to a genre, and it’s contagious for the listener. This season we’re treated to a Western setting. Doctor Who dabbled in Western sounds in Series 6 with “I Am The Doctor in Utah”, but GOLD’s approach is much more full-fledged this year, from the madness of “Make Peace” (1-12) to the solemn goodbye of “Our Little Town’s Prosecutor” (1-17). Standouts in this section are “Welcome to Mercy” (1-13) and “The Salvation of Kahler Jex” (1-16) which both feature gorgeous vocals by singer Halia Meguid, who has been involved in Doctor Who previously as Series 6’s “Deady Siren”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.gamezone.com/uploads/image/data/1120231/Doctor-Who-A-Town-Called-Mercy_1.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://download.gamezone.com/uploads/image/data/1120231/Doctor-Who-A-Town-Called-Mercy_1.jpg&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first disc ends with triumph. Trademark Doctor Who brass is abundant in “A Turbulent Flight” (1-34), an action-packed two minutes featuring just about every kind of horn-tooting in GOLD’s arsenal. Then there’s his love of blurring the line between song and score, realised in the catchy “Bah Bah Biker” (1-35). This is followed by “Up The Shard” (1-36), which teases the 11th Doctor’s theme before bursting into probably the most triumphant rendition we’ve ever heard. Finally, “I Might Change My Mind” (1-37) flutters and tinkles like a happy ending, then grows ever darker and more mysterious, entwining Clara’s theme and descending into melancholic peace. But of course, just when you think it’s over, the 11th Doctor’s theme returns again - ending the piece with all the power and excitement we love from MURRAY GOLD and Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/rings-akhaten-doctor-vs-old-god.CaW4GBHF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From “Market Day” (2-3) to “Infinite Potential” (2-9) we are in the score for The Rings of Akhaten episode. A dreadful 45 minutes of television in my opinion - but that’s irrelevant, because the music is jaw-droppingly, spine-tinglingly, life-affirmingly stunning. Through these tracks choir vocals are slowly incorporated into the sombre, building melody which isn’t played in it’s entirety, only teased until the ultimate piece, “The Long Song” (2-8). There are many emotionally potent tracks on this album, but “The Long Song” wins the ultimate tear-jerker award. Three quarters of the way through the song the lyrical vocals fade away and a spine-tingling rendition of what sounds like certain sections of the 11th Doctor’s theme fills the space. This is arguably the peak of the entire album. Completing this section of the score is “Infinite Potential” (2-9), which gives one last salute to the beautiful melody and ends with all of the orchestral composure one would expect from a first class John Williams score. MURRAY GOLD has come a long way since 2005, and he’s comparable in every way to the greats of the film music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following is a section of Cybermen-themed tracks. As always MURRAY GOLD can be relied upon to reprise his original theme for the Cybermen from Series 2, however this is no exciting revamp. This section of the score is contrastingly flat. Uninvolved melodramatic padding is to be expected in a two hour score, and most of it lies around here. It&amp;#39;s perfectly acceptable connective tissue, totally overshadowed by the wealth of brilliant pieces surrounding it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did someone say brilliant pieces? Oh yes, I did. “To Save the Doctor” (2-30) sees the exciting return of Series 3’s theme for the Doctor’s homeworld, Gallifrey. Another stylistic rehash is “Pain Everlasting” (2-36), a piece similar in manner to Series 5’s “Impossible Choice”, with a Prisoner of Azkaban-esque hollow lead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/uktv-name-of-the-doctor-new-pictures-15.ETpYASFa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remember Me” (2-37) is a powerful end to the album. It opens with a final simple rendition of Clara’s theme before transitioning into a cheeky, hammering rhythm which is - as is often the case with Doctor Who - just one step short of sounding very cheesy. Keen listeners will notice it melds together aspects of the 10th and 11th Doctors’ themes (something I wish we had heard more of in the 50th Anniversary Special).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctor Who’s 7th season since the revival in 2005 may have been the most rough, inconsistent and convoluted, but MURRAY GOLD’s music hasn’t missed a beat. Once again he has struck a pleasurable balance between introducing new themes and rehashing old ones. A few new themes stand firmly among GOLD’s best, and I hope we’ll hear these spectacular earworms again in the future. The only disappointment here is how short-lived some of these wonderful tracks are, but you can only spread butter so thin and you can only squeeze so much brilliance out of a composer each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This soundtrack isn’t surprising, but it does stand strong beside it’s stellar predecessors. It’s a no-brainer for anyone with passing interest in Doctor Who or MURRAY GOLD, who appears content to continue manipulating our emotions and skyrocketing our adrenalin for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>review</category><category>television</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2007</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2007/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2007/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Yet another year with a wonderfully diverse selection of film scores. Here are my favourites!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=5010888&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pretty Women, Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street&lt;/em&gt; - Johnny Depp &amp;amp; Alan Rickman
&lt;em&gt;Hoist The Colours, Pirates of the Caribbean: At World&amp;#39;s End&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. Main Titles, Michael Clayton&lt;/em&gt; - James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. Laura Tollins, The Number 23&lt;/em&gt; - Harry Gregson-Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. Farewell, Atonement&lt;/em&gt; - Dario Marianelli
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. Eastern Promises, Eastern Promises&lt;/em&gt; - Howard Shore
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. Assets and Targets, The Bourne Ultimatum&lt;/em&gt; - John Powell
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. Flight Of The Order Of The Phoenix, Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; - Nicholas Hooper
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. Arrival to Earth, Transformers&lt;/em&gt; - Steve Jablonsky
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Coronation, Stardust&lt;/em&gt; - Ilan Eshkeri
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Wong Chia Chi&amp;#39;s Theme, Lust, Caution&lt;/em&gt; - Alexandre Desplat
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Up Is Down, Pirates of the Caribbean: At World&amp;#39;s End&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;Elegy For Dunkirk, Atonement&lt;/em&gt; - Dario Marianelli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours rousingly,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2006</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2006/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2006/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;In ranking my favourite film scores from 2006 I realised this year has a lot of personal favourites. Check out my podcast and/or list below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=4950398&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Know My Name&lt;/em&gt; - Chris Cornell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. Fructus Gravis, The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. The Painted Veil, The Painted Veil&lt;/em&gt; - Alexandre Desplat
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. The Illusionist, The Illusionist&lt;/em&gt; - Phillip Glass
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. Cops or Criminals, The Departed&lt;/em&gt; - Howard Shore
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. Blunt Instrument, Casino Royale&lt;/em&gt; - David Arnold
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. Rough Flight, Superman Returns&lt;/em&gt; - John Ottman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. The Last Stand, X-Men: The Last Stand&lt;/em&gt; - John Powell
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Jack Sparrow, Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man&amp;#39;s Chest&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Death Is The Road To Awe, The Fountain&lt;/em&gt; - Clint Mansell
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Eragon, Eragon&lt;/em&gt; - Patrick Doyle
&lt;em&gt;The Kraken, Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man&amp;#39;s Chest&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours climatically,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2005</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2005/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2005/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of musical magic in this list. Also a lot of John Williams. I guess that explains it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you can experience my list in audio or text form below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=4925305&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do The Hippogriff, Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt; - Patrick Doyle
&lt;em&gt;Augustus Gloop, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory&lt;/em&gt; - Danny Elfman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. Going To School, Memoirs Of A Geisha&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. The Return To Boston, War Of The Worlds&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. Wall Breached, Kingdom of Heaven&lt;/em&gt; - Harry Gregson-Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. The River Cruise - Part 2, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory&lt;/em&gt; - Danny Elfman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. Remembering Munich, Munich&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. Evacuating London, The Chronicles of Narnia: The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe&lt;/em&gt; - Harry Gregson-Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. Central Park, King Kong&lt;/em&gt; - James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Myotis, Batman Begins&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer &amp;amp; James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Golden Egg, Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt; - Patrick Doyle
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Battle of the Heroes, Star Wars Episode III: Revenge of the Sith&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;Hogwarts March, Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire&lt;/em&gt; - Patrick Doyle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours craftily,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2004</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2004/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2004/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;One decade after the fact, here are my picks for the best film scores of 2004. As always, presented in both audio and textual formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=4899865&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Blue Sky, Eternal Sunshine Of The Spotless Mind&lt;/em&gt; - Electronic Light Orchestra
&lt;em&gt;Tell Me Now (What You See), King Arthur&lt;/em&gt; - Moya Brennan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. The Temple of Poseidon, Troy&lt;/em&gt; - James Horner
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. Main Title, Hellboy&lt;/em&gt; - Marco Beltrami
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. Regarding The Incredibly Deadly Viper, Lemony Snicket&amp;#39;s: A Series of Unfortunate Events&lt;/em&gt; - Thomas Newman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. He&amp;#39;s Back!, Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt; - Danny Elfman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. National Treasure Suite, National Treasure&lt;/em&gt; - Trevor Rabin
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. To The Roof, The Bourne Supremacy&lt;/em&gt; - John Powell
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. Those We Don&amp;#39;t Speak Of, The Village&lt;/em&gt; - James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Hold The Ice, King Arthur&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. The Glory Days, The Incredibles&lt;/em&gt; - Michael Giacchino
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. A Window to the Past, Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams
&lt;em&gt;Mischief Managed!, Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; - John Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours unendingly,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>podcast</category><category>list</category><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2003</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2003/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2003/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m back with my list of favourite film soundtracks from the year 2003, the top 5 of which I particularly adore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can listen to a recording of Scores of Scores here, where I introduce and play a snippet of each score, or if you prefer there is a complete tracklist below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=4873900&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All You Need Is Love, Love Actually&lt;/em&gt; - Lynden David Hall
&lt;em&gt;Wayfaring Stranger, Cold Mountain&lt;/em&gt; - Jack White&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. Matchstick Men, Matchstick Men&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. Flying Jolly Roger, Peter Pan&lt;/em&gt; - James Newton Howard
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. End Credits, Hulk&lt;/em&gt; - Danny Elfman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. First Day, Finding Nemo&lt;/em&gt; - Thomas Newman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. Sandra&amp;#39;s Theme, Big Fish&lt;/em&gt; - Danny Elfman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. Let The Games Begin, Sinbad&lt;/em&gt; - Harry Gregson Williams
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. Suite from X2, X-Men 2&lt;/em&gt; - John Ottman
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Safe Passage, The Last Samurai&lt;/em&gt; - Hans Zimmer
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Barbossa is Hungry, Pirates of the Caribbean&lt;/em&gt; - Klaus Badelt
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. The White Tree, Lord of the Rings: Return of the King&lt;/em&gt; - Howard Shore
&lt;em&gt;Into The West (feat. Annie Lennox), Lord of the Rings: Return of the King&lt;/em&gt; - Howard Shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours profusely,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>podcast</category><category>comedy</category><category>list</category></item><item><title>Review of &quot;Paper Planes&quot; (2014)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/review-of-paper-planes-2014/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/review-of-paper-planes-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;This week I got a chance to see this new Australian film directed by Robert Connolly at the Melbourne International Film Festival. It&amp;#39;s called Paper Planes, and although it appears to be marketed as a film for kids, I&amp;#39;d argue this move has something for all audiences. But then, now that I consider it, all great children&amp;#39;s entertainment can be enjoyed by everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.smh.com.au/2014/08/10/5666882/kq_paper-planes_wide-20140810183659643609-620x349.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For myself, and I daresay most others, the expectation when seeing an Australian film is somewhat lower and more cautious than when seeing a film from any other part of the world. Australian cinema has simply lacked imagination for most of its existence, excluding a brief run of comedy (The Castle, The Dish) and a foray into a dark depiction of suburbia (Animal Kingdom, Snowtown) - a fetish from which we are only just emerging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is with this caution that I sat down to see Paper Planes, but to my delight I found myself totally immersed in this incredibly cheerful film. It was a fantastic experience, no doubt heightened by the fact that each audience member was given a sheet of paper upon entering the cinema, with which to create a plane to toss across the theatre at will. This resulted in a very realistic 3D experience - without the need for big black spectacles - as an assortment of newly-constructed paper aircraft dove above our heads throughout the film (often jabbing an unsuspecting elderly gentleman in the face), making me regret the fact that I deliberately butchered my sheet of paper into a flightless creative mess. Sometimes I worry I&amp;#39;m becoming the kid who jumps on sandcastles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper Planes is an upbeat film in the vein of The Rocket. The narratives are both essentially the same, and predictable. Kid dreams of winning a niche tournament of some kind, overcomes many hurdles, probably succeeds - or at least learns a lot a long the way. But as the titles of both of these films clearly indicate, one is about rockets, and one is about paper planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things move along at a fast click; I was never bored. Cleverly, the film introduces the audience to the fact that it is not set in reality early on. It&amp;#39;s not a film that takes itself seriously, and you have to accept that. This ungrounded tone is something I often struggle with, but after the first ten minutes or so I was in. Like that shifty kid from Les Miserables, the sheer charm won me over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh yeah, it&amp;#39;s charming. The film oozes colour and enthusiasm and optimism. Take the teacher character for example. Played by Peter Rowsthorn, he&amp;#39;s goofy and funny and his students love him and so does the audience. The way he is encouraging and doesn&amp;#39;t underestimate others is refreshing and makes him not only a great character, but also a great role model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a children&amp;#39;s film in the best way. It doesn&amp;#39;t pander to young audiences but nor does it forsake them. The young characters are probably as mature as they can be without slurping whiskey and losing their hair. It&amp;#39;s fantastic, and Ed Oxenbould is astonishingly charismatic as the young lead, Dylan. In most films or TV shows, when a child is given a witty line it comes across forced, false or cheesy, but Oxenbould is totally relaxed on screen, and Dylan is a complete character with enough range to make the audience laugh and cry and truly get behind his motives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative is a pipe dream for classroom introverts like myself. I could relate to Dylan immediately when we are introduced him riding his bicycle down dry dirt paths to school, where he sits quietly in the classroom surrounded by a cacophony of overexcited kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/paper-planes-3.0JoX9qxm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Worthington is adequate as the morose couch-ridden father, but arguably more captivating is David Wenham as the father of an arrogant narcissistic boy - the antagonist. It&amp;#39;s very Veruca Salt from Charlie and the Chocolate Factory. For most of the movie, Wenham is basically the father Oxenbould desires, and I found their one scene together on a mini-golf rooftop in Tokyo particularly engaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.liveforfilms.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/paper-planes-2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack by Nigel Westlake also deserves a big callout, it&amp;#39;s excellent. Big, lively orchestral scores will excite me in even the most tedius films. But Westlake goes a step further with the integration of his music, playing with and off diegetic beats, for example using synchronising the start of a cue with the sound of a character slapping a table (not a specific reference - I forget exactly what kind of object the character was slapping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My excitement hesitated a little at the end, with what felt like a slightly forced conclusion. I can shake that off though. My desire for a realistic conclusion doesn&amp;#39;t complete ruin my enjoyment of this deliriously happy one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s only once the film had ended that I realised exactly what the film had achieved in regards to the coolness of paper planes. Just like the irrepressible desire to become a pirate after watching Pirates of the Caribbean, Paper Planes sold the magic of the concept of paper planes. Kids ran out of the cinema with at least one in each hand, spreading a contagious excitement. I entered thinking &amp;quot;paper planes? That&amp;#39;s cute.&amp;quot; I left thinking, &amp;quot;hell yeah - paper planes!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I guess you can probably tell, I liked this film. More than expected, more than most of Australian cinema, and more than enough to recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://miff.com.au/assets/2014/sessions/1541/130126_19109_2_PAPER_PLANES.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours frenziedly,
Thorough-still-can&amp;#39;t-make-a-paper-plane-for-the-life-of-him-mas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Top 10 Soundtracks from 2002</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2002/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-10-soundtracks-from-2002/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Last week I started a brand new show on Swinburne&amp;#39;s student radio station. Predictably, it&amp;#39;s all about film soundtracks. Each week I&amp;#39;ll be ranking my ten favourite film scores from each year, starting with the year 2002 and eventually reaching 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As explained at the start of this episode, I had some audio issues and this recording doesn&amp;#39;t sound as great as it will in future weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.spreaker.com/embed/player/standard?autoplay=false&amp;episode_id=4867461&quot;&gt;Spreaker Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every piece of music I played throughout this episode is available in full on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/playlist/AMaBXyng1aHaNgBg1bPzplVt8yfJs1RJGmaz8CqYGcrqyhSflCRqWojrFuE8pJkP74rY8l9j_7Y7R1JIBZDrouM1DROuqUKd-A==&quot;&gt;this Google Music playlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also see a list of each track after the bump:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bono - Children of the Revolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. John Powell - Main Titles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;. Pete Anthony - Main Titles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;. Danny Elfman - Main Title&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;. John Williams - The Flash Comics Clue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;. Patrick Doyle - Inspector Thompson&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. Klaus Badelt - I Don&amp;#39;t Belong Here&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;. John Williams - Across The Stars&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. James Newton Howard - The Hand of Fate - Part I&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Howard Shore - The Riders of Rohan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. John Williams - Fawkes The Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stan Getz - The Girl From Impanema&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you&amp;#39;ll join me in future weeks. You can listen live on Wednesdays &lt;a href=&quot;http://3ssr.org/show/scores-of-scores/&quot;&gt;at 3SSR.org&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;#39;ll also post each future episode here on my blog for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours lethargically,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>films</category><category>music</category><category>podcast</category><category>comedy</category><category>list</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;No Country For Old Men&quot; (2007)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-no-country-for-old-men-2007/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-no-country-for-old-men-2007/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s bizarre, violent, unpredictable and authentically American. Yes, it&amp;#39;s a Coen brothers film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by the Coen brothers but based on a novel by Cormac McCarthy, &lt;em&gt;No Country for Old Men&lt;/em&gt; is possibly the Coen brothers&amp;#39; most violent film, which is saying something. From the very beginning Anton Chigurh, played enigmatically by Javier Bardem, is killing people left and right in brutally creative ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative meanders contemplatively, but essentially this is the story of Llewelyn Moss. When Llewelyn happens upon the scene of a drug deal gone wrong and consequently two million dollars, he decides to keep the money for himself - despite the danger he knows comes with it. Said danger comes in the form of Anton Chigurh, a hitman who has been hired to reclaim the money. Very quickly Anton is recognisable as an utter psychopath. In his first scenes he is seen strangling a sheriff&amp;#39;s deputy and stealing a car by killing the driver with a captive bolt pistol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carving a trail of destruction through West Texas, these two men play cat-and-mouse through ingenious set pieces involving switcharoos and a lot of spilt blood. Both parties are proficient and practical: good at improvising and even fixing up their injuries after a violent encounter. It&amp;#39;s always refreshing to watch such clever and driven characters on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authorities trying to keep up with this conflict however, are not so quick on their feet. Or they&amp;#39;re just unlucky. A handful of police die while trying to intervene in the million dollar chase. Perhaps the police fail because they are simply less driven, without the money as an encouraging prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s soundscape is a subtle and carefully designed construct which plays a huge role in the success of the production. Dialogue is minimal and music is non-existent, leaving the few sound effects to stand out as powerful and punchy. Every time Anton blows open a door handle the accompanying &amp;quot;bang!&amp;quot; is unexpected enough to make the audience jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s style and narrative is unconventional and unpredictable in the usual Coen brothers fashion. You never really know what&amp;#39;s going to happen, who are the lead characters, and how much longer anyone will be alive. But as viewers we are allowed to enjoy this uncertainty, because this is an impeccable piece of filmmaking. The audience is always in the safest of hands with the Coen brothers, despite the terrible danger of their narratives.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;The Hurt Locker&quot; (2008)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-the-hurt-locker-2008/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-the-hurt-locker-2008/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hurt Locker&lt;/em&gt; is a film about Sergeant William James, a daring and reckless explosives disposal expert. The film opens with a quote from the book &amp;quot;War Is a Force That Gives Us Meaning&amp;quot; which sums up the central theme explored by director Kathryn Bigelow: &amp;quot;The rush of battle is a potent and often lethal addiction, for war is a drug&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James is addicted to the thrill of war. This is revealed through his keen desire to put himself in the middle of dangerous situations, and the fact that at the end of the film, when his service is over, he decides to leave his family and return to Iraq. This interesting character is made totally believable by a steady, focused performance by Jeremy Renner. When the drama escalates in the second half of the film, James deals with the situations both expertly but also with just enough humanity for the viewer to empathise with the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathryn Bigelow&amp;#39;s filmmaking style is intense to say the least. Scenes build tension with fast cutting between close and wide angles. Unlike typical actions films, however, this cutting is performed with a proficiency that allows the scene to be clear and understandable for the viewer. The film never dissolves into an indiscernible whirlwind of incomprehensible quick cuts, as would be easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hurt Locker&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most interesting and accurate depictions of modern warfare on film. It is relevant to our time and morally interesting - and not only for soldiers but for all people and their everyday lives. The film shows that it is possible for one to become addicted to a dangerous or destructive activity without realising. It raises the question for the United States: will they be able to leave the war when they have the chance, or will they keep looking for conflict, because that is what they are used to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.stevenbenedict.ie/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/The-Hurt-Locker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Chungking Express&quot; (1994)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-chungking-express-1994/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-chungking-express-1994/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chungking Express&lt;/em&gt; is a wacky romance film in two parts. Both set in the same area of Hong Kong, director Wong Kar-wai tells two similar stories of characters between relationships. In the first, a policeman who is struggling to forget his previous sweetheart, May, goes out to find any distraction he can. As fate has it, he meets and develops a seemingly platonic relationship with a surreptitious drug smuggler. The idea of a policeman and a drug smuggler unknowingly developing a relationship is striking, and speaks to the film&amp;#39;s ideas on the city environment: a place where so many people&amp;#39;s lives bump into each other so randomly and frequently that anything is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second story follows another policeman in grief after being abandoned by his girlfriend. This officer attracts the attentions of Faye, who works at a snack bar, and the story follows the development of their unclear relationship. Every character in the film is quirky (in a rather realistic way), but Faye is particularly wild. Often dancing carelessly to her favourite song, &amp;quot;California Dreamin&amp;quot; by The Mamas &amp;amp; the Papas, she continuously sneaks into the policeman&amp;#39;s home to tidy and move things around. This could be seen as a gracious or loving act, but it&amp;#39;s also creepy. Most relationships depicted in the film have some kind of bizarre or slightly twisted feel to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filmmaking techniques are used to vividly portray a bustling Hong Kong. Jump cuts keep events lively and musical montages are engagingly wacky. Shaking handheld camerawork is key to the sprawl; our viewpoint swirls around in a constantly-creative fashion, sending us into claustrophobic shops and smoothly following playful characters - notably the child-like Faye. Another regular film effect is that of time manipulation. In several scenes our main character is quite still while crowds bustle past behind them in fast motion. This has an isolative effect, making us appreciate the fact that we are seeing one man&amp;#39;s troubles in an ocean of millions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chungking Express&lt;/em&gt; provides an original and non-cliche commentary on romantic relationships. Refreshingly, however, it forces no opinions or ideas upon the viewer. The two stories are simply told and are told simply, leaving us to extract our personal meaning from the strange swirl of heartbreak and hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/chungking-express-1.DVHi0jpN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;2001 A Space Odyssey&quot; (1968)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-2001-a-space-odyssey-1968/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-2001-a-space-odyssey-1968/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;In terms of scope, &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; is difficult to compare. It is one of very few films which succeed at commenting on the big picture of life itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film is structured as a series of seemingly disconnected chapters, or vignettes, each of which take place in a totally different environment and time period. Recurring through these stories however, is the mysterious monolith, which likely represents the involvement of aliens in the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see a broad picture of human evolution. From apes to astronauts, from sticks to complicated space age technology. The film&amp;#39;s themes are painted with strokes broad enough that many different conclusions can be derived from the text. For many the film is about how aliens created humanity and guided our entire evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the fourth act, which depicts a human expedition to Jupiter, most engaging. It features an artificial intelligence called HAL, which has been copied, sourced and replicated in hundreds of science fiction narratives in modern culture. HAL is still one of the best though, the perfect mix between human and robotic, likeable and terrifyingly sinister. When he is being activated it is intriguing to witness HAL plead for his virtual life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s special effects are outstanding for the time, and still stand up today - nearly half a century later. Though we may laugh at the men in ape costumes, they still have a practical, confrontingly true quality, which still beats the incredible CGI possible today. And solid as the rest of the film is the score. The use of classical music &amp;quot;Also sprach Zarathustra&amp;quot; has become a cultural icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a reason &lt;em&gt;2001&lt;/em&gt; is still regarded as one of the greatest films of all time, and that is because it goes further than any other Hollywood production dares, sticking it&amp;#39;s fingers deep into mind-twisting themes that no one was previously talking about. It is a perfect discussion film, and will likely be analysed forever, or at least until humanity finds rebirth in the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://wae.blogs.starnewsonline.com/files/2013/05/2001-a-space-odyssey-original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Beyond The Hills&quot; (2012)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-beyond-the-hills-2012/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-beyond-the-hills-2012/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beyond the Hills&lt;/em&gt; is a confronting film about religion, illness and madness. Director Cristian Mungiu has crafted a balanced narrative with a keen eye on the church&amp;#39;s line of tolerance, and the ethics therein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enter the convent and learn its systems with Alina, whose character flavours our impressions with caution and uncertainty. But throughout the film Alina becomes increasingly ill, crazy and distant. In some scenes we don&amp;#39;t even see her face, just the back of her and the apprehensive faces of those she is confronting. Voichiţa could then be seen as the protagonist of the film, but as a whole the film follows no one character, but rather the ideas and moral questions at the core of the events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film is tremendously dialogue-heavy. There are dozens of scenes with many characters exchanging vast back-and-forths in soft, hushed voices. And there is always drama in the discussion, with characters always requesting, convincing, disciplining or attempting to understand one another. This constant and evolving conflict and debate comprises the core intrigue of the film. These scenes are also exceptional for their length without cuts; many long takes go for minutes in one camera shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To pick nits, the film is probably too long. Some shots are too dark and too slow, and could have been trimmed without losing atmosphere or meaning. That said, the filmmaker&amp;#39;s choice to take his ponderous own time is commendable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final scenes, in which the priest and several nuns are arrested for the murder of Alina, show a striking twist of power dynamics. Suddenly the priest, who until now has been a sure-minded leader, appears like a child who has been caught doing something naughty, obeying the every instruction of the now-dominant police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of drama that can be caused by one individual (in this case, the character Alina) is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/atthemovies/img/2013/ep25/beyond_large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;The Piano&quot; (1993)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-the-piano-1993/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-the-piano-1993/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Piano&lt;/em&gt; is a beautiful and dramatic telling of a tragic romance story. Set in the 19th century, the narrative follows a mute woman, Ada, and her daughter, Flora. Despite her desire to keep a distance from others, Ada finds herself caught between two men in a dark love triangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exquisite cinematography and art design is paramount in the film&amp;#39;s successful world building. The setting of the murky New Zealand coast and its misty woods provides an incredible atmosphere, particularly in some of the rainy scenes towards the end of the film. Director Jane Campion demonstrates a powerful mastery of mise en scene; every shot is interestingly framed, and often has layers of meaning and subjects in both the foreground and background. Furthermore, a remarkably unobtrusive edit lets the drama play out very organically. Scenes are minimally cut, and there is a strong sense that no shot is wasted, or is too long or too short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piano at the heart of the film acts as a metaphoric plot device. It is essential to Ada, practically replacing the void her muteness creates. Early on, playing the piano is emphasised as her favourite and most essential activity, as it&amp;#39;s the only time she can express herself. But then in order to get closer to her, Baines and Stewart inadvertently corrupt this haven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musically, the piano is brilliantly incorporated. It&amp;#39;s playing within scenes is oft interweaved into the already excellent score by Michael Nyman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Baines is for some time perceived to be the villain of the piece and Stewart seems the faultless hero, but the drama thickens and their roles are reversed in the second act when Ada demonstrates her affections for Baines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a meta-narrative flair worthy of Shakespeare, the play within the movie - which depicts a killer with an axe - effectively foreshadows the end of the film when Stewart, angry and betrayed, wields an axe against Ada. When he dramatically cuts off her finger, removing her ability to express herself through piano, the camera lingers with Ada as she struggles to comprehend her circumstances. Holly Hunter&amp;#39;s performance is wall to wall incredible, drawing in the viewer with a physical and emotional intensity. This climactic moment is heightened ever more by gloomy rain and the use of slow motion. Many powerful moments in the film take on a theatrical, larger-than-life quality which is epic and cinematically appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of her voices destroyed, Ada attempts to kill herself, but as she is drowning she finds the will to live. Emerging rebirthed from the water, she begins to speak again. A statement not only on the resilience of the human spirit, but the ability for one to change and grow through sincere effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.close-upfilm.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/The-Piano-007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Chinatown&quot; (1986)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-chinatown-1986/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-chinatown-1986/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Roman Polanski&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Chinatown&lt;/em&gt; tells a multi-layered story of small emotional conflicts and large societal corruption. Jack Nicholson stars as private investigator Jake Gittes, a man who is reluctantly pulled into what is at first the simple investigation of an affair. When his target turns up dead, it turns into a murder investigation. As the complex web of mystery continues to build around Jake, he finds himself unsure what he is actually investigating. Still, he is inquisitive enough to follow it to the bitter end. This nosy character trait is reflected in the visual gag of the bandage Jack has to wear on his nose after it is cut early in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Nicholson makes an interesting protagonist as Jake Gittes. He is more gruff and unpredictable than the usual noir detective (fitting that he is a private investigator instead of a true detective).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film feels intelligently built and firmly crafted. It has a remarkably clear sense of itself and has a confident approach to tropes of the noir genre. These tropes exist in character (Jake&amp;#39;s reluctance to get involved in the case followed by his inability to escape it til it&amp;#39;s bitter end), cinematography (dialogue in cars where all but a sliver of the actors&amp;#39; faces are in shadow) and, obviously, the dense mystery plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the cleverest aspects of the film is the interweaving connection of small plot devices. Jake&amp;#39;s most common companion through the mystery is the determined Evelyn Mulwray, played solidly by Faye Dunaway. Subtle, seemingly-incidental references to her left eye are planted throughout the film, such as her rubbing it while driving and Jake noticing a birthmark in it. In the final scene of the film however, these are revealed to be foreshadowing, as Evelyn is tragically shot through her left eye by police as she tries to escape her terrible circumstances. Furthermore, in this final scene Polanski does not even need to show us that Evelyn has been hit. After the police fire at her fleeing vehicle, it slows to a stop and the car&amp;#39;s horn sounds continuously. It is at that moment we remember what had seemed to be an inconsequential moment earlier in the film when Evelyn accidentally head-butts the steering wheel of her car - sounding the horn. This is the primary cleverness of the film: subtly planting devices in the viewer&amp;#39;s head that they do not realise are there until they are dramatically called back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very little is explained translucently to the viewer. We are forced to stay alert through each deliberately slow-paced scene in order to search for any clues to the direction the story is headed. This technique comes at a price of connection to the characters. Since we are never really let in on the characters&amp;#39; goals - most of all those of Jake - it becomes difficult to relate with their decisions and resulting circumstances. On the whole however, &lt;em&gt;Chinatown&lt;/em&gt; is such a solidly constructed film that it&amp;#39;s impossible for this minor lack of emotional connection to diminish one&amp;#39;s appreciation of the film&amp;#39;s many successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/Chinatown_091Pyxurz_5B1_5D.BOwUooNe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Badlands&quot; (1973)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-badlands-1973/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-badlands-1973/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Terrence Malick&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Badlands&lt;/em&gt; tells a dark and dreamy legend which explores the psychology of an unemotional teenage girl and the murderous man she runs away with. Martin Sheen and Sissy Spacek star as Kit and Holly, an unpredictable, offbeat and unconventionally mischievous pair. Both appear somewhat queer at the beginning of the film, but develop into truly confronting characters as they become increasingly desensitised to the violence they bring about. Though their attitudes are always nonchalant, they are undoubtedly the drivers of their journeys. Well, perhaps Kit is the predominant the driver for them both. It is he that first approaches Holly at the beginning of the film and pursues her determinedly, leading him to shoot her disapproving father (the first of Kit&amp;#39;s many &amp;quot;nuisance-removing&amp;quot; murders).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extroverted soundtrack is loud and intrusive and should by all rights be jarring, but in actual fact it blends well with the film&amp;#39;s themes. The high-pitched repetitive melodies emphasise the &amp;quot;fairy-tale&amp;quot; viewpoint of the protagonists; their whimsical journey of carefree destruction across the American countryside. Similar juxtaposition is key to Holly&amp;#39;s monotone narrations, which - often humorously - completely undersell the gravity of the characters&amp;#39; circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleverly, the true focus of &lt;em&gt;Badlands&lt;/em&gt; is only revealed in the film&amp;#39;s final scenes. While most of the film feels like a plot-driven journey which could easily build into a meaningless final showdown, when Kit shockingly surrenders himself to the authorities his character becomes the primary subject. Malick clearly understands that the audience is intensely interested in why Kit would do such a thing. Kit shifts so dramatically into the centre of the film&amp;#39;s spotlight that it feels like we are seeing him properly for the first time. He is shown to be more charismatic than ever before. It&amp;#39;s a subtle character twist which, similar to plot twist films like &lt;em&gt;Sixth Sense&lt;/em&gt;, forces the viewer to see the entire film in a very different light. All of Kit&amp;#39;s motives are thrown into question. One of the most intriguing ideas in storytelling is that of the likeable villain, and Kit is exactly that. In the final scenes the audience is made to struggle with the fact that they are feeling sorry for this psychotic murderer. The film lives beyond its runtime in these unanswered questions of subjectivity, justice and how one should classify psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/badlands1.C13XvOnJ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Grey Gardens&quot; (1975)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-grey-gardens-1975/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-grey-gardens-1975/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grey Gardens&lt;/em&gt; is an understated documentary about the relationship between a mother and daughter. Edith Beale (or &amp;quot;Little Edie&amp;quot;) lives with her mother of the same name (or &amp;quot;Big Edie&amp;quot;) in a large, isolated, deteriorating house. That&amp;#39;s the simplistic premise. It works exceptionally, however, due to the incredible depth and subtext of the uncomfortable relationship between the Beales women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the naturalistic shooting style of directors Albert and David Maysles, the film feels authentic and immersive. With long unedited takes of the Beales living their everyday lives, the audience is allowed complete and objective access to this rather tragic household. It&amp;#39;s like a nature documentary. We get right up close with these interesting specimens in their natural habitat, and we get to observe them for a good long while. It works brilliantly; the Beales are never shy of the camera - bickering unattractively and spilling forth their inner monologues. Without concern for story or plot development, one can easily forget it is a film, truly focusing in on these strange real life characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the isolated, shrub-encircled house, conflict arises naturally between mother and daughter. We learn of tensions between the two, particularly in regards to their respective successes. Big Edie is an accomplished singer who maintains somewhat of her singing voice in old age. However, when Little Edie sings on several occasions, it greatly upsets Big Edie, who spills forth criticisms and objections. Whether ashamed, threatened or just wanting to be appreciated for her talent, Big Edie&amp;#39;s passive aggressive manipulation of her daughter is intriguing social commentary. The film portrays a realistic chunk of family rivalry, up-close and personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutaways between scenes depict birds and planes flying above the house, a motif that hints at the outside world - free and constantly moving. This contrasts with the two women&amp;#39;s stagnant lives - a situation they are blind to, reflected metaphorically in their terrible eyesight (Little Edie even using binoculars to see short distances).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The depth of material the film reveals in such a small physical area and with a leading cast of only two, is incredible. &lt;em&gt;Grey Gardens&lt;/em&gt; demonstrates that interesting narratives, characters and relationships do not have to be scripted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/2009-04-17-beales_of_grey_gardens_detail.Dp6JqR6B.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Vertigo&quot; (1958)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-vertigo-1958/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-vertigo-1958/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Hitchcock&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Vertigo&lt;/em&gt; is a perfectly paranoid thriller about trickery, fear and obsession. The narrative follows James Steward as John &amp;quot;Scottie&amp;quot; Ferguson, a retiring detective who suffers from acrophobia and vertigo. Through the film&amp;#39;s abstract subterfuge of eerie effects and dizzying (vertigo-inducing, one might say) editing, we watch as Scottie investigates a mystery that makes him lose his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film&amp;#39;s second act is difficult for the viewer, as events twist about awkwardly and Scottie is plagued by an unrelatable madness, so it is fortunate that the first act introduces us to an exceptionally engaging mystery. We, with Scottie, investigate Madelein, an inscrutable yet beautiful woman who does not seem to make sense. Scottie&amp;#39;s obsession with Madelein escalates dramatically until the shocking moment when she plunges to her death from the tower of a mission. From that point his obsession is thrown out of focus, and he projects his mania into hallucinating that other women around him are Madelein. Editing trickery allows Hitchcock to make us see what Scottie sees: recurring instances of approaching women who appear to be Madelein, then change into a stranger as they come closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottie fixates on a particular woman who looks like Madelein (whom, fate has it, is Judy, the woman who impersonated Madelein as a part of a murder plot). In his mad attempt to have the unattainable, Scottie works to craft Judy&amp;#39;s appearance into that of Madelein, despite her understandable protests. In this way his &amp;quot;love&amp;quot; is shown to be entirely self-indulgent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernard Herrmann&amp;#39;s score is divine. Punchy and often bombastic, the music punctuates the film&amp;#39;s action and emotional beats from the word go, providing a rather affecting visceral experience. The score is as obsessed with its key romantic melody as Scottie is with Madeleine. It is a beautiful theme which is reprised dozens of times throughout the film to emphasise the heightened relationship. However, as with the reality of the relationship, the melody - when played in its complete form - flows from swirling beauty into a troubled stumbling of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question arises of whether or not &lt;em&gt;Vertigo&lt;/em&gt; is a romantic film. There are elements of romance, as Scottie is clearly infatuated by Madeleine and he pursues her like a lover. However, particularly in the final act, he is not very loving in his actions. He dominates Judy and drives her into a worked-up state of fear through his desperate madness. There are many instances in the second half of the film where it would feel appropriate for the film to end, but they are glazed by. Instead the characters go all the way into the madness, keeping the narrative alive until Judy dies like Madeleine, and then ending abruptly in that moment of horror. &lt;em&gt;Vertigo&lt;/em&gt; can be perceived as an anti-romance film. It&amp;#39;s a story in which love - one of humanity&amp;#39;s most optimistic traits - is twisted into dark, narcissistic obsession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/vertigo-2.CbJMDydB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Top 3 Personalities on the Melbourne Metro</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/top-3-personalities-on-the-melbourne-metro/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/top-3-personalities-on-the-melbourne-metro/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve spent a fair bit of time commuting by train in Melbourne lately. I always find public transport rather fun, as you&amp;#39;re chucked into confined spaces with a random group of diverse strangers. Lately I&amp;#39;ve seen a few particularly interesting personality motifs repeat themselves again and again, which I&amp;#39;d now like to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not necessarily the most common or most irritating or most engaging personalities, but the three which have interested me most of late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;#1. The Openly Disgruntled&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stereotype: female, early 30s, dark hair, handbag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone walks in your way for a second. You stop still and pull a face, a HUGE face, to show how absolutely offended you are. No one is looking at you, of course. But no one needs to. It gives you some kind of satisfaction, pitying yourself for your tragic wounds. You give yourself a moment of angry disbelief before moving on with your probably-busy day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;#2. The Jukebox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stereotype: male, late 20s, sunglasses, jeans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those headphones are bigger than your head. And you&amp;#39;ve turned the sound right up. We&amp;#39;re all grooving to your Daft Punk, but you don&amp;#39;t know it because you&amp;#39;re standing in the corner and staring at the graffiti on the wall like a kid in detention. Are your ears okay? We&amp;#39;re all a bit worried for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;#3. The Old And Nimble&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stereotype: male, early 70s, grey hair, walking stick, old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are quite old. You have a bit of a limp. Your back is heavily arched. We give you a bit of way to get through, but we don&amp;#39;t need to. Woah, look at you go. You&amp;#39;re overtaking everyone. You&amp;#39;re practically pushing teenagers onto the train tracks. Are you really old or is that all just make up and acting? Well, I guess we&amp;#39;ll never know &amp;#39;cause you&amp;#39;re yonks away already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mmm. People are entertaining. More people soon maybe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours disgustedly,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>comedy</category><category>anecdote</category><category>ramble</category></item><item><title>Brief Review of &quot;Withnail &amp; I&quot; (1987)</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-withnail-i-1987/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/brief-review-of-withnail-i-1987/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Withnail &amp;amp; I&lt;/em&gt; is a serious comedy set in the year of 1969. The film follows the characters of Withnail and Marwood - a pair of young, unemployed actors living it rough in their shoddy London flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the opening shot the set design is engrossing. The majority of the film takes place in claustrophobic rooms filled with piles of (mostly ugly) decorative items. Each set is so packed that the actors must dodge and weave through the endless accumulations of &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;. This immediately provides an authentic sense of place; the setting is totally believable throughout the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cadaverous, proudly carried and filled with drunk energy, Withnail is a captivating character in every scene. He shows little indication of truly desiring acting work, turning down an understudy role with his high-horse attitude. He is drawn to the romance and hijinks of this life as an out-of-work actor. It allows him to do no work and blame others for it. And thanks to the safety net that is his family&amp;#39;s wealth, &amp;quot;the unemployed artist&amp;quot; is a life he can afford to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marwood, on the other hand, worries about things (shown to us through his narration of several anxiety attacks). While he certainly likes Withnail and his larks, particularly enjoying their drunken raid of a tea room, Marwood takes life more seriously. He acts as a surrogate for the viewer, allowing us to empathise with his frequent annoyance with Withnail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the film follows our opportunistic protagonists on their impromptu holiday to a run-down cottage in the country. Combating unexpectedly harsh conditions, it isn&amp;#39;t long before both we and the characters experience enough discomfort to want to leave, missing the small London flat where they can at least muster a bowl of coffee. But then their plans to leave are buggered - pun intended - by an arrival in the night: Withnail&amp;#39;s Uncle Monty. One would think the line between rapist and romantic to be easily distinguishable, but &lt;em&gt;Withnail &amp;amp; I&lt;/em&gt; decisively makes it difficult for us to decide quite how malicious Monty is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sexualisation of Marwood is a theme throughout the film. He sleeps in nothing but underwear and his curly hair often appears feminine. When Monty admits his affections for Marwood, it is revealed that Withnail fuelled this unpleasant situation. It&amp;#39;s the final straw for Marwood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surprisingly sad final scenes are brilliant in their sense of truth. Marwood decides to grow up and move on, symbolised by his conservative new haircut. All sense of lark is diminished. It is easy to imagine how the rest of these characters&amp;#39; lives would play out: Marwood working his way towards a stable life, Withnail doing whatever it takes to continue his destructive lifestyle of self-pitying pleasure. The events of the film mark the crossroads where their lives fleetingly intersected. They clung together as long as possible - often quite literally on screen, their bodies pressed together warmly. But &lt;em&gt;Withnail &amp;amp; I&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s final statement pierces the excellent comedy with a powerful dramatic core: nothing lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/withnailfilmDM_428x269_to_468x312.C_Tc42P8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>review</category><category>films</category></item><item><title>Burying Yourself in The Internet</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/burying-yourself-in-the-internet/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/burying-yourself-in-the-internet/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Today I looked back at some of the things I posted on the internet a long time ago, including some of my early posts on this very blog. How very utterly embarrassing it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of a new problem in the world today. The internet is such a great platform for sharing your opinion, but what about when your opinion changes? How is one to react to everything they have shared?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure many will experience such a problem. Let&amp;#39;s go through a couple of the resolutions I considered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option 1: Delete The Offending Material&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I could simply go back into the archives of my blog and let loose my index finger which is positioned over my mouse whilst the cursor is positioned over the &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot; button. But if I remove everything I&amp;#39;m embarrassed about, which - let&amp;#39;s face it - is pretty much everything older than a few days ago, I&amp;#39;m left with a very flat, shallow, empty blog. In just a few days I&amp;#39;ll probably look at this very article and want it gone. But then nothing would ever get written or made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your past self has a right to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Option 2: Bury The Offending Material&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a far more positive, productive solution. The internet, and blogs in particular, are designed in a way that features the most recent content. The latest blog post will usually appear at the top of the web page, in prime viewing location. And if you&amp;#39;re even slightly embarrassed about what&amp;#39;s featured on your website, that can be a great motivator to go ahead and create something better to replace it with. And the more you create and publish, the deeper that old stuff is buried into the deep darkness of the internet where few people go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go on, have a look at your past Tweets, Facebook posts or Instagram posts. Feel the embarrassment. Then do something better, something fresh, and continue to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Fantastic Antidote To The Entire Situation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all boils down to worrying that others will mistake or misunderstand you in some way. It&amp;#39;s self-consciousness on the world wide web. It&amp;#39;s about judgement. So what if we all make an effort to judge less? Simply take everything you read with a grain of salt or two, particularly online. In sharing parts of themselves everyone is developing and changing, constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I will quote Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;We all change, when you think about it. We&amp;#39;re all different people, all through our lives. And that&amp;#39;s okay. That&amp;#39;s good, you&amp;#39;ve gotta keep moving. So long as you remember all the people that you used to be.&amp;quot; - The Doctor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.doctorwhotv.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/p57326-570x320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;ll do it. If you gleamed anything useful from my rambling, congratulations dear reader. And I&amp;#39;ll see you on the other side. Of what? No idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a good one,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours indefinitely,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>anecdote</category><category>ramble</category><category>technology</category><category>idea</category></item><item><title>Review of Trakt.tv</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/review-of-trakttv/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/review-of-trakttv/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Ever wished there was a neat, organised and fun way to keep track of all the TV and films you watch? Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv/&quot;&gt;Trakt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trakt is a website which compiles every single film and TV show (using solid databases such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://thetvdb.com/&quot;&gt;TVDB&lt;/a&gt;). The free service allows you to perform a multitude of actions with this library of content. You can add things to your &amp;quot;watchlist&amp;quot;, you can rate things, you can post comments or reviews. Everything you&amp;#39;d ever want is here on Trakt. And all of this is displayed with beautiful, large screens from each show or movie. Overall, the whole website has a brilliant, luxurious layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_astro/trakt.CFsx577I.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service makes keeping track of what you&amp;#39;ve seen and what you want to see simple as a plate. Especially in regards to TV shows, which can get complicated with their seasons and special one-off episodes etc. With Trakt, you can see exactly what you&amp;#39;ve seen and where you&amp;#39;re up to - even when the next episode is coming out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an optional paid &amp;quot;VIP&amp;quot; service ($15/y), which is nice but definitely not necessary. You can enjoy just about everything on Trakt without paying a cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: Trakt is a magnificent website which I highly recommend to lovers of TV or film. You can join for free right now at &lt;a href=&quot;http://trakt.tv/&quot;&gt;Trakt.tv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;#39;m very positive about it. No, this little review was not endorsed by anyone. No, I&amp;#39;m not signing autographs right now. Yes, I am answering real questions. No, there aren&amp;#39;t any more questions to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours fictitiously,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>review</category><category>films</category><category>television</category></item><item><title>Why The Government Should Increase Spending on the Space Program</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/why-the-government-should-increase-spending-on-the-space-program/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/why-the-government-should-increase-spending-on-the-space-program/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;Right now there is frozen moon orbiting Jupiter called Europa. Underneath its surface of ice is a liquid ocean. Who knows what unimagined ecosystems might exist in those oceans? Someday, somebody who was inspired as kid is going to drill down to explore those oceans. If we are smart in our choices then those kids could still be our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year in America, 79 billion dollars were spent on Education. 84 billion dollars were spent on Health. And eclipsing both of these, a massive 683 billion dollars were spent on defense and military, including funding for war in Afghanistan and Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far below this is something which is far more beneficial to us all, something which has changed all our lives several times throughout history. Space exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, only 17.7 billion dollars were spent on the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or NASA. And according to recent trend this is going to go down each year. NASA have recently stopped their space shuttle launches due to lack of funding, which is due to a lack of interest among people in general. This is a trend that must change if we are to give the chance of exploration and adventure to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people argue that even less should be spent on space exploration programs. They say that the money should instead be spent on fixing problems here on Earth, such as housing, health and medical research. But the reality is that space isn’t as expensive as many people think. Contrary to popular belief NASA doesn’t make big shiny fireworks then fill them with expensive stuff and launch them into space just because they feel like it. The money stays here on Earth. It drives the economic system just like any other industry, paying the wages of - in the case of NASA - over eighteen thousand hard-working employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, more and more people are of the opinion that space exploration is a waste of money, time and effort. But the benefits of astronomy may not be direct as expected. Close examination reveals that there are many benefits to space exploration that we can all - and have all - experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many people know how much space exploration has changed our lives in recent history. It’s an industry which brings together thousands of smart people from a variety of fields and puts them to work on very difficult problems, and this has shown to result in many excellent new inventions. For example, astronomers sought ways to reduce the weight of rockets and came up with the micro-chip idea. Modern computers were then developed from these micro-chips. Where would we be without the computers we have today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invisible braces, scratch-resistant lenses, ear thermometers, long-distance telecommunications, water filters, improvements to athletic shoes, smoke detectors, roads, aircraft runways and so many more. These are all thanks to NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these are only the beginning. It’s impossible to know what other discoveries could be made in research for space exploration. It is definitely an investment for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth’s population is growing dramatically. Less than a century ago, in 1927, there were roughly 2 billion people on the planet, and we now number well over 7 billion. The risk of natural or manmade disasters make human settlement in other areas of space a very real possibility. Thanks to space exploration we already have a habitable satellite orbiting the Earth. It’s called the International Space Station and right now, there are six people living on it. And that’s only the beginning. Various entrepreneurs and businesses are working on real plans to put hotels in space, which anyone can visit. Any of us could, in our lifetimes, take a holiday into space … as long as you have four million dollars. It’s only a matter of time before the ideas of science fiction can become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, money spent on astronomy is used to defend our planet against possible threats. NASA funded research scans the skies for dangerous asteroids, and tries to work out how we could divert them from a collision course with Earth if the need arose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space exploration also acts as a point of inspiration for future generations. The remarkable feats that have been and are yet to be accomplished in space will naturally encourage many students to study high levels of science and mathematics. Nobody can deny that space inspires people. Over five hundred million people watched the Apollo 11 moon landing live on television in 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a natural human instinct to explore the unknown, but there are now very few outlets for this on Earth. Space really is the next level. It’s a field in which we can all feel pride, excitement and wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first we need to stop the growth of the stigma that space exploration is a waste of time and resources. It has proven its benefits in the past, and the possibilities of the future are beyond imagination. Let’s make space exploration an exciting opportunity for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>writing</category><category>ramble</category><category>idea</category></item><item><title>Why You Should Check Out The Doctor Who Fan Orchestra</title><link>https://thomid.me/posts/why-you-should-check-out-the-doctor-who-fan-orchestra/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/posts/why-you-should-check-out-the-doctor-who-fan-orchestra/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;p&gt;A few days ago the Doctor Who Fan Orchestra released their fifth piece, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/SfNVhEN50VU&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The Impossible Astronaut (Suite)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which is a collection of Murray Gold&amp;#39;s music from &amp;quot;The Impossible Astronaut&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Day of the Moon&amp;quot; episodes. This is an incredible collaboration, and here are the reasons you should check out the DWFO:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By The Fans, For The Fans&lt;/strong&gt;
There aren&amp;#39;t many fan bases that could pull off something like this. It is an example of the huge scope of Doctor Who fans and their passionate commitment to the show. These are all people just like you and me from all over the world, whipping out an instrument and creating something very special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#39;s Hard Work&lt;/strong&gt;
Everyone involved in DWFO spends incredible amounts of time and effort putting together each piece, but none more than the creator, Stephen Willis. Imagine the work it must take to not only put together and distribute sheet music for a range of instruments, but also compile hundreds of submissions into a high quality audio and video production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#39;m In It&lt;/strong&gt;
That&amp;#39;s how nice and accepting this group of people are, they even let me take part! In the latest piece you might be able to spot me playing the piano and donning a bow tie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#39;s Great Music&lt;/strong&gt;
Who doesn&amp;#39;t love Murray Gold&amp;#39;s work on Doctor Who? The music he creates is incredibly beautiful and exciting. Stephen Willis&amp;#39; arrangements in the DWFO capture this with astounding quality, when you consider that he is receiving hundreds of part submissions of varying quality from all over the world. Each of the five pieces performed by the DWFO so far have included superb selections of Murray Gold&amp;#39;s score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Check out the DWFO&amp;#39;s latest piece here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/SfNVhEN50VU&quot;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours momentarily,
Thoroughmas&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content:encoded><category>soundtrack</category><category>television</category><category>music</category></item></channel></rss>