<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Thomas Midena</title><description>Generally genuinely enthusiastic</description><link>https://thomid.me/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:43:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>That fresh new website feeling</title><link>https://thomid.me/fresh-new-website/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://thomid.me/fresh-new-website/</guid><description>I&apos;ve built a lot of personal websites in the past, but this one is my favourite! (obvs)</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
                    &lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
                        
                        &lt;p&gt;Smells pretty good right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually yeah, don&amp;#39;t sniff too hard. Knowing how I&amp;#39;ve thrown it together, it&amp;#39;s probably got errant links that take you directly to my bank account or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had many personal websites over the years. Making them is something that I&amp;#39;ve always been interested in and only mildly good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the earliest ones I can remember I built with Freewebs. Which later changed its name to Webs, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/l2jzib/webscom_aka_freewebscom_deleting_tens_of_millions/&quot;&gt;shut down completely, apparently deleting everything&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early websites featured my projects under the moniker &amp;quot;Lcm Film&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/lcmfilmsite.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s one of the final forms of that Freewebs site (which went through a ridiculous number of regenerations... every few months it was &amp;quot;Let&amp;#39;s remake the website!&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much as changed, has it? Get rid of the dated Google+ link and the ear-searingly bright background, and this website could pretty much do the trick for me today. Actually, I wish I&amp;#39;d had that thought a couple days ago...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s even got a &amp;quot;Brand New Website!&amp;quot; blurb there, just like the one I&amp;#39;m writing right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you look closely, my favourite bit is the little &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s going on!?&amp;quot; image on the left, with a link to go back to the previous version of the website. How thoughtful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My websites were actually much more fancy back then. I mean, each of those menu links lights up when you hover over them. And the Library has links to separate pages for each short film I was hosting. Yes, actually hosting. Videos weren&amp;#39;t all just hosted on YouTube back then, like they are now (for better and (lately) worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/thomasmidenaogsite.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looked like when I was just starting to get into minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I was using my own name, a picture of myself, and starting to base everything about my YouTube Channel. Exciting times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/thomasmidenarefinedsite.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I had this site. Which again, in hindsight I&amp;#39;m pretty impressed by, and I wonder why I got rid of it. It&amp;#39;s pretty elegant for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t take all the credit for this one though. It was created with help from my mate &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewcollins.me/&quot;&gt;Drew Collins&lt;/a&gt;. Who was and I have to assume absolutely still is an absolute legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/Thomas_websitebanner_v3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a little while I had a website that looked like this. Holey moley. We all go through design phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then and in-between I&amp;#39;ve had various other sites, hosted with Blogger, Squarespace, Wordpress, Drupal, and I think at one point in my teens I lost my mind and went pure CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the website I&amp;#39;ve had for the last few years has been a very basic Wordpress page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thomid.me/_astro/thomasmidenawordpresssite.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to go proper minimal with this one. No icons, only a few lines of text, one image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think it has served me well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have been wanting for something a little more robust. A little cleaner. A little better at communicating everything I&amp;#39;m up to. And with a blog built in, so that I can write &lt;em&gt;stuff like this&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was choosing a platform. I don&amp;#39;t like Wordpress, it&amp;#39;s a clunky mess to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted something that was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modern and widely-used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;affordable (or free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and highly customisable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t take long to discover that there are more great options out there than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could use something like Publii. It&amp;#39;s got everything I want, and even has an easy to use GUI. But after trying it for a little while, I quickly realised that unless there was a template that I really liked, it was going to be frustrating to customise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking at others: Ghost, Hugo, Zola, Eleventy. So many good options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately, it came down to the availability of templates. Even though I intend to customise a lot, I want a very solid base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so this new website is built on Astro. Which ticks all the right boxes and appears to be very popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, I really love this template by Muhammad Syakirurohman. It&amp;#39;s clean and elegant, putting projects and blog posts at the forefront. And since it&amp;#39;s built on Astro, the potential for customisation is unending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also a great boon that platforms like Astro integrate beautifully with markdown files. I&amp;#39;ve been using Obsidian a lot over the past year for extensive note-taking, and being able to write blog posts the same way is very intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tricky part is, of course, learning Astro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code is something I&amp;#39;ve always dabbled in but never really become proficient. So it&amp;#39;s only with the help of Claude and ChatGPT that I&amp;#39;ve been able to stuck into designing this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as helpful as AI bots are for getting started on something you don&amp;#39;t understand, it sucks to rely on them too much for too long. After a while, you want to ditch the training wheels and fly on your own, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s the journey I have ahead of me! And that&amp;#39;s what makes it fun! Sure, I could fork out however much money each month for Squarespace and have a great website in minutes (or so all the podcast ads tell me). But I wouldn&amp;#39;t feel like I am &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; the master of the website. This way, as long as I don&amp;#39;t absolutely crash and burn, nothing is holding me back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the key themes of 2024 has been not getting locked in. Not getting locked into a bad habit, a particular way of thinking, or a digital app or service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s it, that&amp;#39;s my new site, and this has been the first blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the internet becoming &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; fragmented all the time, it&amp;#39;s wonderful to have my own independent space to bring together everything that relates to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hey, if you do find a link to my bank account... eh, you&amp;#39;re welcome to whatever&amp;#39;s there.&lt;/p&gt;

                    &lt;/div&gt;
                </content:encoded><category>web design</category><category>open source</category><author>Thomas Midena</author></item></channel></rss>